<text>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/brain.html">
        <level degree="1">I pictured the inside of my brain as something like a burrow, a labyrinthine system of contorted tunnels with hairpin turns. Ordinarily, the passages were roomy, pale and dry, like tunnels worm-bored through chalk or bone. When my head ached, those walls became an angry red, and swelled until the passages shrank to fistulas. I tried not to think. Thoughts were dirt, and collected in greasy seams in the walls, and inflamed them. If I could trepan myself, I thought, and fit a nozzle in my skull, I would run a hose into my brain. I could almost feel the cold water stretching its insistent fingers into the labyrinth. That would cure me. Or a high wind, blasting through.</level> <analepsis><level degree="2">One night, I went out on the back porch and screamed until blue pressure lights dazzled out the stars. What was that? my mother said. I thought it might help my headache, I said. Did it? she said. No, I said.</level></analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/eyebrow.html">
        <level degree="1">My eyebrows are thick and dark with a witchy point at the arch I sometimes exaggerate with pencil, remembering</level> <analepsis><level degree="2">the day after Halloween when I was ten or eleven. I could never get off all the greasepaint the night before. My eyebrows were black, glowering, joined with a shadow over my nose. I remember staring at my pale face in the bathroom mirror. I was wearing a light blue t-shirt I disliked. I looked dirty, like a pirate. I rubbed a bunch of toilet paper across my eyebrows and threw the blackened wad away, reached for more. Officially, I despised make-up, though secretly, guiltily, I was fascinated by it. But nobody could blame me if I just didn't wash my face. I went to school smudged and interesting. When people commented on my eyebrows, I gave explanations, feigning exasperation at the inefficacy of soap.</level></analepsis>

        <analepsis><level degree="2">In Spanish in seventh grade, I taught myself to raise my left eyebrow with a tug of a muscle at the upper left, while forcing down my right. It is a perfect inquisitive arch. From the first, though, I could barely locate the corresponding muscle on my right side. It made me squirm in my seat. It was like trying to move my legs in a dream, an almost intolerable impression of strain in all the wrong places, nothing but weakness and indecision in the right one. I could only work on it for a little at a time: more, and the tension started making me fidget, yawn, jam my legs hard under my desk.</level></analepsis> <level degree="1">I can crank my right eyebrow up a little, but not without making faces, or feeling the urge to grab my crotch.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/eyelid.html">
        <analepsis><level degree="2">My eyelids twitched for four days once in high school. I wondered if other people could see it, and tried to catch the twitch in the mirror, but it never happened when I was looking. That was the period when I went to the public library every lunch hour and strained my eyes over drawings by Durer and Kollwitz. I studied the heavy, dark eyelids in their sunken sockets. The thick greasy curve of the underlid, the weight of the eyeball in its sling of skin: I copied it into my notebooks with the blackest pencils I could get, pressing the soft lead voluptuously into the paper. A blind person could trace my drawings with her fingertips three pages down in my notebook. My own eyelids are embedded in flesh. I thought they were tediously modern. When I drew myself, I exaggerated the shadows, scoring harsh lines under my eyes.</level></analepsis> <prolepsis><level degree="1">Time is making these lies truer every year.</level></prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/eyes.html">
        <level degree="2"><analepsis>On summer mornings I lay in bed until I was called to breakfast, conducting lazy experiments with my eyes, closing first one, then the other. The different views were sometimes startlingly different: one eye saw only blankets, the other eye saw the sun coming through my Alice-in-Wonderland curtains. This bothered me. I thought a real artist ought to be able to render every view her eyes framed between waking and sleeping. If she had time outside time to paint her day, she could make something like a film, each frame a canvas. How could I be expected to draw things the way they really looked if in any given moment things looked, not one way, but two? In class, slipping my hand unobtrusively over one eye, then the other, I noticed that my geometry teacher's thick glasses, which notched the counter of her cheek and miniaturized her eyes, interrupted her face differently from my left eye than from my right. I could let my eyes slide out of focus and see two worlds, slightly out of register. They were different, but not very. But one day my eyes went out of focus and for an instant I saw two completely different worlds. I picked one,</analepsis> but ever since, I have been haunted by the feeling that this world is insufficiently real. It only happens to be as it is, it might have been otherwise.</level>


        <level degree="2">When lying in bed in the dark I sneezed I saw blue cat-whiskers of light at the edges of sight. When I pressed on my eyes I saw concentric circles that slid around with my fingers, circles of blue and muted orange, the very color of pressure. When I opened my eyes the night however dark was not by any means simply black but a field of granular bits with complicated movements in it like boiling soup, a roiling, curdling quicksand that at times even seemed to firm itself up into meaningful entities, stern or laughing faces that alarmed me slightly, though I knew well enough from protracted drowsy study of the patterns in curtains and coverlets that any harmless pattern could spontaneously squirm, settle and become the leering face of some devil, elf or clown, and that while a runaway imagination might consider these characters envoys from some Mephisto with a bone to pick with me, I could and probably should take refuge in the supposition that my eyes were only overzealous about making sense of shapes, which was after all their job.</level>

        <level degree="1">It was interesting to consider that my eyes were objects, not gusty spiritual wardens of the great void my face seemed to be. To touch the surface of the eye was a forbidden thing, I shrank from it without needing to be told, and that was probably because the eye was not really a thing, but a visible soul.</level> <analepsis><level degree="2">Surprising, then, to study our cat's eyes from the side, one afternoon on the sunny sofa in my living room, and see that the colored part was a thin membrane, iridescent as a butterfly wing, stretched across a ball the front part of which I could see right through, and that the pupil was just a hole in the membrane whose edges tightened and flared as the light changed. Surprising also to half-open my eyes in the sunlight and see the rainbow corona in my lashes, and even see the lashes themselves, complexly cross-hatching the sky. Astonishing to consider that I really was looking out from between my eyelashes, across the swell of my cheek, down my nose.</level></analepsis>

        <level degree="2">In fact, I could see my nose. It was distressing, to discover that everything I saw was permanently haunted by a fuzzy pink Caspar, bobbing around in the bottom center of every single scene like the stuffed toys tourists carry with them to prop up in front of Vesuvius, Fuji, Lassen: my nose wouldn't leave me alone. To notice it drove me a little wild with craving a clear view. So did the blinding after-image of angled roof, tree, telephone wire against the sky, and the boiling that started up in the blue or indeed in any clear strong color if I stared at it for long. If I really wanted to render what I saw, then I would have to paint a faint nose-shadow just above the base-line of every canvas. In addition, I'd have to include the white ghosts of nearby shapes looked at too long and the incompletely joined, not-quite-duplicate views of objects closer to than the subject at hand: I'd have to learn to render the condition of Out Of Focus. Nothing stayed still and flat and bright like a picture, not even a picture. Everything was jostling, shimmering, bleaching out or darkening, receding and then riding forward with a jerk. To stop that hokey pokey for long enough to pick a view and draw it wasn't easy. Why didn't the books mention this? <prolepsis>What a relief, when I finally read the words: "There are no lines in nature." So outlines, those supposedly self-evident bits of piping around every given thing, didn't exist. Finally someone had the guts to admit it!</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/migraines.html">
        <level degree="1">Migraine blindness starts with the funny feeling that I've missed a clue, that someone's pulling a prank on me. I know what to look for, and I spread my right hand in front of my face, palm up, and stare at the tip of my baby finger. My thumb disappears. If I let my eyes stray toward where my thumb should be it will reappear, but fix my eyes on my pinky again, and it vanishes. As soon as I check, I am aware that I have known of the problem for some time, but that it has only now reached my conscious attention. Things have been missing (ears, page numbers, the arm of a sofa) but I have been filling in for them. Now that I am paying attention, reading becomes impossible; the ending of a long word disapp . Everyone is one-eyed, smiles are weirdly abbreviated. Try driving; indeed, try walking in this condition. Objects appear out of gopher holes, or lumber toward me on half their ordinary complement of wheels, or cross my path and vanish. Soon, this simple absence becomes visible. A shimmering arc stands before me. It is energetic and purposeful. Quickly, it lengthens and becomes more elaborate. It moves when my eyes move, and I can see it with my eyes shut. Within the scimitar are short flashing vanes of light that ripple across the arc in quick succession, at varying angles to one another. The arc becomes a blazing shield that blots out the whole right side of the world. Its surface is hectic with churning blades of light. Then the blades fade back, the churning calms to a slight eddy, the whole apparatus recedes. There is something both horrible and magnificent about the chimera that visits me and borrows my eyes for the duration of this ceremony, twenty minutes, then rolls on its way. When I have my eyes back I am not sure I know them. The healed real world looks whole, but its colors are a little tawdry, it turns up at the edges. I keep checking to make sure all the pieces are there, but if something were missing, could I tell?</level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/theories.html">
        <level degree="1">It seemed my body could do anything I wanted it to. How much I dared was the only question. Climbing, I felt surefooted to an almost mystical degree. I was with the tree or rock I was climbing on, I was married to it. There was no reason for me to fall, any more than someone standing on solid ground would suddenly topple over. I knew how much weight I could put on something before it tipped or cracked; like a spider, my mind was in the center of my body, conscious in all directions. I seemed to know where I was with my very skin.</level> <analepsis><level degree="2">In this exalted state of confidence I descended the steep shingled slope of the roof of my grandparents' house on the downhill side, which was forbidden, because the house was wedged into the slope, like many houses in the Berkeley hills, and the downhill side was three stories to the uphill's one. The shingles were silvery with age and so dry on this, the sunnier side, that they crumbled to powder rather than rotting. Some were loose, and the whole roof was strewn with slithery pine needles; I was conscious of all this, but not of the possibility that something might go wrong, and I went down the metal rain-gutter in a half-sliding crouch, plowing up a wall of pine needles before my feet. I sat at the very edge of the roof, not relaxing, still balancing, looking out over the valley. I felt my thoughts contract and harden in the center of a vast dangerous emptiness that I held at bay just by being sure who I was. When I heard voices I scurried back like a monkey, using my hands, to the safe side of the roof, but this undignified retreat only slightly marred that proud and distant feeling.</level>

        <level degree="2">At more or less the same time I dared myself to step out my window - also on the downhill side of the house - onto the cracked roof of the dog run my grandparents had built onto the house, a rickety affair of chicken wire nailed to a wood scaffolding, with a slanted roof of wavy green fiberglass that reached the wall four feet below my window. I knew that it was possible I would crash through the fiberglass into the shitty, dirty dog run and hurt myself, though probably not die. I also knew it was possible, another class of disaster but almost equally dreadful, that my grandmother would at that moment lean into the African Violets clustered into the little windowed corner above the sink, which projected from the side of the house, and see me doing deadly wrong. But neither of these things happened; further cracking the fiberglass, I crept down one of the support beams, marked by a line of nails, to the edge. I had known, charting my course from the bedroom window, that this would be the hard part, but it was harder than I had anticipated. Somehow I lowered myself onto my stomach and edged down until I could dig my toes into the chicken wire, and on my stomach let myself slide farther down until I was able to catch one hand in the wire, and then, in the moment my weight slipped off the roof altogether, transfer the other hand to the wire as well. From there it was playground stuff to monkey-climb to the ground. I stood looking up with shaky thighs, considering the unusual idea that it might not have worked. I shouldn't have done that, I thought. It was a grave thing to carry alone, the feeling that something terrible had just whisked by, brushing my shoulders, but leaving me unharmed. But I was guiltily jubilant as well: I knew I could do it, I did it.</level>

        <level degree="1">I climbed innumerable rocks and trees as well, but it is these forbidden feats I remember most clearly, because I knew something about my body and what it could do that the grown-ups did not. I had many theories about my body at that time. I remember</level> <level degree="2">expounding my thoughts about Strength and Flexibility to my sister, very gravely, while practising maneuvers (made up and incorporated into my plan on the spot) on the trapeze bar, which was a treasured feature of the rusty swing set down below my grandparents' house, in a little clearing in the poison oak. To my embarrassment and furious annoyance my father appeared from behind a bush, offering to show me the real, grown-up exercises to do "if you really want to get strong." I kicked my toe into the dirt and felt like crying. Of course I knew my exercises weren't real exercises. In a way we were playing a game. At the same time I thought I might be discovering things the world didn't know yet. I didn't want to be strong in the world's ordinary way. I wanted to be strong like a hero, like Pippi Longstocking.</level>

        <level degree="2">It was in this same period that my sister and I held Olympic Games in our room, behind a locked door. Well-informed by Kenneth Clark's book on The Nude, which I perused for hours in the partial concealment of the top bunk, we did our broad jumps and push-ups naked, like the Greeks, and if I had sweated enough I would have squee-geed myself dry with a scraper, which I imagined looked something like a metal shoehorn. The chill on our naked bodies as we threw ourselves through the air felt racy and unfamiliar, and we kept our voices down, knowing complicatedly that if we were caught our nudity would be questioned, and that while the real answer would exonerate us, the game (but it was more serious than that) would be ruined by exposure to the grown-ups' humorous gaze.</level></analepsis>

        <prolepsis><level degree="2">Later, entertaining the dangerous theory that I would never be able to fly unless I jumped off something high enough to prove I really believed, since if I only jumped off little things, then I must be secretly planning to hit the ground, I threw myself off the neighbor's garage roof. Even as I did it, I knew my faith wasn't steely and absolute enough: I bent my knees, I crouched, I landed perfectly.</level></prolepsis>

        <prolepsis><level degree="1">I don't know if this was before or after the most terrible fall from grace.</level></prolepsis> <analepsis><level degree="2">I had climbed up what had become my favorite tree (I rarely climbed the old tree now, which was scratchy with little dead twigs and crowded around by other trees which shaded it and blocked the view, while the new tree stood a little apart, and</analepsis> <analepsis>I had groomed it for climbing, with my father's approval - I think he thought of it as a safety measure - breaking off all the dead branches that choked the open channel around the trunk and hurling them down, to be collected and wood-chipped).</analepsis> <prolepsis>I had climbed higher than ever before, up to the young branches at the top. I was in a state of exaltation, gazing desperately around me at the soft brilliant green needles with the sunlight sifting through them, the hot sky overhead, the space around me which seemed to rock with the wind as one mass while the tree stood still. The branches were terribly real, their brittle bark crumbling in my hands, the sap sticking my fingers together, and their flexible presence behind my back and underfoot seemed knowing and even encouraging. The very top of the tree was a cluster of three or four new branches radiating out like spokes from a central point, and suddenly it came to me that I could lie in the saddle they formed, if I was very careful. Trying not to put my whole weight on any single branch, I manouvered myself into the top, and lay back along the strongest of the spokes. The tree swayed under me. It was just as I had imagined. There was nothing but sky above me. Turbines rolled in the blue.

        When the branch under me split off from the trunk, it made a terrible, raw sound. I plunged downward. For a minute I hung half upside-down, then I righted myself. My whole body was shaking and I knew I had just nearly died. In that moment I knew that my feelings of entitlement and sympathy with the physical world were a fantasy. The world was still wonderful and I was still eagerly a part of it, but I was not the world's privileged daughter and suitor. I had no magical insight into the will of things, and I would be doled no special favours. The broken branch hung by a hinge of bark, and I felt ashamed and full of rage at myself for breaking it. I had been shown up: I was stupid and brutal in my pride, just like everyone else.</level></prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/erogenous__gen.html">
        Once, impressed with my own malleability, I had just taught myself a new way to masturbate.
        I decided to learn to come from touching any part of me. It was lazy to take everyone's word for it that sex began and ended between the legs, with merely scenic excursions to the breasts. So maybe the most obvious hot spots were between my legs.

        There were other points all over my body that burned in a barely-there way I thought I could amplify with a little practise: what about the crook of my elbow or my wrist, the hollow at the pit of my neck, the sore saddles between my fingers?

        I thought if I concentrated I could hitch the rising fever to another spot. I wanted to be able to enter my playground anywhere. I thought about people who went blind from brain damage, then learned to see again with an entirely different part of their brain. The neurons found another way to link up. If you needed to, you could rewrite your brain. What if you just wanted to?
        I had already found that I could rope more into my orgasm than the clitoris itself. If I dug my fingers into the muscles of my inner thighs while I masturbated, my orgasm had a different flavor than if I rootled in my belly button. Once I had established a fingerhold somewhere else, maybe I could let go of my clit and proceed to unassisted thigh orgasms, elbow orgasms, earlobe orgasms. In the meantime I kept one hand between my legs.
        I lay with sweat breaking out all over my body in a curtained room afternoons, rubbing my upper lip. Who would presume to tell me I couldn't do it? It was an experiment in will. Why shouldn't will intimately inhabit and entertain pleasure as well as more ordinary actions of the day, like chucking a stone into the arroyo back of my grandparents' house?

        I gave it up, marooned on the familiar island of my cunt. Now I think I should try it again; I admire that almost holy dedication to the study of my own mysterious flesh, my faith that I could unpack unheralded advantages from its portmanteau of possibilities. I was a kind of nun of fun, a Hildegarde of Bingen of the body!
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/cabinet.html">
        <level degree="1">In the course of writing these reminiscences, I increasingly began to conceive of my body as a great cabinet of curiosities. Some of those many recondite drawers slide easily out and whack you on the shins, some need a little wax and sandpaper. Inside the drawers are folded sheets of cheap blue-lined paper, pages from journals or school reports, with pictures and diagrams pasted in. There are drawings, biological specimens with neat labels, inscrutable items with no labels, stains from bygone experiments, stoppered bottles and broken vials and their spilled, dried contents, in which a squadron of tiny fruit flies met their sticky deaths. There are slips of paper referring you to other drawers, unlabelled keys (you may despair of finding the locks they fit), and there are drawers within the drawers, behind sliding panels or false bottoms. I have found every drawer to be both bottomless and intricately connected to every other drawer, such that there can be no final unpacking. But you don't approach a cabinet of wonders with an inventory in hand. You open drawers at random. You smudge the glass jar in which the two-headed piglet sleeps. You filch one of Tom Thumb's calling cards. You read page two of a letter; one and three are missing, and you leave off in the middle of a sentence.

        As a matter of fact, I am making a replica of this text: a huge wooden chest in the shape of my body, with innumerable drawers in which I will store my findings. Some of the drawers will be large and c a p a c i o u s, some smaller than matchboxes. Some will be disguised, some will be booby-trapped. I will hide secret buttons, levers and locks in my carved folds and crevices. You will have to feel your way in.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/tie_in_products.html">
        <level degree="1">I am selling small vials of pee, female ejaculate and spit to libraries, collectors and speculative investors. The vials are numbered pee 1-100, spit 1-50, come 1-10, and labelled with the vintage (1997). As pee is the most plentiful fluid it is also the least expensive ($300; spit is $500); however, I have limited the edition to one hundred as shown, so as not to flood the market. Female ejaculate is hard to produce and equally hard to capture and bottle. As a result I am asking one thousand dollars for this rare first edition. If there is a significant demand I will issue a 1998 vintage next year, numbering these in similar fashion. Of course these early editions will appreciate dramatically in value. Collectors may wish to own the fluids from the year their favorite works were written or published, or to assemble a complete sequence in chronological order. Some will prefer the humble and colorful bottles of pee, the Every(wo)man's Library of collector's items. Others the rarer fluids. Sorry, but I cannot part with any solid matters and will not be engaged in discourse on this point. If you want to spend your money on shit, look elsewhere.

        This is a work in progress. If you would like to sponsor further study of your favorite body part or you are a collector, please email me care of Alt-X.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/ears.html">
        <analepsis><level degree="2">The Silly Putty coils of the ear looked devoid of sense or regularity until I copied a Durer drawing line for line, then found the same whorls in my own ear. Abbreviated or elongated, squeezed thin or bunched thick, every ear was made on the same pattern.</level>

            <level degree="2">My friend Lisa, who was rarely right about facts, but had a colorful sense of story, told me that earwigs crawled into your ear (if you were foolish enough to go to sleep outside), laid their eggs in your brain, and crawled out the other ear. When the eggs hatched, you went crazy. She delivered this fact from my garage roof, where we were sitting in disturbing proximity to earwigs, who were fond of the apples that dropped and rotted there. I gave the idea some thought. It had not occurred to me that the ear passage might go all the way through my head, despite "in one ear and out the other," a phrase popular with my mother. It was true that earwigs were unnerving animals and I later found they were named after the rumor Lisa was spreading, centuries after it was recorded in the Old English name, earwicga, or ear-beetle, but I suspected I would have heard by now from someone besides Lisa if they really were bent on laying their eggs in my brain.</level></analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/nose.html">
        <level degree="1">Things I can do with my nose: I can wrinkle it in distaste. I can wiggle my nostrils rhythmically. I can 'make a long nose.' I can thrust it into small, tight places. I can nuzzle things softly. I can blow streams of bubbles underwater. I can make a loud reproachful sound, like a krummhorn.

        My nose is pierced on the left side.</level> <analepsis><level degree="2">The operation was quick and antiseptic, an ink dot placed, wiped off, replaced, a smooth little wooden rod up my nose, a deep breath, the needle plunged through. The ring slid in and pushed out the needle. The only raw and beautiful thing about it was the sudden hapless surge of tears to my left eye, which instantly overflowed down my cheek.</level></analepsis>

        <level degree="2"><prolepsis>I remember</prolepsis> <analepsis>other kids in school whose noses would regularly bleed for no reason, a violent color gushing out of them, while they sat calm and rather saintly, the center of a fascinated crowd. I would have been happy to be one of those people.</analepsis> <prolepsis>My nose rarely bleeds, but I take a secret luxurious pleasure in it when it does. I like the sudden warm liquid welling up in my nose, flowing extravagantly forth. I show off the brilliantly spotted tissue in an off-hand way, enjoying the worried remarks.</prolepsis></level>

        <level degree="1">I have often imagined what I would look like without a nose. Inescapably I have concluded: in the land of the noseless, a nose would be a monstrosity. A fleshy, perforated blemish, and right in the center of the face, for anyone to see. It is important to remember this when regretting one's nose, or pitying someone else's. It is an accident of evolution that makes us appreciate a nose at all. Far better, maybe, if we had a happy void in the center of the face. For young artists, if nobody else.</level>

        <level degree="2"><analepsis>I started out drawing a dot for a nose, as children do. I could see perfectly well that it looked nothing like a nose, but it was not at all clear what a nose did look like, so I was happy to use a dot as a stand-in until some future point when genius would come over me and I would draw it a perfect nose. Still, there were problems with the dot schema. At five I wanted to draw my mother giving suck to my baby brother. To make the action clear I had to draw a side view: a great balloon for a breast (the first breast I had ever drawn) with a red medallion at the tip, and my brother's face attached to it. But I had never drawn a face in profile before. I thought about the problem: I was not ready to draw a "realistic" profile, but the schema I had adopted, the circle, three dots and a smile, did not come with a side view. Nonetheless I had faith in it. I decided that a circle in profile was still a circle (true of rubber balls), but the dot nose, unproblematic in full face, was baffling from the side. Was the dot to be conceived as a dot, that is, as a flat circle of color? Then viewed from the side it would disappear: unacceptable solution. Or was the dot to be conceived as a small bead or button stuck onto the circle, like the nose of a teddy bear? I doubt I posed these issues so clearly to myself, but they were at the heart of my confusion. (I went with the button solution,</analepsis> <prolepsis>which caused me much embarrassed hilarity at a slightly later age. I had drawn my mother and brother looking like dogs, with protruding snouts and big black noses!)</prolepsis>

        <analepsis>The next nose paradigm was a little arc, with or without two dot nostrils (no nostrils was for beautiful princesses and other adorables. Action heroines had nostrils, and a smattering of freckles). In profile, I resorted to a sketchy, unsatisfactory bump; again, the schema had no side view. This lasted me a few years. It was my mother, annoyed by my parade of identical princesses, who blew the whistle on the pug nose. She showed me the bridge of the nose, and the way the fat knob at the end fit between the wings of the nostrils. I could see her point, but not what to do about it. It was disturbingly unclear where the nose began and ended; still, when she said I should draw a line down each side of the nose to set it off from the cheeks, I took her word for it, despite grave misgivings. On the other hand I was quite pleased to discover the little cups of the nostrils and adopt two parentheses to delineate them. The result, two slashes enclosed in parentheses, sometimes punctuated with two bold polka-dot nostrils, was weak, even in comparison to the pug nose and its limitations. It was not cute. But I felt it was the mature thing, and I stuck with it. Not for long, though; there was too much wrong with it. There were no lines between nose and cheek in the real world. There was, if anything, an elongated area of faint shadow. I could smudge my lines and approximate a shadow. But these shadows changed as the face moved; there was no longer one definitive face, there were thousands of partial and accidental ones. How could I learn them all?

        My drawings had been unproblematically winning, even to me, when they were a toss of signs onto a lassoed playing field. Now that realism was all that would do, I had years of bad drawings ahead of me. Nothing short of right was good enough. I couldn't settle for a nose-gimmick because there was no such thing as a nose, that is, what was cheek and what was nose wasn't clear, so to render either I had to render both. Drawing well was a kind of powerlessness: I had to subordinate myself to what was there, and helplessly let it have its say, whether I understood it or not; by making myself its clear medium I might look more knowing than I was, but the dirty secret was that I might never catch up to what I copied, never understand how out of gradations of smudged pencil a nose erected itself on the page.</analepsis></level>

        <level degree="2">Standing by the weeping willow tree from whose shredded fronds I had just been illicitly swinging, my friend Mary's mother told me in her humorous loud way that her mother had told her never to put a bean up her nose, because she wouldn't be able to get it out. So she put a bean up her nose to see, and it got stuck. A green bean, I wondered? No, a dried bean. Pleased I had not been scolded for shredding the fronds, I went away to mull it over. Why had her mother given her such strange advice? Who would ever think of putting a bean up her nose? And how could it get stuck? Couldn't you just press on the side of your nose and pop it out? I stuck a bean up my nose to find out. It stuck.</level>

        <level degree="2">There were all kinds of snot and all kinds of approaches to dealing with it. I scorned the heedless kids whose nostrils were packed with snot, walled up like old mine shafts, and the kids who licked the runoff from their upper lips. I was quiet and methodical about removing it and secreting it away. It was an interesting substance, a bit like amber: a viscous sap that turned into a hard clear gemstone. Elmer's glue did the same thing. I kept my gems in a little box and watched them alter. Later I began pressing them together. I made things, little figures, then began to build up a landscape on the top of my dresser. I made a tiny model of Hastings Castle, the hill, and the funicular railway (with moving parts). One day my mother, stern-faced, scraped it off into the garbage, and I was too disheartened to start over.

        Instead, I learned to blow my nose with a loud, sonorous honk, a noise memorialized in a family recording along with parakeet shrieks and my father's jovial commentary. The wind rocketed through my nose and drove everything before it, either out into a Kleenex, or simply away, into any quiet cul de sac in my sinuses.</level> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>This made me prone to ear infections for the next few years, to which I probably owe my slight deafness, obvious only in noisy bars and restaurant kitchens.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/lips.html">
        <level degree="1">The line of my upper lip is interrupted on the right side by a slight thickening where</level> <level degree="2"><analepsis>my grandparent's Dalmation Essie bit me one of the times she didn't recognize me. Something flared up in her damaged brain now and then, making everything strange. I pictured the room turning white. I was a black, ominous signature, something to flee or bite. I could tell it was coming, watching her strange sidle. I ran to the bathroom afterwards, to see the blood run down into my teeth.</analepsis></level>

        <level degree="1">Joining my upper lip to my nose is a narrow channel between two well-defined banks. I can fit the tip of my baby finger into the soft ditch.</level> <level degree="2"><analepsis>I was proud to point out this feature to my mother, who had never noticed its existence.</analepsis></level>

        <level degree="1">The little hanging swell at the center of the top lip is so sensitive that I sometimes, when I permit myself, bite and suck and pull at it so devotedly that a bit of skin peels up and dangles loose in my mouth.

        My lower lip is pierced by a labret with a flat head, which looks like a small nail through my lip. The hole is slightly to the right of what my nerves tell me is the center of my lip, and this fraction of a millimeter is enough to make me slightly edgy when I think about it. I pry and tease incessantly at the little shaft, pulling it inward by catching my tongue under the back, bending it over against my lip, and then rotating the shaft around its insertion point, like the hand of a clock. Or I catch the little metal disk between my teeth and bite at it carefully.</level>

        <level degree="2"><analepsis>After I had my teeth drilled and had to have a shot of Novocaine, I studied my lips. They were much thicker than I thought, smooth rubbery slabs that easily got in the way of my teeth. Once I asked for a consolatory treat after a trip to the dentist, and got a strawberry milkshake. I stabbed myself in the cheek with my straw several times until, with the help of the car mirror, I managed to guide the straw into my mouth. A little later, I felt a funny tickle at my collar, and looked in the mirror. A big dribble of pink had flowed all the way down my numb chin and was running down my neck. My lips, I figured out, only worked because they were conscious. Without feeling, I would leak continuously. (A principle that might hold true, I thought uncomfortably, for other parts of my body as well.)</analepsis></level>

        <level degree="1">Things I can do with my lips: I can suck in the corners of my mouth, hard, so the top and bottom lips make two soft beaks, turning my whole head into the body of a fat fish,</level> <level degree="2"><analepsis>like my mother used to do, when I sat on her lap in the rocking chair. Only she could slowly open and close the tiny parrot-fish lips, making her eyes big, while my cheeks always pop out of the clamp of my jaws, with a little squeak.</analepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/neck.html">
        <level degree="1">When I strain in a certain way a tendon in my neck pops across something, another tendon or a bone spur perhaps, and snaps back into place. When this happens, the right half of my tongue goes numb for a few seconds.</level>

        <level degree="2">In my earliest drawings, there are no necks. Then there are necks, but they are too skinny; <analepsis>the phrase "swan-like neck" had entered my consciousness and done a violence to my ideas about the body. I have coveys of princesses with necks no wider than their chins. It took a book to correct my eye and point out that the neck is a sturdy extension of the trunk, bigger around than most people's arms, not a spindly perch for the head.</analepsis></level>
        <level degree="2"><prolepsis>The next entry of the neck in my file of images is from a soft-porn science fiction novel in which enslaved lovelies writhe at a despot's feet. Entranced, I sculpted a little figure out of something described as modelling wood (I think it was no more than sawdust; you added water to make putty, then let it dry); her head was thrown back, her hands were shackled behind her back. I kept it for years on a high shelf where I supposed it would escape notice and took it down from time to time to look at it.</prolepsis></level> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>Now sometimes I put on a thick leather collar, smooth and heavy, and that little figurine pops up at the back of my mind.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/shoulders.html">
        I was proud of my muscular shoulders, molded by swimming and tennis, and I used to stand facing the bathtub, holding up a hand mirror so I could stare at the reflection of my back in the bathroom mirror. At school, though, I felt like a football player, hulking, musclebound. For some reason, almost all my friends were very short, and I loomed over them. In my mind's eye I was a leering giant, gesticulating and capering around the little people, making them laugh, just one jot off a Frankenstein monster. My parts didn't match; I couldn't even make them move smoothly together when I thought I was being watched. I scrutinized myself in the shop windows on my way home from school and cringed at my hustle, the way my butt stuck out so I could take big steps, the way my jeans strained over my thighs, the funny bulge someone might take for a penis where my jeans bunched up in front.

        Mind you, it gave me an interesting feeling to look down and see the penis-bulge. While what I really wanted was to keep the stick-figure of childhood, I wouldn't have minded a boy's body, all narrow and hard, and I might have traded in the indignity of breasts for the indignity of a penis, which at least I could bundle invisibly away. Or no, perhaps not. I remember thanking my luck that what I had between my legs was tucked neatly up and away. Everything that wiggled and hung loose seemed embarrassing to me. I wanted to be shiny and aerodynamic.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/back.html">
        <level degree="1">My back aches every time I sit down to write. Perhaps it is because of my tail; it goes numb if I sit on it, so I have to arch my back slightly to make room for it. I have always stuck my butt out; despite this habitual arch of the back I have never been able to do a backbend, even at an age when other girls could flop over easily, bendy as rubber dolls.</level>

        <level degree="2"><analepsis>In a book I liked a boy sprouted wings from his shoulder blades, so I examined my back for pin-feathers every time I felt a prickling. I lay face down on my bed and tried to imagine my wings with such conviction that reality, embarrassed, would have to give in and produce them. Slowly, not wanting to rush it, I would turn my head and peek back over my shoulder, holding the sensation steady (the weight, the counter-tensed muscles, the confusion of feathers). I must have blundered, because I saw nothing there. One day, though, fingering my shoulder blades, I did feel a rough patch. I dug my nails into it and brought around a few triangular bits of a horny material that I realized were scales. So I was changing, but into nothing so angelic as I'd pictured.Very well: I rearranged my ambitions with surprising ease. I was growing up into an outline I couldn't see, like a scribble of crayon in a coloring book, trying to guess what I'd be before I touched the edges anywhere, but I knew that whatever it was would be big and complicated. Wings, tails, extra legs: I could cope with anything but the usual.</analepsis></level>

        <level degree="1"><prolepsis>I shed my scales (I still have one, in a bed of dirty cotton: a translucent bit of nail with faint concentric stripes) and nothing more came of it, but I took it as a comforting kind of promise: anything might muscle its way out of me.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/arms.html">
        <level degree="2">At twelve I did more chin-ups than anyone else in my class, and the boys came running jubilantly across the playground and caught me up like a sports hero. The girls were exhorted to manage one chin-up. That was considered sufficient. I looked at the other girls' arms and knew I was a different animal. It did not seem possible that I could ever have wound up with arms like theirs, no matter how religiously I abstained from climbing, swinging, sawing wood. The scant flesh lying so mild over the bone, the slender arms, as uniformly tubular as sleeves. The thin wrists, the soft knuckleless hands. I couldn't admire them, nor could I despise them with any passion. Does the moose despise the antelope? My arms are an anatomist's fantasy, muscle and bone in a thin sheath of skin.</level>

        <level degree="1"><prolepsis>Weirdly, popular opinion has voted for my kind of body. Women train to look like me, and now and then come up to ask for tips. What do you do to look this way, they ask. Nothing, I say, I was born this way. I get a worried look in response. They think I'm lying. Well, I'm pretty active, I say, to help them out. I roller skate, I play tennis. They call me lucky. It is a quiet revenge for years of incredulous shrieks in bathrooms and dressing rooms. There's a boy in here! Groups of girls stand around in conference, throwing glances at me. I do my best to look indifferent. Finally a spokesperson is elected, comes up: Are you a boy or a girl? The rest cluster around. My breasts, which I would just as soon hide from the world forever, are adduced as evidence. My clothes are plucked, assessed. Sometimes the interrogation is merely curious, sometimes it is hostile. It is all horrible to me. I wish I could keep my body out of the running, go to a third restroom, the one for monsters and hermaphrodites.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/phantom_limb.html">
        <level degree="2"><analepsis>I discovered my phantom limb in fifth grade, when I stubbed a member I didn't have against a tether-ball pole and asked to be excused from gym. My teacher was unsympathetic, but later on my classmates rallied around me and one of them, Vonda, said knowingly, "It's got to be a phantom limb; my uncle has one."</analepsis></level> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>I learned to be more careful with my phantom limb, and it has saved me more than once.</prolepsis></level> <level degree="2"><analepsis>I locked myself into the hallway an hour before I was meant to show up to receive my MFA: my phantom limb kicked open the door.</analepsis></level> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>When I'm tired after hours behind the counter at work I can put down my phantom limb like a kick-stand and lean against it, so that I stand at a slight, imperceptible tilt. My phantom limb tires fast, but is very strong. I can't run on it, the choreography would be too confusing, but it is handy when I go rollerskating as a sort of sideboard motor or a brake. There are many other uses for it, in fact it has thousands, as lever, probe, and truncheon. But it is more ( or maybe less) than helpmeet. Though my native tendency is to avoid conflict, with my phantom limb I have kicked, tripped, goosed, tweaked, rabbit-punched, poked, pulled, pinched and pried.</prolepsis></level> <level degree="2"><analepsis>Once, bored at dinner, I came to attention to discover that my phantom limb had slid up under the skirts of the woman opposite, a writer of whom I was rather in awe, and was paddling with its phantom toes in her august parts. She seemed to approve, but I was mortified.</analepsis></level> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>My phantom limb has kicked people, then tucked itself up and left me to run away on my own; it is an irresponsible limb, a gadfly and a turncoat.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/armpits.html">
        <level degree="2">I was induced to shave my underarm hair by my mother, I think, though I don't remember it. It was high school, I was playing sports, and I reeked. My dry, stainless, odorless child body had shivered all over and metamorphosed into a stinking, sweating, oozing hulk sprouting hair. I found myself disgusting. I tried a few deodorants that only added the stink of perfumed toilet paper to my own smell and turned my t-shirts yellow under the arms. I sweated so much more than any of the other girls did. Whether I was losing to them or beating them, they looked the same: pink, a little moist. My sweat sprang off my face when I shook my head, ran down my arm and made the racquet grip slip in my hand. My gym clothes hardened into origami in my locker overnight.

        If my mother did coerce me to shave it was to control the stench. Shaving was violent and painful. My blood made pink rivulets through the soap suds. I detested the stiff, shiny stubble springing up in the white skin, visible as a blue shadow even before the adamantine tip emerged. Deodorant stung like citric acid in my cringing pits. But armpit hair was grotesque, I thought. Then one day a fascinatingly bad girl made one of her rare appearances in Trigonometry with a bush of black underarm hair sticking out of her pale, fleshy armpit, in the gap between her green tube top and the shirt she wore open on top. I stared at the hair, trying to parse it. Bad girls had sex. She flaunted her underarm hair. Maybe people who had sex liked hair. I kept looking at it, to check whether I was disgusted or not. It made me feel like I was looking up her skirt. I disapproved of the hair, but was it possibly also kind of sexy? This idea hung on tenaciously.</level> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>A few years later I grew my own underarm hair. It is profuse and sexy, and I feel strangely tender toward it, as if it were a small animal I carry under each arm.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/skin.html">
        <level degree="2">There was one good thing about the uncomfortable plastic chairs I sat in all through grade school: if I rubbed my arm against the back of the chair on a dry day, I got a funny feeling as if there were a layer of warm felt between my skin and the plastic. If I held my arm the right distance away, every hair stretched straight out toward the plastic. Then if I moved it slightly further away, every hair would droop in unison. With infinitesimal movements, invisible to everyone else, I could make my hairs straighten and bow, straighten and bow.</level>


        <level degree="2">I swam on the neighborhood swim team every day all summer long, and wound up with stars and stripes on my stomach and my butt, a faint duplicate of my swimsuit, with light and dark reversed like a photographic negative. Inspired, I snipped a cursive S out of cloth tape and stuck it to my shoulder, replacing it when necessary, and by the end of the summer when I took it off my initial was emblazoned in white on my tan shoulder. I was a little disappointed, though: in the mirror--my best view of it--it was reversed, and looked like an &amp;.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/other_bodies.html">
        The women's swimsuits cut into their rounded backs like the strings around roasts. Their backs were a deep mottled red brown, shiny like beetles. Their bodies presented startling features: a soft, strangely independent pot belly on an otherwise skinny body, little puckers all around it; a pale lobe of flesh hanging off the back of an arm, with little dents like thumb-prints in it. They held these deformities up to the sun as if to be made well by it. So did their husbands, boldly presenting their hard, massive stomachs like shields. Some of the men had bosoms, borne up on their fat stomachs, crowned with little crests of hair. I was afraid to look at them. I remember crouching over a water jet in the shallows of the park pool, which had once been a natural pool and had the sloping sides of one, while legs and crotches went by me, striding up all sheathed in water, or haltingly descending with coy small steps. I looked no higher than their hips because I was embarrassed to look at their faces, partly out of simple shyness, but also because I was afraid they would read the curiosity and the passionate disdain I felt for them in my eyes. I despised them because they rarely swam. Tanning was their primary occupation. They brought coolers and radios and arranged them in clusters around their lawn chairs. It was as if they were marking out invisible houses on the lawn. Carefully, they fit their wet bodies into the lawn chairs and worked their way back to the correct angle. They spoke out of the sides of their mouths, to keep their faces pointed at the sun. They were pleased with themselves. The tanner they were, the more pleased with themselves they were. I understood that my own grown-ups were extraordinary because they were pale and because they swam. Despite my scorn for the tanners, I felt a tender, resentful embarrassment for my own grandparents, who pedalled their large, pale bodies around in the water, laughing and clowning with us. My grandmother wore blue swim goggles and floated serenely on her back, her colorful swimsuit rising in a dome to the sky. My grandfather guffawed and splashed us, his sparse chest hair making river patterns between his pale breasts. Stubbornly I played with them, aware of mocking eyes on us. I judged myself very harshly for being aware. My grandparents were sublime in their buoyant unconcern.

        My own body was, I felt, invisible. It was difficult to negotiate the field of crossed gazes between my towel and the pool, but I knew my sudden feeling of unhappy celebrity was my own invention. I didn't register, I was like a stick figure, of which you don't ask, is it well drawn, is it beautiful? My body was the engine that propelled a pair of eyes through the world.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/tattoos.html">
        <level degree="1">I have twenty-eight tattoos, of which two are visible. On my right arm, over my triceps, I have a black ampersand, about one and a half inches high. I have a black vortex on the inside of my left ankle.</level> <level degree="2"><analepsis>I got tired of answering questions ("and what?") about my tattoos, so I had the remaining work done in ink the exact color of my skin. It was tough to persuade the tattoist that this was what I really wanted, and he was a little afraid he would have trouble staying within the lines, but in the end he got interested in the problem.</analepsis></level> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>I am virtually covered in tattoos. I teach my lovers to read them but they are otherwise entirely private, except when I get a sunburn and parts of them show up as pale swirls in the red.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/breasts.html">
        <level degree="2">The first breasts I remember belonged to: my mother, a big cheerful woman at the pool in a green flowered swimsuit with a gaping neckline (I loitered around hoping I might be able to see down it), and Playboy. I I had been introduced to Playboy at the age of seven by my best friend, whose father had stacks of them on his back porch. Oddly, it was not the centerfolds that interested me. It was the cartoon dames with the zeppelin breasts and outsized nipples. I was interested in breasts: I made breasts out of clay for my flat-chested dolls, and little bras from cloth tape and telephone wire. I sat with my best friend under a blanket and we took turns reading the sexy bits of Are You There God? It's Me, Margaret out loud to each other, speculating about our own future developments.</level>

        <level degree="2"><prolepsis>But the arrival of breasts was traumatic. A few months before they showed up I swam in the river in my cut-offs with no shirt on and nobody cared. Then the area around my nipples began to ache and swell, and my mother gently suggested I keep my shirt on. That summer I was spending a lot of time in a tree house a few blocks from home, over the wall at the back of the parking lot behind the church. One day I needed something, string or wire or a knife, and I started running home. I had to stop; my breasts hurt with every step. I couldn't run without pressing my forearms to my chest.

        I was filled with an objectless fury. My breasts were making me not me (it was not me to walk, or guard my chest, or keep myself covered up). My mother and I went to a department store to shop for bras. It was humiliating even to stand there, in my tennis shoes and stinky t-shirt, waist deep in the frilly white and beige things with their arcane, embarrassing straps and clips. I would have nothing with lace, nothing with flowers. The antique saleswoman, her own bosom fused and immobile, walked right into the dressing room to confer with my mother about my size, as if my breasts were now the public provenance of all womankind. Bras made me feel like I couldn't breathe, but at least I could run without clutching my chest. I spent high school giving my shoulders sidelong glances, to see if the straps were showing, and fiddling with safety pins to keep them in. If possible, I would have no one know I wore a bra at all; it was like making a public announcement that I had breasts. I hated having breasts: dangling, ridiculous extras. I was no longer streamlined: gravity had a taunting grip on me.</prolepsis></level>

        <level degree="2"><analepsis>I learned to draw breasts before I had any, shading them carefully, keeping an eye on all those Adams and Eves to assess my progress. No matter how well formed, they looked wrong, but it took me a while to understand why. I had forgotten about gravity. Breasts hang: the ones I drew stuck straight out at the level of the armpits, like the Playboy breasts before them.</analepsis> <prolepsis>Later I saw beautiful drag queens who looked wrong in an eerily familiar way and recognized the same fault in their antigrav breasts.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/hands.html">
        <level degree="1">My middle fingers curve away from my thumb. On my right hand my writer's callous, building up the outside of the curve, makes my finger look even more awry. On my left hand that finger locks straight sometimes under pressure, as when I am masturbating or playing guitar. My forefingers were always marked (and are today) with magic-marker dots and dashes.</level>

        <level degree="2"><analepsis>In elementary school I spun on the bars every recess; the backs of my knees were sometimes too bruised to perform without someone's jacket wrapped around the bar to cushion it. Sore callouses built up at the base of each finger, and were squeezed into hard yellow ridges by my grip on the bars. I liked my callouses, which made me feel tough. I stick pins through them and waved them in my brother's face to convince him I was a witch.</analepsis></level>

        <level degree="1">The only part of other people's bodies for which I feel the instant sympathy I feel for dogs, any kind of dog, is their hands. I look at the bodies trundling past, grinning and tilting like carnival cut-outs you're meant to hit with bean bags, and I can't see past the paint. Watching a herd of goats would be more personal. But in their hands I glimpse their souls. Hands are naive, usually: unconsciously curling, or tending to things with a kind of earnest helpfulness it's impossible not to find endearing. I can't even describe it as earnest, because it is devoid of attitude, hands do what hands do, even when they are attached to the cuffs of a wicked man. Watching their movements I know a person had to be there to learn to do those things. It is like watching a dog with a mean master: in their knowledge of each other you can see the record of days, not all of them bad, a bungled love struggling between them, and it's like that with hands: in their essential bewilderment and their willingness, they betray the grudging humanity of their owners.</level>

        <level degree="2">Holding up my hands against the sun, or cupping the light of a flashlight, I looked at the bones inside, a shadow in a luminous mantle. It was the secret of my death waiting to wear its way out of me, a centimeter under the skin, reaching for what I touched. Hiding in there like proof.</level>

        <analepsis><level degree="2">I broke my baby finger playing follow the leader on bikes with my brother and sister. I was the leader, and looking back over my shoulder to egg them on, I veered too close to a vine-covered chain-link fence. My finger caught in the fence and when I looked down it was sticking out at a right angle to the others. I couldn't push it back in place. This bothered me more than the pain did. I was filled with horror at myself, as if I'd suddenly become a stranger, the kind of embarrassing person to whom gruesome things happen, things that touch the victims with a little blame for their share in shocking us. My mother pulled up in her car as promptly as if I had planned it, home from work, and we went to the doctor, who made jokes while he took a pen from his pocket, laid it in the saddle between my weird finger and the others, and banged the finger back in its socket. The shock of it made me guffaw, though I was secretly resentful that he had handled me so lightly.

        I had to wear a cast that covered my whole hand and wrist, which made everyone imagine I was much more badly hurt than I was. People who wouldn't ordinarily talk to me came up to ask me what had happened - it might have been the making of me, only my damage was so pathetically little, that I imagined I saw them bridle at the fraudulent bid for their sympathies, and hastened to explain, almost apologize, not wanting to seem to claim credit for pain I hadn't suffered. I would have preferred a cast commensurate with my injury, and tried to play down the whole thing, more embarrassed than anything else by the celebrity of my finger.</level>

        <level degree="2">Though hands and feet were my most reliable artist's models, the naked ladies of page after page, I could not, when I was drawing a scene, net these poses from memory and attach them where they belonged, at the end of arms and legs. My swashbuckling heroines had their hands in their pockets, their feet in high grass; my princesses hid their hands in their skirts. Unpocketed hands frayed into a vague fringe of pencil strokes. It was a grim relief when I set to learning hands, memorizing the shapes. Tiring to discover I could never settle on any rendition because every turn revealed a new personality. There were as many hands as sparrows and I could hardly catalog them all. Every so often though, my pencil left some careless line that humped off the page with extraordinary meaningfulness, more knowledgeable than I would ever be. I learned to recognize the truth in the accident; I pirated chance for booty.</level></analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/skeleton.html">
        I can always give myself a funny feeling by picturing what my skeleton is doing. It startles me that I have a skeleton at all. Skeletons are another species, it seems to me, beings of a drily humorous sort, antic fellows who can't keep track of all their parts. They are whole unto themselves. My skeleton doesn't need me, I think. It's waiting me out, tolerating my spasms, my ambitions. When I am kissing someone and our teeth bump together, jarring us both, I think: our skeletons touched.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/teeth.html">
        <level degree="1">I am always teething. My gums are so sensitive that any time I even think of them (as now, writing) I want to fiddle with them. My tongue pries at the little points where my gums tuck between adjacent teeth. I like to floss or pick my teeth because I like the pain, and the more it hurts the more pleasure I get from it, so I saw and dig with ever-increasing brutality. My gums start to bleed. Every so often I stop to gingerly clack my jaws together. There is a metallic taste in my mouth. Behind the last tooth on my lower jaw on each side there is a chubby flap of skin where it seems another tooth is always on the verge of coming in, and where even poking with my tongue gives me some pleasure. But the sturdy smidgens can take a lot more abuse. Sometimes, though I know I'll regret it, I take a spoon and poke it under the flap, prying up until I feel the fibers strain and pop.</level> <level degree="2"><analepsis>I wrenched out my baby teeth with similar relish.</analepsis></level> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>Later, when the riot is over, I feel both amused and ashamed, my gums swollen into caricatures, so sore I can hardly chew.</prolepsis></level>

        <level degree="2"><analepsis>The first teeth I drew belonged to monsters and were shaped like long, tapering V's. The first human grin I drew also looked like a monster's. The problem was that if I outlined each individual toothas an impulse toward accuracy instructed me to dothe smile seemed ghoulishly crowded. What's more, teeth are all different, and to stuff a smile with a row of identicals threw a drawing subtly out of whack, yet to try to sketch the idiosyncracies of each tooth seemed as finicky as painting a portrait of every single leaf on a tree in the background. I had seen ads in which the teeth were painted as a single bar of white. That looked better at a casual glance, but viewed more closely it looked like the happy surfers and smokers had a mouth guard clamped in their jaws. Teeth made me wonder what realism really was. When you drew a tree you didn't draw each leaf, but only because, I thought, it was too huge a task. But with teeth it seemed there was such a thing as too much accuracy. Realism lay slightly short of the exact copy. This surprised and unsettled me.</analepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/fingernails.html">
        <level degree="2">At one point, studying the world for signs, I pretended that I could read the future in the white clouds rising slowly behind the pink panes. But, like all systems of augury I invented myself, there was a flavor of phony about it.</level>

        <level degree="2">In my tumbling class at the Y I grabbed quick looks at the little girls' tiny nails daubed pink and wondered at how different their lives were from mine. My nails were chewed ragged and rimmed with dirt. Sometimes I colored them black with pencil when I was bored in class. More recherche were the fake fingernails I snipped for myself out of fruit leather at lunchtime and stuck on with spit, to my friends' disgust. I privately thought they looked glamorous.</level>

        <level degree="2"><analepsis>When I was five, I slit open the fourth finger on my right hand with a razor blade my babysitter, Miss Mudd, had left lying around. I cut through my fingernail right up to my first knuckle,</analepsis></level> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>where the scar dwindles to a pale line, and my fingernail has a point at the apex of its arch like certain cathedral windows - the style is called ogee - and has a ridge bisecting it which at the nail end is a weak spot where the nail tends to split. It is an arcane detail, a devil's mark, neither beautiful nor ugly, but it reminds me of myself, like the scar on my upper lip.</prolepsis></level>

        <level degree="2"><analepsis>My sister sucked her thumb, but I chewed my nails. When I was five or six, everyone in my class were given a daily piece of fruit at school and ate it in unison. Bananas and apples were fine with me, but oranges made my heart sink. I dug what was left of my nails into the peel. A thick, sticky scum collected under my nails. The raw skin under my nails and my ragged cuticles started stinging. We had to rise from our desks and leave the room in single file past a washroom where, if I was lucky and the monitor was kind, I could wash my hands. If not, I sat through prayers with burning fingers, desperate to be done.</analepsis></level> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>Since then, I hate to have anything sticky or slimy on my hands: tree sap, Crisco, what slugs exude.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/elbow.html">
        <level degree="1">On old people the pad of thickened flesh, divvied up into hexagons by criss-crossed creases, hangs in the softer folds of the back of the arm. It is powdered white with dry skin.</level> <level degree="2"><analepsis>At one point I was terrified of allowing that to happen to me.</analepsis></level> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>Now I don't think about my elbows at all: what happened to my parents is happening to me, my attention has lapsed, the upholsterers are sneaking up on me.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/organs__internal.html">
        While I know that the inside of my body is a dense press of lubricated meats

        I can't help seeing it as hollow space, like the inside of a trunk.

        Each elusive hint of sensation from one of my organs is a glint of colored light
        that reveals the organ hanging there like a Christmas tree ornament,
        so it's never lightless inside, but a warm, ruddy dark.

        It is a secret, busy space, and when I imagine myself inside it, I am filled with glee and self-satisfaction.
        It is mysterious in there
        and so when I can track the passage of some bubble through the labyrinthine turns of my intestines
        I feel like an archeologist unearthing the passages of a royal tomb under the featureless sands of the desert,
        pleased, but slightly uneasy about laying bare such an deliberately private structure.

        When something goes wrong with the inside of my body
        I feel woebegone
        in a more than physical way;
        my feelings are hurt, my trust seems to have been betrayed.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/stomach.html">
        My stomach is white and completely flat, and consequently unfit for bellydancing, which nonetheless I work at, off and on. Bellydancing has taught me to roll and flutter it, though awkwardly and unreliably. When I was little, I could suck my stomach in and make a cave or stick it out in a resilient dome that sounded like a drum when I tapped it.

        I have a gold ring through the little lip of flesh at the bottom of my belly button. When I am writing, I lock myself to my desk by a chain through my navel ring. Otherwise I would get up every five minutes to clip my toenails or refill the ice trays. The chain, which is short, forces me to sit upright, which relieves the back-aches I am otherwise prone to.

        The weight of the links - it is not a heavy chain - is enough to make me aware of my bondage, and strangely, this is a relief; it stops me from wondering where else I might want to be..
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/hips.html">
        <level degree="1">My hips are narrow and hard like a boy's. The white skin pulls thin over the muscles; when I twist my body, one muscle pulls a long hollow all the way across my hip.</level> <analepsis><level degree="2">I never understood hips, what or even exactly where they were, though I knew the womanly hip was supposed to be a desireable entity from occasional soft-core pornographic passages in novels (I remember the phrase, "churning hips"). My hip was an indeterminate straight stretch connecting my stomach to my legs. There was nothing there to linger over.</level>

        <level degree="2">I wrote a paper for my seventh grade World History class about the early statues of the ancient Greeks, a regiment of stiff dignitaries, their hair in rosettes that looked like Danish pastries. They stood with one foot awkwardly advanced, marching out of history, buttocks clenched, holes bored for pupils: a nordic brotherhood, bleached white. The early ones were porous and worn, pitted like corncobs, their muscles more sketched than sculpted by a few straight slashes  across the torso. One of the few featured muscles in these simpler years was a marked bulge over the crest of the hip bone, and it perplexed me. I couldn't find that muscle on my own body, which was in other ways a lot like the slim teenage boys' the Greeks idealized. The next year, a friend and I invited ourselves into the pottery studio at the university and huddled together at one of the tables, making identical naked men out of red clay, outstretched flat like corpses. I incorporated the ancient Greek muscle, pleased with myself, sure my man would be realer and more complete than my friend's man. But when I showed her my finished work, she made fun of me; I had sculpted a little penis, but left out the balls. I had known there was some complicated business down there, but I wasn't sure if there was a real thing there with a definite shape, or just an unsignifying mess that you might leave out, for clarity. Hot-faced, I copied her work. Adding the balls made me guilty and ashamed. I felt high-minded about the penis: the ancient Greeks certainly knew about the penis. The penis was a simple, legendary fact, and to leave it out would be infantile. But the balls had no mythological status; they were smut. To include them was a sign of dubious knowledge, first, and prurient interest, second. We hid the men in the back rows of the drying racks, behind the pots. I was glad to distance myself from them, go outside to cool my burning cheeks.</level></analepsis>

        <level degree="1"><prolepsis>I have a small mole on my right hip, from which two springy dark hairs grow, shaved off whenever I shave my legs, though I don't otherwise shave my upper thighs. Across my hips at the widest point are pale striations with a faint sheen to them, like a crochetted net just under the skin, like the cream curdling in coffee, just a little, and collecting into pale skeins. Though it is 'cellulite,' word that sounds like the brand name for a packing peanut, and makes me think of dank dressing rooms and curdy flesh glimpsed under a slipped towel, it is beautiful, like the brindle in a tabby cat's coat. Of course, it is also strange and worrying, like all things that turn up late in the day.</prolepsis> <analepsis>I sanguinely thought I could avoid change by unremitting emanations of my will, a steady, comforting glow I could bask in my whole life, a tadpole in a puddle. The rays would melt off anomalies and excrescences, pits and bumps; I would keep the body I had as a kid, which was entirely malleable, almost boneless, uncharted and unrated, neither good nor bad, but springy and invisible like an angel's.</analepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/vagina.html">
        <level degree="2">For years I was confused about where exactly pee came from. It seemed to come from the little tip that stuck out and forward between the lips, but that would indicate a hole, and as far as I could see there wasn't one. The lack of a hole was just one puzzle in the whole puzzling arrangement between my legs, where somewhere there was also supposed to be a hole big enough to let a baby out someday, but where there seemed to be nothing but a convoluted surface of folds overlapping folds. It's not that I was uncurious. As soon as I was alone in bed, my hands slid down into my pajamas to their resting place between my legs. I liked to pull at the flaps of skin, let them spring back. I plowed my finger through the tacky folds, deciphering them. The landscape between my legs was hard to map, though, and I was content not to understand it yet. If there was a vagina in there, it didn't seem to be any concern of mine, any more than those other organs mooted about, whose functions I hardly understood, the kidney, the liver. (When I heard those words, all I pictured was the small, dense lumps from inside the chicken, simmering in a pan, to be picked out with toothpicks.) The sheets were heavy and smelly. Underneath was my laboratory, where painstaking researches went on. Progress was slow and scarcely resembled progress at times, the findings were so bewildering, my methods so whimsical. I was more like an alchemist than a modern scientist, interested in intuitions, affinities, not in logic or proof. I pottered about in the steam, my hands silent confidants of my secret parts. I pulled, I plucked, I unstuck fold from fold. So dedicated was my curiosity that when, later, the inner folds, which had been neat and small, stretched until they sprawled over the outer lips, I thought I had damaged myself, made myself into a freak: half boy, half girl.

        It upset me that I'd never know what it felt like to have a penis. The division of the sexes seemed like a grotesque blunder, as all-around unfair as if some people were born without eyes and others born without ears. We couldn't even compare notes: there was no zero degree of pleasure we could measure from. It was the same discovery I had made about colors: I couldn't know whether I meant the same thing by "red" as anyone else did. I could describe what I saw, but what I would evoke in someone else would not be my red, but theirs.</level>

        <level degree="2"><prolepsis>I concentrate my thoughts on the front of me, the tip of my clitoris, the vague ache in my crotch, and thrust it all forward in my mind. I throw my legs far apart so no touch of thigh to thigh reminds me that nothing hangs between. I imagine all my sensations the same but elongated, turned into the protruding tip of me, rather than pocketed, swallowed. For a second, a cock erects itself over my pubic bone. Then it shivers, it falls to pieces.</prolepsis></level>

        <analepsis><level degree="2">For years I referred to everything between my legs as my "bottom"("if we crawled under that house and there was a crack in the floor and a lady was standing over it we could look up her dress and see her bottom," I said, my last such usage, to which my friend responded with a scathing, "her bottom?")</level>

        <level degree="2">I began inserting the pages of books into my vagina as soon as I located that orifice. In fact, my libidinal attachment to books sped my exploration. I was in the habit of tearing off the corners of pages as I read and chewing them into pulp. I became quite a connoisseur of the different flavors and textures. You could truthfully call me a voracious reader. I delayed tearing off the first little piece as long as I could, but after the first rip I figured I had committed myself and might as well carry on, though I was reprimanded for chewing books that didn't belong to me, like my aunt's brand new copy of Chitty-Chitty-Bang-Bang. Though labelled a vandal and a hooligan by librarians, I have always felt the warmest affection for books. Why else would I want to ingest them? Later on I read a description of this malady, considered a nervous ailment. I was lumped in with eaters of mud and sand, which seems to me quite another thing, though not without appeal. There is a good word for it: pica, which also, appropriately enough in my case, is a unit of size used in measuring type. (Spelled pika, it's a little rodent.) I did not consider myself to be suffering a nervous ailment, of course. I liked the taste of books. New white paper, pulpy yellowing paper (dissolves), glossy coated paper that squeaked between the teeth, whose sharp triangular edges needed to be cautiously bitten blunt, I liked it, and also liked the cud I chewed it into, and considered it as good as gum, though lacking in flavor. In fact, on the theory that delicate things are more toothsome, and that everything tastes better with sugar, I once served a tea-party desert of moistened Kleenex with sugar on top. It was disgusting; I speculated that it would have been better not to use scented Kleenex, but the experiment was so emphatically unsuccessful that I never had another try.

        It wasn't a big leap from eating books to sticking them up me, a page at a time. Fine literature in my vagina, pulp fiction up my ass, that was my instinctive decision, that is at first, before I began to question whether the distinction was really so clear. I sat through English class with Chaucer and Boccaccio here, S. E. Hinton there. One day, when I fished out the slippery wad, laid it on my desk and teased its folds open with a pen, I noticed that some of the words seemed changed. I took the stinking page to the library and confirmed my discovery in the echoing stacks. My vagina had rewritten Joyce. It was then I knew I was going to be a writer.

        I also found, and would like to share with other women, that a dictionary in a pocket edition, if well worn, can be rolled up and used as a tampon in case of need.</level></analepsis>

        <level degree="2"><prolepsis>Later on, though hardly tiring of the printed page, I experimented with other objects. Talking on the phone to my best friend, I inserted the receiver into my cunt, then bent over and yelled endearments in the direction of my womb. She said she heard me say: sample my donuts. I said nothing of the kind. This should be taken into consideration by parents seeking to give their kids an edge by pre-natal read-alouds. I have also inserted dolls, dice, piano keys, and school filing cabinets with hanging files in alphabetical order. (I would not do that again. I did it on a bet.) My vagina has very long and sticky lips and sometimes I would stroll pantyless through a store in a short skirt, brushing nonchalantly against the merchandise, and come out with valuable items stuck to me. I always felt these goods were mine by right, as they had attached themselves to me like burrs without my deliberate intervention, though once, when I began dragging a whole sofabed out the door behind me, I was hard put to explain this reasoning to the manager; but his embarrassment won the day for me, and in the end I even prevailed on him to help me load the sofabed into my car.</prolepsis></level>

        <level degree="1">When I have my period my body aches from my ribs to my knees. I feel like I am melting from the center outward, like a candle. Or I'm dissolving into silt and flowing toward the ocean on my own slow river.

        With a razor, I carve a labyrinth into my pubic hair, and require my lovers to find their way through it. This is not whimsy, it is practical. By the time they have traced their way through it to the end, the most backwards suitor will find me ready for them.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/butt.html">
        <level degree="1">My celebrated butt. I take it as a gift, a windfall. I've done nothing to earn the encomiums. It is mildly humorous to be congratulated for something I didn't work for and can't see, stuck on the back of me. It is like when I am walking my dog and someone says, what a beautiful dog. Do I say thank you, as if he had complimented my dress, or yes, she certainly is, as if he had complimented my best friend? I have a beautiful dog. I like her too. Thank you very much.</level>

        <level degree="2"><analepsis>Walking home from school at seven, I watched the masses of flesh shift in the woman's butt ahead of me, wondering whether women really did wiggle their hips when they walked, which I thought was dumb, and if so, whether the woman in front of me was "wiggling her hips" on purpose, or whether her hips were just wiggling, as anyone's would, from the weight swinging back and forth. I wouldn't wiggle my hips if I could help it, and I'd rather have no hips to wiggle.</analepsis></level> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>Genetics has sided with me on that prejudice.

        But drawing is an antidote to judgement: skin pulled over bone is beautiful, so is bulge and sag. At one time or another, learning to draw, I have been obsessed with every part of the human body. The butt is no exception. With a sharp pencil I incise an arc into the paper to mark the crease where the mass of the buttock wedges into the back of the thigh. The fat swells on both sides of the crease, then smooths off down into the back of the thigh. If I smudge the whole area, I can take an eraser and slather the top of the buttocks with light, wrap a faint shimmer of reflected light around the undersides, run a little gleam down the curve of the tailbone. Could I mistake this doting attention for disinterested curiosity? Drawing is almost sex.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/tail.html">
        <level degree="2">I was born with a short tail, which my parents decided not to have removed when I was a baby, since I seemed to take so much pleasure in it, curling it around my own wrist, whipping it on my buttocks when I was itchy or testy, and dragging small objects into my crib with it. When I was old enough to realize none of the other kids had a tail, though, I became furiously ashamed of it. I said nothing to my parents, who had gotten quite used to it, but when I went to school I pulled it forward and squeezed it between my thighs to stop its waggish commentary. At home I subjected it to horrors: sat on it, hung weights from it, clamped clothespins on it.

        I tied it to the doorknob and tried to run away from it. I failed, but I did manage, in time, to subdue its temperament, and to keep it coiled, barely twitching, in the seat of my pants. It even shrank a little, atrophied from lack of use. When I finally got it out and had a look at it for the first time in years at the end of high school, it lay limp and slightly damp across the palm of my hand like a part of someone else's body. I had to coax it to move, a nerve-wracking process like learning to wiggle one eyebrow, writing, or practising scales, after which I had to slouch into my bedroom to masturbate. In time, though, it came back to life.</level>

        <level degree="2"><prolepsis>It thickened and grew lithe. At night in bed it explored, violating me shamelessly. Every morning I had to perch on the sink and wash my dirty tail. My freshman year of college I fell asleep after a late night of study in my best friend's room. Sometime in the night we shoved the books off the bed, turned off the light and climbed under the sheets. I remember her hard back against mine. In the morning I woke up with a yellow highlighter marker under my right shoulder blade and an uneasy feeling. I slid my hand down and felt my tail; it was slightly tacky, and the longer hairs at the tip were stuck together. My friend rolled over and looked at me. I started explaining: my tail wandered in its sleep, I had no knowledge or control, it had happened to me many times, it should have occurred to me that something like this might happen one day, I should have kept my jeans on, I didn't mean it. I stopped. She gave me a long, strange look, her brows knit. What? I said. She plunged her arm under me, closed her fist firmly around my tail, rolled me onto my side, my back to her. Then she guided me inside her. I lay there staring perplexedly at the wall while she panted and strained behind me, sketching out a new world for me.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/legs.html">
        When nobody else was around or willing to sit still for me, I drew whatever I could see of myself: my feet, for example; my legs. What my eyes showed me, though, looked very strange on paper. My dinky, knobbly feet were hitched to spindly ankles that swelled like a bellows to the knee, then widened even further to my thighs. My massive, conical thighs were like two funnels jammed to the bottom of a grain hopper, which was my squarish torso, big as a house. I was a funky headless homunculus with linebacker shoulders and Tinkerbell toes. It was the truth (from my perspective), but what use was it to art? In my renderings of all-I-could-see, I had better leave myself out, or regard myself in a mirror, at a safe distance. Look too closely, I noted, and you will see monsters. Realism, and possibly reality itself, is reticence and fudging it.

        I was a scholar of legs, carrying on my investigations down on the bricks or flagstones, among the grown-ups' feet. Here I am with my jacks, my tops, my patterns in the dirt. Around me are the tree-trunks of legs, with their tropical growths, the parasitic vines of their varicose veins, the gorgeous locoweed of burst blood vessels. The wild hairs standing off the stretched, dessicated skin, or the coarse black stubble, hard as jet. My grandfather's knobbly knees were crude and overlarge, like the club of a cartoon caveman. Feet were battered arcane shapes, polished in places to patent leather.

        I looked at my own body: flesh still growing is almost spirit, it clasps the bone, doesn't hang from it, you hardly recognize it as a substance. Grown-up flesh has more and more in common with sand, bark, old canvas, rust and mud. We resemble inanimate things more and more, until one day we become one. But at the time, casting judgement with my jacks, I wondered why they had let themselves come to such a pass. Flesh was thought, corrupt thought corrupted flesh, but will could strain and clarify both thought and flesh. That was my despotic fantasy. At what point did their attention lapse? I wouldn't let that happen to me.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/leg_hair.html">
        <level degree="2">I left my leg hair unshaved all through high school. It was thick and sun-bleached so it had coppery glints in it and I adored it, especially the little fringe around my ankles where it petered out. I sat on my front stoop in the late afternoon sun and twisted it into little dreadlocks or made vain humorous attempts at french-braiding it which made my friends shriek. I knew I was sometimes the butt of jokes but I thought it was stupid to shave my legs, and have a field of stubble in place of fuzz. But my leg hairs got blacker and more profuse, and I started to envy my friends with white-blonde hair that didn't show. Though I still liked to look at it on my naked body, sticking out from under clothes it looked incongruous. Crushed and writhing under stockings, like my Trigonometry teacher's, it frightened me. I shaved it off.</level>

        <level degree="2"><prolepsis>For years the razor was seized and won back by opposing camps. I shaved my leg hair defensively, I grew it back dogmatically, I shaved it guiltily, I grew it back proudly, I shaved it experimentally, I grew it back humorously. I shaved it.</prolepsis></level> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>Objectively, philosophically, morally: fishnets look better on shaved legs.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/knees.html">
        <level degree="1">My knees were so often marked by scabs that they still look naked without them, and when I see someone with a skinned knee, I feel a warm fellow-feeling, hearty and a little envious. I like the sheer page-white of the first instant. Then the measles of blood that decorate the white, then the slow, rich flow of blood down my leg, a warm thick worm. It's comforting, almost like lotion. After the blood stops, I like the thick slippery translucent skin of pink stuff, sticky as fresh Jell-o, coming up in stuck-to-finger-tip peaks when you touch it. This goes stiff, like a bit of cardboard stuck to the skin, then even stiffer. It is as if I weirdly grew a shard of crockery! I like the feeling of the scab stretching when I bend my knees, and bunching when I straighten them. Repeated, this action wears creases in the scab, which eventually cracks. Then blood and pain again.</level>

        <level degree="2"><analepsis>Watching films of volcanoes in school, I recognized myself: the black crust cracked, the hot-orange lava welled up, darkening, and hardened into new crust. I was planetary!</analepsis></level>

        <level degree="1"><prolepsis>I haven't mentioned the sweet, rich smell of the open cut. (I'd sit hugging my legs, and bow my head to smell my knees with a private smile.) Or how the scab would soften in the bath, like an old newspaper in the rain. Or discussed prying at the sides of the scab, which were raised like a dinner plate's, only to find it was still stuck on by a dot of raw meat in the middle.

        Hairs grow up through the scab, like blades of grass through the old doormat we left to rot in our hideout. The hairs sew the scab to the skin underneath. The scab breaks up but hangs on. You scratch it off in bits. Underneath the new skin is hard and white.</prolepsis></level>

        <level degree="2"><analepsis>When I was five I ran whooping down the steep slope from the yard to the road in Falls Church, Virginia, accompanied by skipping, rolling, half-airborne pebbles and crumbs of dirt, and the moving surface got whisked out from under my by some trick and I found myself sliding on both knees down the slope, until I tumbled over the curb into the road. There was no one to see what a terrible thing had just happened to me, so I didn't cry, just got up, shocked and lonesome under the happy Crayola sky. I toiled, suddenly small, up the long, long driveway. I realized something about time: that the moment was lost forever when I could have righted myself and skidded down in triumph. The present stretched out gravelly and mundane as a driveway and for the whole length of it I was bleeding and a blunderer. At some point I would reach the house and my mother would comfort me for my bleeding knees, but I already no longer needed comfort. That would also come too late.</analepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/shins.html">
        <level degree="1">My shins are slightly bumpy and when I get a tan, mottled with tiny white dots as with sunlight through leaves. The dots are faded scars, dozens of them of different vintages, criss-crossed and overlaid. The newest is a slight hollow on my left leg,</level> <level degree="2"><analepsis>got when I slid down a bit of the Rocky Mountains three years ago.</analepsis></level> <level degree="2"><analepsis>When I was little I acquired them more often.

        Over and over I ran full-tilt into my bedroom and threw myself onto my bed, banging my shins on the metal frame, hidden under the bright coverlet. I took a breath in the pause before the pain hit. Then rolled on my side, squeezing the long bone, waiting for the great steel-grey vane of agony to soften, warm, and melt away. In summer my brown legs were interrupted by transverse streaks of white at bed-level.</analepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/feet.html">
       <level degree="2">I believed in practise, which was why one summer I walked barefoot every day on the neighbor's gravel driveway, mincing and wincing in the hope of one day being tough enough to walk barefoot over the toughest ground without flinching, like someone in a book, an Indian tracker or a beggar girl in Calcutta, bare brown feet spreading comfortably on the earth, toes f l e x i n g and gripping. But the hard corners toothing my soles never ceased to be painful. The blinding stretch of white gravel was so wide I seemed to see the curve of the earth in its swell. The gravel squeaked underfoot. I lowered my weight slowly and the rocks shifted under me, dealing me new, unanticipated shocks. An stretch unproblematic to the shod became an epic to the barefoot, fraught with doubt. I rewarded myself with a stem of the bleached sourgrass that grew in the shade under the trees on the other side of the driveway, and stood there cooling my sore feet on the grass, dourly chewing the tangy cud while I plotted my way back.</level>

        <level degree="1"><prolepsis>My feet rub each other under the covers at night or while I'm reading, sliding sensuously on each other. The ball of the big toe screws into the arch of the other foot, the toes fraternize, side slides by side. The pace steps up when I'm excited, the foot cranking around the ankle joint in slow circles, toes spreading and then squeezing together: a whole waltz under the covers, very comforting and secret and like company, like two small dachshunds rolling on each other.</prolepsis></level>

        <level degree="2"><analepsis>One summer I got swim goggles for the first time and became a lurker under surfaces, a spy in the underwaterworld. My eyes never tired of looking into that luminous space into which objects were abruptly born from above, sometimes only piecemeal: a leg punched in up to the knee seemed amputated, sutured to the elastic blanket of the undersurface, which was an oily, undulating sheet, a pewter-greasy blue. Bodies were restfully relieved of the burden of heads. They were cleansed of shadows and the hang of flesh. I hunkered at the bottom of the pool, bobbing a little on my bottom, where my swimsuit snagged slightly on the rough spots, bubbling in a controlled flow through my nose (a pleasant feeling like letting a string of pearls run bead by bead through my nose) and settling a little more surely the more I deflated, peering around in the satisfyingly curtailed and secret world. I knew I could be seen from above, a sketchy figure pulled apart by light, but I felt invisible. I waited for the jumpers and divers, hurled into being in a bag (like a kitten) of air and a sudden architectural column of bubbles. But what I liked most was the feet: all those problematic people, so firmly planted on slavish, characterless feet - like slabs of clay - were suddenly afloat like angels. Their feet swelled and softened. Their feet looked like fruit, like fleshy tropical flowers. They became expressive and gentle, even beatific - they kicked softly at nothing, sought the bottom, and no sooner found it than dabbed at it coquettishly and rebounded away: relieved feet, lucky, suspended as in amber, beautiful and whole and to be considered for their own merits as forms.</analepsis></level>

        <level degree="1"><prolepsis>I am reconciled only to my own feet; everyone else's are ugly and strange. I understand that they feel the same way about mine. Feet are alien, like a hoof or a wing. They are more like tools or furniture than like flesh, they are so sturdy and well-crafted and so serviceable. Maybe they are a little too far away from the heart to befriend, though at one time I could put my big toe in my mouth, and I aspire to do it again, though without much hope.</prolepsis></level> <analepsis><level degree="2">Besides my own, likeable feet I got to know my mother's from sitting beside her chair and I was quite censorious of the shiny pink callouses, the contorted baby toes. Allowing ugliness was, I thought, a practically moral failure.</level>

        <level degree="2">I should mention that the glimpse of toe cleavage in women's pumps aroused a passionate aversion in me when I was little, as did the crookedly bunched together two or three toes sticking out the little hole women's shoes sometimes have at the tip. I disapproved of stockings when the tip of them was visible, binding the toes. I felt nervous about socks that had worked their way down so the empty toe flapped loose, and socks that were too big, so the heel stuck out in a bunch above the tops of the shoes. I pulled my own knee socks tight up over my calves, and took great satisfaction in their tight grip on the backs of my knees.</level></analepsis> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>My strong feelings about feet have lessened in intensity as I have put distance between myself and them.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/toes.html">
        <level degree="1">I have a few glinting hairs on the tops of my feet and a little tuft on each toe.</level> <level degree="2"><analepsis>When I was nine I read that hobbits had hairy feet and went around barefoot, and that was enough to persuade me that hairy feet were good.</analepsis> <prolepsis>Much later a girlfriend firmly opposed to almost all kinds of body hair persuaded me to try shaving my feet, but stubble on my toes seemed so ludicrous that I gave it up forthwith. Besides, I still felt that my hairy toes were cute.</prolepsis></level>

        <analepsis><level degree="2">At five I wanted to learn to dance on my toes. I supposed that ballerinas had incredibly strong toes, because no matter how I strained my toes couldn't hold my weight without buckling. What I could do, balancing myself against a chair while I arranged myself en pointes, was fold my toes under and hobble along on the knuckles.

        There's a snapshot of me doing it. I was prepared to practice until I mastered it. But was this really what dancers did? I could scarcely imagine spinning or leaping on my turned-over toes. How was it possible? If other bodies could do things, magical things, that I couldn't even approximate, then a body was like a cabinet of wonders inherited from a great-aunt: you didn't know what was in it, but one day you opened a drawer and pulled out something wonderful. I might be able to do things nobody else had even imagined. All I had to do was try everything. Sooner or later I would find out what my own big trick might be.</level>

        <level degree="2">My kid brother owned a miniature grand piano with color-coded keys. I thought I might be able to play it with my toes, as it was the right height off the ground. At first my baby toe seemed welded to its neighbor and I could only sound a note with it by rolling my whole foot to one side. But with assiduous practise I learned to move it on its own, and in a matter of months I had mastered Frere Jacques. Sadly, my parents were too poor to provide me with a suitably scaled piano of better quality, and my talent stifled in its infancy.</level></analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/cabinet.html">
        In the course of writing these reminiscences, I increasingly began to conceive of my body as a great cabinet of curiosities. Some of those many recondite drawers slide easily out and whack you on the shins, some need a little wax and sandpaper. Inside the drawers are folded sheets of cheap blue-lined paper, pages from journals or school reports, with pictures and diagrams pasted in. There are drawings, biological specimens with neat labels, inscrutable items with no labels, stains from bygone experiments, stoppered bottles and broken vials and their spilled, dried contents, in which a squadron of tiny fruit flies met their sticky deaths. There are slips of paper referring you to other drawers, unlabelled keys (you may despair of finding the locks they fit), and there are drawers within the drawers, behind sliding panels or false bottoms. I have found every drawer to be both bottomless and intricately connected to every other drawer, such that there can be no final unpacking. But you don't approach a cabinet of wonders with an inventory in hand. You open drawers at random. You smudge the glass jar in which the two-headed piglet sleeps. You filch one of Tom Thumb's calling cards. You read page two of a letter; one and three are missing, and you leave off in the middle of a sentence.

        As a matter of fact, I am making a replica of this text: a huge wooden chest in the shape of my body, with innumerable drawers in which I will store my findings. Some of the drawers will be large and c a p a c i o u s, some smaller than matchboxes. Some will be disguised, some will be booby-trapped. I will hide secret buttons, levers and locks in my carved folds and crevices. You will have to feel your way in.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/jackson__my_body_a_wunderkammer/toenails.html">
        <level degree="1">I have a wary, mistrustful relationship to my toenails.</level> <level degree="2"><analepsis>The thought, introduced early on by my father, that the baby toenail was an unnecessary fixture, which might as well drop out of the human equation forever, if evolution worked that way, made me resent my littlest toenail slightly. At the same time the thought of a bare all-flesh nubbin was not a pleasant one.</analepsis></level>

        <level degree="2"><analepsis>At sixteen, jumping up from the table in frustration at a sewing project gone awry, I knocked over my chair, which fell squarely onto my big toe. The nail turned a deep plum and began to loosen itself at the sides, unsticking itself completely over the course of a few weeks until it was only held on by a sort of hinge at the base, and flapped unnervingly when the bandage that bound it flat came off in the swimming pool. When the whole thing did finally detach, the beginnings of a new nail were revealed, so I never did get to see my toe as bare and soft as a nose. The new nail, bizarrely thick and rounded, moved slowly across my toe, and it was more than a year before it looked normal again.</analepsis></level> <level degree="1"><prolepsis>Its faint ripples are still more pronounced than those of its twin.</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

</text>
