<text>
    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/Twelve_Blue.html">
        "So a random set of meanings has softly gathered around the word the way lint collects. The mind does that." from On Being Blue by William Gass
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl1.html">
        Follow me doesn't have much of a ring to it, though god knows there's music for a fifteen year old girl holding tasteless blueberry cotton candy on an August afternoon and flirting with a gap-toothed carny, arms brown as twisted rattan, hard thighs in jeans black as grease, jack o'lantern smile below a thief's indigo eyes. Music likewise for <prolepsis>a woman, shivering in the air conditioning and half having to piss, seated years afterward bare-legged and squirming upon a gray leather banquette lit by dim cobalt sconce lights, her reflection and the candle's weaving together in the Art Deco mirror, its woodwork burnished like the luscious brown arm of one of Gauguin's sleepy girls, yellow arabesques across her full breasts.</prolepsis>

        "Follow me."

        A girl will leave stale candy for a hard man running a whirly ride or slip out of her arabesques for a priestly man with grey flecked temples. See him swirl Petit Syrah in a crystal globe before a candle, the wine's leggy shadows dancing garnet on the dark blue veins of his manicured fingers, each nail square and white as the sail of a Dutch schooner. <prolepsis>Even here and after so long she can still smell</prolepsis> oil and the burnt sugar of the midway, the sweet dazzle of aftershave.

        Follow me before the choices disappear.

        It is not the season for love, however, thin blue snow in the air, distant carols. There's a rumor someone drowned in the river. The evening star is icy phosphor. You'll be doing alright with your Christmas of white but I'll have a blue, blue, blue

        Follow me? What choice do we have but love, what season after?
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl2.html">
        Each river flows two ways for at least an instant, whether a gasp at the source, the spring half lapsing before going on, or a watery wavering at the uncertain edge which joins her to sister or the sea. Nonetheless the long sigh of the estuary is something different, the Hudson easing swollen and recumbent upward halfway to Albany, plumping in her banks like the bluish flesh of an oyster, pregnant with pearl sheen even when no stone forms.

        When you make a slide, for an instant as you capture the smear before staining it you can see life itself in microcosm in the mucousy swirl. A diviner wouldn't need science. She could look along this shore of the body's river and see lifeforms: virus, pearl, cancer, fetus, yeast spore.

        The violet stain is like no color in nature. Alkali. Kali. Queen.

        Instead she gazes on the samples with a neutral eye, labwise and detached as a river in December. In the microscope there is no difference between the birth of an infant savior or the death of a crone at year's end. Life is a river that flows both ways, it doesn't do to get caught up in the threads the water weaves. <analepsis>So the men taught who tutored her in these alchemies.</analepsis> Even so she sees dreams in algae, lotus blossoms in saline solution, a sister in the oyster.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl3.html">
        Coolly competent and in synch, that's how they thought her (like mother like daughter).

        There was some truth to it. Ontario left you cool if you survived its impoverished spirit. (God to be French! she thought, the men gaily pissing along the shoulders of the QEW; Quebecoise women always half bare somewhere, in short sleeves or stockingless, snorting like thoroughbred horses through ripe, noble noses. It was an Anglo stereotype, she knew, but she believed their lives more carefree, more sexual.)

        Retroviruses also kept one cool. There was an art in restraint, in patience. She looked at life through a blue glass, looking down into its watery, wonderful depths, holding her breath.

        Abandon wasn't in her heritage, she had had to grow into it.

        She couldn't stand the feeling of anything covering her legs, it was like she couldn't breath. Sometimes in winter, however, she wore knit wool socks thick as pillows. Everyone has her own peculiarity.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl4.html">
        She looked out on the creek and measured out the threads like the fates, silk thread in twelve shades of blue. (Is pink blue? Is yellow or purple? She supposed so, she believed in her stories.) The trimmings she saved and cast out on the water like pollen, all the pretty colors. They would sink like barren nymphs for the fish to bump with fleshy lips, float for birds to pluck away and decorate the muddy basket of a nest. <analepsis>She had taught herself abandon, taught herself to understand that they were not minor characters, she and her daughter, but at the center of something flowing through them.</analepsis> This is why they lived by the water (this was why she was so taken by the awkward, foolish doctor, Javier).

        It was sad to think of death there. A drowned boy. <analepsis>(Once a dead swan had floated in against her short dock among the lillies. It was not as frightening as it was fantastic, the long white neck trailing through the black water, one mangled wing showing threads of crimson. Bluegills pecked at the ragged wing from below.)</analepsis>

        She measured out the threads and onto the short quilting needles, thirty needles at a time. Samantha played music in her room, so loud it floated down upon the water like settling fog. The marsh shone with rainbow feathers of oil. Already the water chestnuts were choking the channel.

        Her music so loud it could wake the dead.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl5.html">
        <prolepsis>She was was making a quilt of the river, it was the antithesis of science. Twelve feet long and eight feet wide, the covering for a giantess.

        "But who would ever use it?" Samantha asked.

        "Basketball players?" her mother offered. They laughed together.

        "I need it long so I can get the flow I wish."

        "So it's not for using, it's for flowing," Samantha said.

        "Exactly," Lisle said, clapping with delight. She was a good daughter, the best.

        They believed each other's stories and knew they were not minor characters.

        "It's a quilt for swimmers then."

        "Night swimmers," Lisle said, "We are all night swimmers."

        Even the retrovirus, she thought.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl6.html">
        <prolepsis>Sometime she missed <analepsis>being on call</analepsis> (there were few emergencies that dragged a virologist away from her quilting), not <analepsis>the disruption of it but the constant sense of expectation. It was like being aroused, not all lathered and horny but the buzz along your limbs, the slight sensation of sinking like drinking wine.</analepsis>

        Now that everyone on earth wore beepers (or so it seemed in a walk through the Galleria), she wondered had it lost its sense of expectation or rather was the phenomenon now simply more widely shared. It seemed as if the whole pedestrian world strolled with small plastic packets of electronics at their hips-- in shades of pastel now as well as basic black-- all of them pleasantly abuzz and mildly aroused, awaiting word of what would be, word of what had been.

        The creek here likewise shimmered with expectation, more lake than creek, where swollen with tide, it met the river. The surface called to her in times like this, blue-white moonlight filling the slight chop with hundreds of pale mouths.

        A lone heron cried, jarred from sleep, then flapped slowly to another bank.

        Perhaps it was a little lust as well. She longed for Javier, longed to hold him down, pinning his wrists with her hands like ivory manacles against the river of the quilt, feeling it flow up and around her bucking buttocks like a wave. Instead she took the needles up, thirty silver spines in twelve colors, and looked for where she would enter the quilt again, thinking we are all night swimmers.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl7.html">
        <prolepsis>She had willed him in, she knew, from where he snagged and lingered, brought him shoreward just as surely as <analepsis>once she had birthed a daughter</analepsis> from the smooth space within the roil of other banks and water. She was sorry if it gave Samantha a fright and in fact had every hope that it would be she who found him and not her daughter.

        He was falling inside-out and inverse, from dark to light, from bottom to top, from death to life, from silence to the sound of stars and the sirens of the police cruisers.

        Samantha had taken it well, a little frightened of course, a lot really. Deep sobs racked the drum hollow beneath her budding chest, Niobe's tears in her eyes. The world was a drum of dark water where we sometimes caught our wings like moths and fluttered until we freed ourselves and dried our wings and set off for other lights more real than this reflection. Other times, of course, we stuck there, adhered to mystery and illusion, unable to move. Sometimes we died there, wings crucified by reflected light.

        In the water the reflected constellations were blue rhinestones.

        Floating, her daughter would grow strong, as <analepsis>she had long ago before her birth.</analepsis></prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl8.html">
        There were so many ways from her house out to Route 9 that it sometimes seemed a labyrinth. In mid-summer each road tunneled through a canyon of impenetrable green, a jungle of wild grape and loose strife. By November the hardwood was no longer festive and the woods showed their bones like the skeletons of dia de los muertes. In another month you would be able to see the forest floor.

        Wappingers Creek Road took you back along the creek bank first past the boat launch and finally past sad river town working class flats to the center of the village. Or you could make the hairpin loop and rise along 28 through Hughsonville past 9D to 9, emerging at La Fonda del Sol and Seven Eleven. You could take the left at 9D and come into the village that way, then follow the road right where the Delano family shared a lot for their two businesses, Delano Brothers Paving and Delano's the Italian restaurant with home-made cavatelli and old-fashioned red sauce specked with oregano. Past the park and the ugly new suburban Post Office you dead-ended in a T at 9, Home Depot and Ben&amp;Jerry's to the right on opposite sides of the highway, Wendy's and eventually Poughkeepsie to the left. Going left at Delano's instead of right also brought you to 9 eventually after you circled through the old part of the river town, past Mill Street, where the other route, via Wappingers Creek Road, emerged and around the bend where the falls were hidden and through the northside where yet another possible route also emerged.

        You reached that one if you looped back through New Hamburg from the house making a right where 28 ended at Main Street and where a left would take you to the railway station. Turning right you rose instead to a fork, a dogleg really, where Channingville Road went straight ahead on over a ridge and past the Catholic church cemetery where the boy was buried down to the north side of the village <analepsis>once known by the name of the road.</analepsis> You could pick up 9D here again on the other side of the village and follow it to 9 near North Hills Mall which had become the ugly discount step-sister in the years since <analepsis>the Galleria,</analepsis> itself now fading, <analepsis>had been built</analepsis>. The dogleg outside New Hamburg took you there by another route, along Sheafe Road past Bowdoin Park and to another T, where the right brought you to the Galleria side of the mile-long complex of old and newer malls. <analepsis>In Bowdoin Park some fifteen thousand years ago indians camped in the caves above the river and left petroglyphs of impossible beauty beyond the blue page of the water,</analepsis> though you had to know your way through the park trails and crawl in tunnel-like caves to find them.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl2_2.html">
        He tried to look at things from her viewpoint. (Through the eyepiece of a microscope? she wondered.) He watched the ruby rivulets lapse down along the inside curve of the wine glass and he could see how she might have thought that he worked at seducing her.

        "The doctor gazes between her liquid thighs," she had said impishly.

        "I'm sorry," he said in a pardon-me tone as though he had not heard her, although (like god) <analepsis>he had</analepsis> but had no idea how to answer her simplest prayer. I am more a boy than you can think, he thought, grey hair can't hide giddiness. He was giddy for her (could someone say that these days? He would ask Beth, ask his daughter. He needed to tell her, tell this woman, about his daughter; they each had daughters. He needed to ask her.) and it was nearing Christmas. He longed for a family and red wine. He nodded and the waiter poured the wine, hers and then his.

        "Why else would they call them legs?" she asked. She said this in response to his pretended claim that he hadn't heard her, he knew. She knew <analepsis>he had heard</analepsis> and went on.

        "I'm afraid I won't sleep with you, tonight at least; however charming you are, doctor."

        "My god!" he said, almost fumbling the wine glass, "I haven't asked you to, doctor."

        "Ah doctor doctor," she said and smiled. "It used to be my favorite game."

        She was somewhere between smart and smartass. Smart in the British sense: stylish. Cerulean pearl eye shadow above sparkling eyes. Though curiously she wore no hose, not even in winter. Smart also in the usual sense: sharp as one of the opal headed tacks on the grey banquette.

        Smart like a hurt, a slap, as well.

        We learn from our teenagers, he thought, her daughter and mine each teaching us to date again. "Pretend you are a widower, dad, it's more romantic," his daughter had said.

        <analepsis>It was a month ago. They began to date a week before Christmas. She wore no hose. They didn't sleep together.</analepsis> "My god," he said, "She knows very well that I'm divorced. She probably knows your mother. It's a small world in a hospital, everyone knows everything."

        "Whatever," she said. "A woman likes a man with a story behind him." She was nineteen years old with a ring through her nostril. "You need to get a story, dad. You need romance. Shipwreck and drowning men. Blues songs and lost love." (He thought of <analepsis>a mad woman he had slept with once, Devi, someone else's daughter, a blue mountain and serene thighs.</analepsis>)

        <analepsis>At age fifteen she ran away with the carnival, in love she said with a fool.</analepsis> Not Beth, not his daughter, not the mad parenthetical goddess (her name Elli not Devi, a different queen). It was Lee, Lisle, his colleague, a virologist, the woman he had begun dating, his friend. Even so from time to time she mourned for lost love, she said.

        "Javier is such a romantic name," she (Lee) had said. "Does it mean January?"

        It was a new year. He tried to look at things from her viewpoint. He was a drowning man, speechless and in love too late in life.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl2_3.html">
        Studied history carefully and loved lost love. Eleanore of Castile, for instance, (the name also of a fine soap) who <analepsis>died at Harby in 1290, was so mourned by her husband, Edward I, that he erected crosses at each place where her cortege stopped between Lincoln and Westminster where she was buried. (How he must have loved her.)</analepsis> Three crosses remain, at Hardingstone, Geddington and Waltham Cross. Others were in Lincoln of course, and Woburn, Stony Stratford, Dunstable (a name Eleanore, this one, loved for its sound), as well as at St. Albans, Cheapside and Charing Cross. Legend has it that there may have been two more. One day Eleanore hopes to visit England and to see. For now she has retreated to the mountains (although she is college educated, at Brown University in Providence, Rhode Island). <analepsis>"Providence looks over her," her mother often said before she died. It was a joke between them. (Don't you mean "looks after?" she would ask, but her mother said she meant what she said.)</analepsis> Eleanore weaves wreaths and crosses from wild grape vines which she pulls down from trees in winter (this is February, mild this year, in the mountains at least) and sells at craft fairs in the spring. Otherwise she lives on her wits and a small pension from the King. She's vowed to murder Ed Stanko before summer.

        Her heart is broken.

        <analepsis>Once she lost a baby, its father Javier, a Portuguese sailor.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl2_4.html">
        Ed Stanko was gnarled as a crabapple, knobbed and hard. He hated too many people to remember them all. From that fatass Flossie Reilly onward, a hundred or more (a thousand if you counted the service, millions if you counted all the goddamn Koreans). His wife and kids as well, goddamn them. Let them weep at his casket; he swore if there was an afterlife he'd curse them from the very brink of hell.

        God damn them all.

        He was a hard man, hard as a crabapple, and only worms could soften him. (He laughed at the thought.) It wouldn't last, the fires of hell would turn him hard again, hard as a cinder. <analepsis>He had been a coward all his life and so for a long time couldn't turn his hate to anything of value. Then Flossie died and the hotel was his, thanks to the GI Bill and a tax auction,</analepsis> and he sat there all day now, in the piece of shit lobby, a room no bigger than a Holiday Inn room, drinking beer and hating and looking out at the road. It was something to do in this piece of shit life (twice a week he shaved with a straight razor, Thursdays he drank a shot of cognac neat; every night he watched TV with the wife until he slept, in good weather his kids would come over and cut the lawn or fix a broken window, but this was March, half mud and slush and grey as his wife's ass, and no one came near).

        There was no more hotel. <analepsis>He'd turned the place to four cramped apartments as soon as he got it, turned the lobby into a tavern. It was too much goddamn trouble. He'd closed it up years ago, sold all the inventory but the shelf of cognac and a huge blue jar of pickled eggs</analepsis> which still sat there like dead babies in an abortion ad. Sundays he opened the door and sold the Roanoke paper. It was something to do, pocket change. He had an eleven percent disability from the army for a gimp leg and, thanks to Flossie and Uncle Sam, made the rest of his money screwing social services out of rent for these sad-ass tenants who in Korea or somewhere else would (and probably should) have been put to death. There was a mongrel half-wit in his fifties who couldn't remember his full name, a fat slut with four kids covered with scabs, an old fart all dressed up in a gaberdine suit that smelled of piss and mothballs, and a hard-looking but uppity woman named Eleanore with black hair and murderous eyes who could have been a whore once. Sometimes they would try to complain about something, a sink without a washer, a slow radiator, rats. He put an end to that soon enough, threatened to tell social services that they took drugs or broke things, threw them out on their sorry asses.

        Otherwise sometimes a car would stop and some asshole show up at the door, expecting quaintness or country wisdom. Their wives and kids would peer around the beaming assholes at the door. What the fuck do you want? Ed would say then laugh as they drove away.

        <analepsis>He had been a coward.</analepsis> No one liked him. It was a life. Each morning he woke up surprised and a little disappointed that he'd made it to another goddamn day in this empty stinking valley.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl2_5.html">
        <analepsis>Her father and her mother unmarried. It happened.</analepsis> Now he wanted "quality time," it was so ironic. <analepsis>All through her growing up-- dance recitals and class plays, paper dolls and Star Wars movies, a sleazeball first boyfriend always wanting his hand in her pants or, really, hers in his-- her father was nowhere to be seen. Always at the office or the hospital, popping a heart into someone like the Wizard of Oz the same way other fathers changed a carburetor, stitching a sleeve around an artery like a lacemaker (she had seen him on videotape, his peasant fingers holding the instrument and making pristine, small stitches to patch a blown-out heart). And when he wasn't at the hospital he was away for conventions, conferences, and vacations the latter both with and without her and her mother and where in any case when they were with him he was always really somewhere else: leading them through guidebook streets, behind the wheel of a rented Lincoln, a triptik in hand, on the tennis courts, submerged in a pool. Each evening ending up with him screened by an elaborate menu choosing wine for the dinner, each night ending behind the connecting door in a hotel room clinging to her mother then snoring above the noise of the air conditioning.</analepsis>

        He wanted quality time and she longed for it. Her mother welcomed it as well. She still loved him really, though it was clearly over for them. She was happy with who she she found she was. "Maybe he can become somebody," her mom said. "With you, I mean. The poor man never had a chance to become anything but what they said he was."

        He wanted her (not his wife, his daughter, though probably the former as well) to be what they had said she was, Tevet, her given name as strange as every name in their minimal family: doctor, doctor's wife, daughter. They were a three legged stool, their whole family: Javier, Aurelie, Tevet, not a real name in the bunch. <analepsis>And then they unmarried, her mother became Ms Undoctor and she became Beth.</analepsis> Her name was her birthday, this month, April, the fourth month in the Jewish calendar. And since it was sometimes also Tebet or Tebeth, she called herself Beth. April was a fat girl with a scrapbook (<analepsis>she had been that once</analepsis>).

        The woman her father was seeing was a doctor named Lisle, a lacemaker's name, though she called herself Lee. It was, awkwardly, her mother's nickname though few people used it. Lisle's daughter was Samantha, apparently called Sam, generation upon generation without a real name. The woman her mother was seeing was named Lisa, just as awkward, one supposed.

        "Maybe when you grow," he said. It was awkward, not <analepsis>what he had meant.</analepsis> He wasn't good with words, though he loved them. They were in the Blue Ridge Mountains, this trip was her birthday gift, a pilgrimage to see the picture of her great grandmother, it was the only photo of her on earth, a woman with a normal name (Mary Reilly) whom someone else, though unrelated to any of them, claimed absurdly as his heritage because <analepsis>he had bought the small house where she once lived.</analepsis> (Ed Stanko was the man's name, her father said. He was "hard as a crabapple." He loved words, her father did, she didn't know about Ed Stanko.)

        It is hard to keep the names straight, like a Dickens novel.

        She knew he meant (her father that is) that she would grow when she became a woman. It was just as awkward, of course, though sweet. He had some idea that she would grow into her name, like the last reel of a film, a training bra, the sad-ass graphic on the final screen of an adventure game: Princess Leah, Princess Tevet. She noticed that every second thing she thought of had the word awkward stuck to it, she hated how that happened, how a word stuck to you like velcro or thistles.

        Happily. Awkward. After.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl2_6.html">
        Think of lilacs when they're gone. She looked out the window to the water and tried to think what they were doing upstream. Divers in black wetsuits shiny as seals. The grapple hooks into doughy white flesh like what forms under a band-aid left on too long. Dandelions forming under a tipped over washtub white as bones, the leaves soft and damp as the feathery transparent skin which peels off after a sunburn.

        The tide was up and where the creek met the river the whole thing swelled. Estuarial. <analepsis>The boy who had drowned was deaf they said.</analepsis> She wondered had he screamed, voiceless and white as hidden dandelions. Behind her, mindless morning radio voices on the old Philco. Outside the window the banks of lilacs gone like fragrant dreams.

        There would be the Sheriff's boat. What did he call it again? The Terminator or something as adolescent. <analepsis>She had seen it at White's Marina on the trailer, the name painted on the hull, and it had made her smile. Boys and their toys, she thought. A deaf boy and his girlfriend stole away from school to swim in the still icy waters of the creek.</analepsis> The Sheriff's boat circling now like a fiberglass shark. Divers' buoys floating like cartoon waterlilies. He could float down to you, she knew, like Moses, his back a loaf of bread dough cresting the black water, deceptively moist, a viscous sheen.

        Not grapple but grappling hooks. Samantha wanted to pierce her nostril. Everyone was she said.

        Safe at school.


        If I pierced myself it wouldn't be a nostril or a nipple. The smallest ring of thin, thin gold wire through a hidden fold of the labia, like an iris in back water hidden in reeds, lapis lazuli, clitoral and estuarine. She said a prayer for the drowned deaf boy though she no longer believed god heard us.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl2_7.html">
        Some choose to be minor characters. There is nothing wrong in this despite your suspicion, itself most likely colored by your own understandable and ordinary desire to take a central place in someone's story. Few of us think ourselves wild iris in backwater (what was the line from the poem? something blue..., then she recalls: a violet half-hidden by a stone. There was beauty in poetry, she couldn't put it differently, she was an ordinary person, a minor character, though it made what she felt no less real).

        The girl on the Pacific shore stares out looking for her mother.

        <analepsis>Or the girl sitting on a log by the water at the deserted public boat launch waiting for him to surface. Ever there, a minor character</analepsis> (it had been a whole month now, the boat launch now in June alive with fishermen heading out in the Hudson after spawning stripers), <analepsis>waiting and watching carefully, scanning the whole surface of the broad creek, ready to help him were he in trouble, watching every second because he could not cry out.

        Though that was wrong. He could cry, it was halfway between grunt and yelp really, he just couldn't hear, though she made that mistake often, before that morning, ever after: he couldn't shout. They had slipped out during third period and went to Wappingers Creek. He wanted her to swim too. He had stripped down to white undershorts, his penis and whathaveyou a little white sack in the middle. He signed the sign for swim and grunt-yelped, "Du twim doo! Du twim doo!" Though the way he talked often made it seem like he was scolding, it was so sweet too she had to smile. No, she signed, I watch. It was her period, she didn't sign that, and she wore ugly cotton panties her mother had bought "for day-to-day wear," and a bra that looked like it was designed for the Russian army. She wouldn't want to be seen so, so she sat and watched for her, saw him grin as he dove down, his back arching, white white against the dark water.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl2_8.html">
        Aurelie and Lisa ran in parallel like the blue lines of a notebook. They had between them a notebook's sense of margin and blank edge, a place, a vertical red double half-rule, where they began and, while she had no sense that they would end, ever or soon, there wasn't a vanishing point where their lines merged, rather the regular march of page upon page of parallel lines gutter to edge.

        Still we fill them well enough, she thought, watching as Lisa hauled another wheelbarrow of compost down the woodchip path into the lower garden near the river. My warrior girl, she thought, seeing the samurai sweatband and the muscled flanks. Butterfly was a curious name for a torturous event, arms swinging in full arcs around the rotator cuff, the muscled flanks and hydraulic calves hammering in the dolphin kick.

        She redeemed dolphin, Aurelie thought. A creature too often seen as fey, smooth, merely ballistic. The dolphin like Lisa was all (not not all, there were moist spaces, the faintly violet labial serrations like the pinked violet edge of the membrane of a clam) muscle.

        We are paired but not mated.

        <analepsis>Lisa had been an All-American swimmer, her picture once in the section at the front of Sports Illustrated where they heralded the melting pot of amateurism, the coming generation of simple citizen athletes. It was a page of lies. Or rather mug shots of the innocently duped, believers in the lies of the body, believers in the democracy of federations, councils, associations. So and so of Zeppelin, Illinois set an amateur record in the sixteen thousand something. See him smile. Lisa in her own mugshot looked a little grim, though duly Californian, like the sun-bleached daughter of some celebrity scientist who had cooked her dolphin's genes into a salty broth before injecting them into his perfectly fit wife, finishing it all off with a nubby little ride on the vibrator and a glass of chardonnay to calm her after.</analepsis>

        I am bitter for her, she thought. Or perhaps bitter from her.

        Perhaps it was only the heat, the thick of July, Lisa's white leotard top stained with perspiration and the potting soil bran of the compost, damp at her belly, the small of her back, the sweet long scapula, the shoehorn curve between her tight breasts. Satin Umbro soccer pants, still the All-American. It is the heat, she thought. A butterfly borne by a burnished silver cocoon.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl2_9.html">
        She says August is a month of Sunday nights. She thinks of an electric fog of blue light in steamy living rooms all along the street. She says she hates the book that begins with the light like television. "Boy talk," she says, "typical Canadian sensibility. 'Gonna go down to the gay-raj, eh? Fix me up a spaceship...'" She is from Fort Erie, Ontario, at the mouth of the Niagara River across from Buffalo. She has the right, he supposes. She says 'cyberspace' as if it were the word 'clubhouse,' laughing at him. She thinks of searching for breezes in the dog days along a dimly lit street where there is blue light in steamy living rooms and outside the moon flowers spread so coolly they seem to be sighs.

        Sometimes you see a sweaty man in a strap teeshirt fiddle with the dial, a can of Molson's blue in his hand, looking like a wrestler gone to seed.

        You could never imagine a woman sleeping next to him. Moon flowers.

        "Cyberspace," she laughs. It makes him feel panicky and foolish, though he knows she means to soothe him. "Cyberspace is a sweaty man in a teeshirt wrestling with a teevee dial with a beer in his hand like a remote control for dreams."

        She has a book by a Canadian woman poet which is called Furious. He knows she loves him.

        "I've been to cyberspace. No one sleeps there. It's all August and autumn rushing in and back to school."
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl2_10.html">
        <prolepsis>September's embers. A nonsense rhyme running over and over in a girl's head as she watches her feet in new blue leather Mary Janes taking step after step after step along a hot walk toward school in what has suddenly been declared the end of summer though the red wing blackbirds do not know this and only a vague lapsing in the draped sunshine along her shoulders hints that heat could end or blood begin.

        September's embers never ending.

        She supposed there could be a prairie where peat fires burned or scrub pine smolders in the chill days at the mouth of this month. Frost warnings in the mountains and high valleys. <analepsis>August was a month of Sunday nights.</analepsis> September's embers remember. By month's end Fall was distinctly possible and blood bloomed like cramped apples. In first hour the melancholy ghost of chalk skim where the board was wiped the previous night. The ceremony of a lavatory pass and whispers: I have my period, Mother Superior. The shoes came with their own bottle of blue polish smelling like winesap.

        "So young..." she sighs. As if the seasons were whose fault?

        Remember the embers. Straw snuffed, curl of silken smoke in the river of the air.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl2_11.html">
        Consider the mind of god a drowning boy, all-seeing but deaf, his white limbs caught in the black swirl of time itself, a creation of serpents, his sacred body borne down to the muck depths and swampy tangle, splayed there, serene, cruciform, ivory.

        <analepsis>Once, swimming off of Malibu, a man told me the story of their neighbor, the first wife of a famous scientist, a television icon, tanned, handsome, able to explain mysteries of the universe to a mass audience. (One imagines his wife as someone suitable for such a celebrity: red-gold sun-bleached hair, tan flanks flecked with dried salt, ample though not unbecoming breasts in a modest electric blue tanksuit.)

        We were swimming in the Pacific, the scientist's house and the man's house each up on stilts, surprisingly modest knowing their exclusivity and cost. We stood wiping the gleaming salt from our brows and faces, tentacles of seaweed wrapped about our ankles. Out farther, he said, the weeds became a tangle. She was diving there for langoustines.

        They would often dive for supper, it was paradise.

        Somehow her scuba gear tangled and she wasn't able to free herself. The scientist himself joined the police divers. They found her rather easily, she shone like a goddess. He said she was perfectly framed by the ropes of seaweed, herself cruciform, calm at the last, caught like a bright moth in the drab web and the blue sea, the spiny creatures still alive in the mesh bag at her waist.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl2_12.html">
        We wish we knew more about Samantha. <analepsis>When her father and mother split she went into a shell of jaunty but ultimately false happiness, doing it so successfully that she fooled everyone, herself included. The truth is she had a knack for feigning happiness and did it so well that she was mostly happy. For three years she was too silent even for her own tastes, but then she began to smile. After awhile she was able to talk so easily that her classmates treated her as if she were someone who had come back from a long journey with stories to tell, which was of course the truth. She resolved to fall in love as often as possible so as to avoid the inevitable distrust which afflicts an orphan or the child of divorced parents.</analepsis>

        She had a literary sensibility as you can see.

        She liked this month and thought the year was wrong to end in December rather than in the great harvest feast of Thanksgiving. This she had learned from Shakespeare where, a favorite teacher told her, a banquet of some sort closes every successful comedy. Years did make her laugh, though she didn't like to see her mother grow old unloved.

        This month was her month, her birthstone Topaz, her sign Scorpio. She liked that it began with what in Mexico was known as Dia de los Mortos, the Day of the Dead. In her room she had a pair of waltzing skeletons from the Day of the Dead, the skull faced man in a top hat and the woman in an sapphire gown with blue sequins, a gift of her father.

        The man kicks back one jaunty leg and dips the woman as if she swoons.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl3_2.html">
        <!-- level change in this lexia? -->
        He loved words though they worried him. It was a result of being named Javier, a name no one ever know how to say (<analepsis>have a beer, boys turned it to; and she wanted to know about the month, this month, whether he was named January</analepsis>). Janus, the month of two faces, forward and back, death and life, dolphin zeppelin.

        He remembered <analepsis>the first time he saw a dead man, really saw death.</analepsis> It was a story he often told. <analepsis>This morning he had told it to the new resident (they had lost a woman in the OR as she came off pump; sad-eyed and black hair he remembered her from pre-surgical rounds). He watched the resident shut off, as clearly as the heart monitor, as he began to tell the story. The young doctor had already learned to make his face form a mask of interest but his eyes behind it were dull as a drowned man. It was words, he knew, they didn't trust words, words made them shut off, float away into this remove.</analepsis>

        Zeppelin. Dolphin.

        <analepsis><level degree="2">It was in Iowa in August</level> (August and September always seemed to rhyme for him, the same month in inverse, one cold white and one white hot) <level degree="2">and I was in med school, quite used to cadavers and death on the floors and wards, or so I believed. I was walking, it was white hot did I say?, along the river toward Hancher auditorium. Anner Bylsma was playing Bach there that day, the cello sonatas, a matinee.</level></analepsis>

        "Suites," the resident said, "Cello suites."

        So he was listening, behind the mask, and took this risk to correct the senior man. It was brave really. Suites of course.

        <level degree="2">Suites of course. In any case</level> (ah a bit of annoyance here, surprising himself, so he too played his part in a masque: the senior surgeon irritated at the correction), <analepsis><level degree="2">I was young, it was the first time in weeks that I had a day off.

        An afternoon really, stolen from the day.

        The sun was a blanket, woolen, wet. My collar clung to my clammy neck, already burning. There were fishermen at the river and the had two great hemp lines strung to what looked like a zeppelin out in the slow river, a white billowing. Someone watched from the bridge, it was curious, a man in a long green overcoat on such a hot day. It was something alien, this scene, men holding hemp ropes against the stream, as if flying a kite in a muddy swirl. Perhaps they have captured a UFO, I thought, a small craft like a cocoon. fallen in the river. But it couldn't be a zeppelin, not in the water. It was a dolphin</level> (the words forever linked for him that afternoon, zeppelin and dolphin; as a young man he had been a hypnotist's subject, the words television and Massachusetts likewise ever linked in post-hypnotic suggestion: any time he heard the word television, he thought inevitably of the name of the state).</analepsis>

        "Did you wander so much, when you told this story to the poor boy?"

        <analepsis>He looked at her like a creature from a dream. It was a dolphin (he said), he realized they were steadying a dolphin in the river and that it was dead. And then suddenly it was clear. The arched back of a drowned man, the shirt billowing like the shape of a balloon or a manatee, white and puffy but faintly blue in the places where the wet shirt clung to the puffed flesh. He had been in the water a long time. The men with the ropes looked around. They were waiting for something, angels or the morgue wagon. It was death in the water. He began to retch, first along the hot gravel path, then into dry evergreen shrubs, prickly things, holly or some poison berry. He could make out parts of things in the spew in the dust, the contents of a stomach. Inside the auditorium it was cool and dark, air conditioning and velvet and the burnished wood of the proscenium. Bylsma sat up on a small platform with the cello held between his thighs. His hands were peasant hands, lovely, strong and gentle gripping the cello and the bow. Fingers like his father's hands, like sausages. For awhile, he wasn't afraid of death though he didn't want to go out for awhile. He waited through the movements of the Suite No. 6 in D Major.

        Prelude
        Allemande
        Courant
        Sarabande
        Gavottes one and two
        Gigue.

        He waited through the inevitable (though gentle) encore,</analepsis> waited through the rest of his life for death to touch him so again.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl3_3.html">
        She was not crazy, it was a pose, a stance she took as others did happiness. This was the measure of holiness, she supposed, to act according to your nature and hold to that.

        She was very self-aware, a type (she termed herself so, <analepsis>she had studied the subject known as "Victorian types" with Professor George P. Landow, a noted scholar, and had learned from him, via Thomas Hartwell Horne, that "a type may be defined to be a symbol of something future and distant, or an example prepared and evidently designed by God to prefigure that future thing"</analepsis>) and so, when she chewed plug tobacco it was something meaningful, itself and not a symbol (this was what type meant) and in any case not untypical of the peculiarities and idiosyncrasies of students at Brown University, <analepsis>which she had attended not unhappily.</analepsis>

        Likewise her knife prefigured The Triumph of the Innocents.

        Sometimes she spent whole days drinking spring water in order to purify herself for The Triumph of the Innocents, a common Victorian theme which someone as ignorant as Stanko could not be expected to know. <analepsis>Professor Landow was elegant and often wore a British tailored blue blazer, close at the waist with tasteful brass buttons. His shoes were benchmade black pumps of the sort worn through history by English kings.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl3_4.html">
        Once, for instance, this arrogant bastard floats in like he's the King of fucking England, though he's half-spick by name at least, Javier Reilly, Flossie's great nephew or some goddamn thing, all moon-eyed about the old studio photograph of Reilly and his wife and slut hanging on the lobby wall.

        I don't have to smell your shit, he thought looking at the sad bastard. He was all done up in khakis and plaid shirt and campfire moccasins like he's mountain man, just a regular guy even though Ed can see his emerald green BMW in front of the inn. Even so he played it cool. There was always an edge to be had if you play it cool.

        "Would you consider selling that photograph?" says the King of fucking England after he's been standing around for awhile looking at all the shit in the lobby.

        "Not for a million dollars," says Ed, "It's part of my heritage. You can see it clearly here, the Blue Stag Inn is where you're standing. That picture dates to eighteen ninety something... I'm the proprietor now."

        "I know that," says the weenie bastard, already half-crying by now. He's never run into someone he couldn't buy. "My great-grandfather is the man in the photograph. That is the only known photo of my great-grandmother. I can't believe you have this. We know almost nothing about her."

        He's changed his tone now, all forlorn and full of feelings, as if Ed gave a shit.

        His edge was he didn't care about anything.


        "Then you knew that old bitch Flossie," he says, "Sat here all day long on her fat keester, looking down at people. Used to treat me like shit though I did all the work for her, from cutting the grass to cleaning out the fucking privies. I hope she's burning in hell, lard dripping from her blistered ass."

        "She was my father's aunt, I hardly remember her," the bastard says. He'd sell her out for the picture.

        "I have a daughter," the guy says.

        I have a smelly asshole, Ed thinks.

        "Is this one your grandma?" Ed asks. He points at the scullery maid, a wrinkled little toad in a long skirt and apron on the far end of the long porch.

        "Oh no," says King Have-ye-air. "She's got to be this one here. My great-grandmother." He points to the woman with the dark eyes standing off under the tree in front of the house.

        Ed knows her, he's studied her face in the picture for years, her dark eyes like the whore, Eleanore, upstairs. "Cold looking bitch," Ed says. "Back stiff as a ramrod. You'd never think of poking her, would you?"

        Ed cackled. Javier didn't answer.

        They agreed that the doctor could take the photograph into Roanoke and have a copy made at a photo studio Ed knew. Javier stood in the lobby and talked on a cellular phone to arrange with the studio. Ed charged him two hundred dollars for the privilege of taking the photo for the afternoon. "Security deposit," he said.

        "How's it a deposit when you don't give it back?" Eleanore asked. <analepsis>She had come into the lobby when she saw the car outside, talked the doctor into a ride to Roanoke then run upstairs to change. When she came back down she was slutted up, a black satin miniskirt and black stockings with a hole in the back of one thigh, peacock blue eyeshadow.</analepsis>

        "How do you get to open your fucking yap about my business?" Ed snapped.

        She gave him the finger. The doctor looked worried, like the arrangement would all fall apart. He'd sell her out as well, Ed thought. He made him leave the cellular phone to make sure he'd come back with the picture.

        "Three hours," he said. "Any later and I keep this and the money both."

        When the two of them drove off, Ed called the photo studio, using the redial on the doctor's cellular phone.

        "Charge him what you want," he told his sadass so-called friend at the studio. "He's rich as shit and he'll pay anything for this. I'll give you fifty bucks to make sure he never gets his copy of the picture. Tell him you have to mail it or something, then lose the negative or something. He's on his way home tonight and in a rush. By the time you call him it will be too late to do anything."

        You had to have an edge. (Ed's edge over his friend with the photo studio was the kiddie porn which his friend sold and which could get him quality time in a federal penitentiary where guys would fuck him bad from behind.)

        It's a long story. Life's hard in a hollow. Hard and dark.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl3_5.html">
        <analepsis>It would be a fruitless chase, he thought, uncertain what that meant. He thought of <analepsis>arms full of grapes and a woman he once met in these very mountains. She spent her life gathering dried grape vines and desiccated, decorative berries</analepsis> (he liked those words in sequence, like berries themselves), <analepsis>weaving the berries like beads into wreaths.</analepsis> In his office he still had the small woven cross <analepsis>she had given him as a keepsake ("soaked in rue," she said, though he knew--he had studied botany and still thought it a hobby-- rue wasn't native).</analepsis> The cross was a fetish object, holy and frightening both, and the Haitian woman who cleaned the office suite wouldn't touch it. <analepsis>(He asked her would it hurt him, was it voodoo and she laughed. "Oh no sir, such a ting hurt only she who it don't belong. For he whose it is, it watch over with them eye..." She gestured at a distance toward the wrinkled blue beads stitched into the arms of the transept.)</analepsis>

        Beth slept. He would wake her when they entered the spine of the mountains below DC. For now she slept, folded hands under an ear like a dozing angel, her eyes moving dreamwise under her soft lids. He loved his daughter and had unreasonably high hopes she could soften Stanko into releasing the photo of her ancestors. They eased into the blue mountains, and he mouthed the words like a mantra:

        For he whose it is, it watch over with them eye.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl3_6.html">
        Samantha watched her mother watch the dark surface of the water, her gaze sweeping over it like a searchlight, her breathing measured as a clock, the tick-tock swell of her breasts against the starched white blouse each time she inhaled, a sad smile on her lips.

        "Are you looking for the blue heron?" she asked.

        "No. The drowned boy."

        "Yuck," Samantha said. "Sometimes you are so weird."

        "I live in my eyes, love." Her mother turned the searchlight to Samantha's soul. She felt the light scour its lobes like an xray searches for lung cancer. (She was, recall, the daughter of a clinical physician, a virologist. Vir was the word for man in Latin.)

        "And what will you do if you find him?" she asked.

        Hold him. Hold him, her mother thought.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl3_7.html">
        Look out. A lookout. Looking out for you. Her outlook.

        What you did was you kept a picture of the space, whether a pool or the segment of water beyond the beach in front of your station, in your mind. You saw the whole thing but you saw it in motion and changing how it usually changed and you looked for changes that weren't the way it usually was, a still point where there had been movement, movement where there was stillness, something slipping away or flailing, a smooth silent space where moments before the water churned. You refreshed the picture every few seconds or so but without ever really looking. It was like sometimes how you can drive home and get there before you realize you don't remember driving there at all.

        Look out. Her outlook.

        Like <analepsis>the girlfriend who didn't know the sign for drowned.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl3_8.html">
        <analepsis>She had,</analepsis> the story went, <analepsis>run off with her daughter's swim coach, though they went nowhere</analepsis> (save margin to edge like parallel lines). Run off was a curious term, rain spilling from a gutter (O they needed rain, they needed moisture and relief, anything inward and dark, a breeze, movie theatres, malls, the bedroom air conditioner, lavender powder, the honey membrane of plums tinged with crimson at the pit). Run off was the filmstrip memory of girlhood science lessons, farmers fields running off to the sea (she had a faint memory of <analepsis>a lesson regarding the Po Valley in Italy which had to do with heavy metals, recalled sitting at her desk and thinking how a ball of mercury felt in your palm, something they did for fun in the days before they knew the world was poison. It was a pleasant thought, one that took her from school.</analepsis>)

        She wished she had run off from school.

        Run off suggested more mystery, an idiot's sense of romance, the moviegoer myth of Thelma and Louise. It was something ordinary enough, they were an ordinary couple (and this was why their parallel lines would not merge into a vanishing point, nor cross like the wishbone of the loveline on the palm). Still it was, she knew, what people said, Tevet (Beth, she called herself now) reported as much. And though the divorce would have happened had she had "run off" with a woodchuck or buried herself up to her armpits in the garden, she knew they said as much in the staff lounges, scrubrooms, and OR lockers at the hospital. Not Javier, however, <analepsis>he had been, if anything, a little excited, a little too solicitous, a little too happy to be delivering her up to someone whom he imagined soft and sweet</analepsis> (dolphins were hammers, sometimes, pinked elsewhere, and this one sometimes held her down until she wriggled like a moth, its wing caught under a fingertip). Still his macho wasn't affronted (it was supposed to be otherwise, she knew) since there wasn't a man to rival him and this event enabled him to continue to claim (his constant out) that all women were a mystery.

        Lisa saw it more simply: "He imagines himself among dykes, there are men like that." It made Aurelie uncomfortable to hear her say this, it was surely cruel and she disliked the word in any case and, if the truth be told, hated even the suggestion that this man or any could make his way into the dark, quiet space between.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl3_9.html">
        <analepsis>When we were girls,</analepsis> she says, <analepsis>we built a barrel out of burnished aluminum in the shape of a cigar case or a pupa, just small enough to lay in.</analepsis>

        Is it lie or lay?

        <analepsis>It was a casket, a seed, a penis.

        The top fit closely like a spun sugar Easter egg burnished silver. We would caulk it with beeswax and take turns sailing down the river through the rapids and over the Falls. As you floated through the last rush of hesitating water, you could hear a distant collective shriek rise among the horrified tourists along the esplanade above the roar of the Falls, then feel the hurrying water take you over like lovemaking. The crash came like dreams, dark first then settling into the calm of the whirlpool.</analepsis>

        She recites: "There's fennel for you and columbines. There's rue for you and here's some for me. I would give you some violets but they withered all away when my father died."

        He knows she's acting crazy.


        <analepsis>Sometimes there were great moths the color of straw flowers, like tattered blue cotton.</analepsis> "We were never arrested," she said. "Because, unlike daredevils, virgin girls have an ancient right to go over the falls. There is nothing the authorities can do to stop you."

        He asks. "How old were you when your father died."
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl3_10.html">
        <analepsis>Her mother used to walk to school in blue shoes,</analepsis> it was a story she heard often enough though never really tired of it, though she couldn't say why.

        "It is because women haven't given themselves over to the ironic. It is on that account that history will mark this as the age of women. Unlike men, we believe in our stories and in what we do."

        It wasn't a question which she had thought her mother would answer, but once she had she believed in it. It was what they did. <analepsis>They had raised each other,</analepsis> her mother often said. It was an inversion.

        And so I am steady, she thought, while she is silken.

        For as long as she could remember they slept on silk sheets. It was a practical step, her mother said, there was nothing warmer than silk, nothing cooler. It was un-ironic, practical. For Samantha there were silk long johns in winter; Lisle, however, couldn't stand anything on her legs, just nappy woolen socks on the coldest days. When Samantha asked her why her mother told a story about a girl encased in a silk cocoon and floating on a river toward the falls. It made great sense to her and she often asked her mother to repeat it, even after she had grown.

        In the story of the blue shoes the girl got her period. A crimson thread. With silk sheets you had to take care.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl3_11.html">
        Once he got used to it it didn't seem so bad, only lonely, far lonelier than he ever had imagined. At first he felt his heart like a falling anchor until it stuck, caught on a bone or rock deep in the muck and hooked there, steadying him. For awhile he was comforted by the distant light of a woman's eyes scanning over the estuary like the sheriff's searchlight. After a time that too grew familiar and vaguely distant like the ache of the anchor within him. Then he became slowly aware of the damp smells of the shore, lilacs and the metallic smell of blood, musk, clove, a faint odor of fuel oil. Something else, the powdery smell of the girl who haunted it and the sweet, indistinct rot of the log where she waited for him.

        Lonely, far lonelier than he imagined.


        He pulled the water over him like a blanket and slept, anchored in the gaze of an unknown woman and the girl who loved him.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl3_12.html">
        Coolly competent and in synch, that's how they thought her (like mother like daughter).

        There was some truth to it. <analepsis>She had been born to a Canadian woman doctor and an unknown man.</analepsis> (God to be French! she thought, where a bastard heritage added mystery and cachet. Grey eyes and slim hips and mysterious dark lips the color of cranberries, a thin line of blue lip pencil making them fuller. It was a Marie Claire stereotype, she knew, but she longed for romance, a tub full of flowers, a harem knife.)

        Growing up in a house without males also kept one cool. There was an art in restraint, in patience. She looked at life through a glass, looking down into its watery, wonderful depths, holding her breath.

        Abandon wasn't in her heritage, and as yet she felt no longing for it.

        She couldn't stand the feeling of anything touching her neck, it was like she couldn't breathe. Even in winter, however, she wore open collars and kept the covers down around her shoulders.

        Everyone has her own peculiarity.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl4_2.html">
        Like most men he wanted a son and sometimes dreamed that he had had one, one who drowned or slipped away <analepsis>(a deaf boy had drowned, a dolphin, in the creek upstream of Lisle in the Spring; once he saw a drowned man in steaming river, puffed like a manatee).</analepsis>

        Dreamed a son by a dark mother.

        Sometimes in the dreams it was the mad woman who was the mother of his son, the would-be Devi, the strange queen of the blue mountain, the ghost of his great-grandmother. (There was a litany of names for her but only one memory: <analepsis>how she pulled him into her hungrily, gripping his buttocks so frantically there were scratchmarks for a week, like the irregular parallel lines of a falcon's claw. He swabbed them with Betadine in the wardrobe mirror, feeling a fool, rust yellow stains over the lines on his white buttocks. She had bit his shoulder as well, leaving a curved row of blue marks which he likewise swabbed, a doctor. This wasn't what Tevet meant by romance.)

        He tested himself for HIV and STDs as well.</analepsis> You pay for sins in a world of sciences. Pay for witchcraft also. In a careful life it was his only slip from grace and, though he was certain he would eventually suffer its consequences, he nonetheless sometimes stared at the cross she gave him and dreamed of being deep in her thighs. In his dreams her long fingers clawed at his moon white ass until the scratches bled and the sperm pumped from him in a white billow.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl4_3.html">
        She piled the tub with dried wild flowers and fresh lilacs and violets and scented the bath with rosewater and a few drops of oil of clove. <analepsis>She had scrubbed Stanko's stinking tub for days in preparation for the ritual, alternating scrubbings with butter, sea salt, and Comet cleanser, driving away all traces of his blood and shit, his foetid breath.</analepsis>

        She prepared herself as well, scrubbing each inch of her skin and the bodily orifices with sisal cloths that had been barely dampened in a solution of boiled oatmeal water and the skins of blood oranges <analepsis>she had had to go all the way to Roanoke to find.</analepsis> She used a dried loofa to clear away the chaff of dried skin then sponged herself with witch hazel until she shone.

        <analepsis>Once, likewise, she had prepared herself for her Portuguese lover. Once, likewise, she had given birth in fragrant water to the blue infanta that the Satan Stanko killed. At his conception the sperm flowed in a white billow like the lace of bubbles surrounding the dark diver in his cocoon.</analepsis>

        When the water was ready she set sail like Ophelia over the falls.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl4_4.html">
        Ed Stanko saw it coming from a mile away. He had a way that he always knew what was coming, good or bad. Though this time they gave him fair warning (he imagined the asshole doctor calling on the hinged cellular phone from the leathery smelling interior of the green BMW, his daughter sleeping ripe and sweet beside him, her young breasts with nipples like berries), still he would have known anyway.

        He felt the spunk raise inside him, blue balls, a knot of aching below his tired thighs. He had half a mind to lock up the place and have a look at his pictures when ("I'll be damned," he thought, "my dick is like a dowser. I see things coming a mile away.") his whore of a tenant shows up wondering whether they couldn't work out something about the rent this month again, rubbing up against him, breathing perfume on him.

        "You can suck me off for a week's rent, no more," he said. "And I want it fast because there's business heading my way."

        "Whatever you say Eddie," she said. He almost came hearing how she said it. "I'll wait for you in my chambers."

        She was nutty as a fruitcake, she thought she was a queen.

        She had a mouth like a viper and a knife like a flame.

        He didn't know what hit him.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl4_5.html">
        She imagined an invisible city in the air, its roads like glass. (This isn't necessarily a coincidence, nor an obvious parallel text. She might have heard the same story you did from the same woman.)

        Javier thought women communicated differently, on another frequency known only to them, like the band of nerves along the flanks of fish which serve as a second sight: sonar, radar, reflex and intuition all in one. (In his own mind he could see a salmon, as clear as anything, its sides vaguely rainbowed, plump, silvery. It wasn't often he could summon any vision.) There were bands below the pictures on a television screen which, he had read, could themselves convey information. It was, he imagined, how they carried text with the television channels in Europe. You could sometimes touch a woman along her spine in a way that her whole self trembled. <analepsis>Tevet and Aurelie used to communicate without words. Sometimes he could feel the energy of their communication passing through the room like the currents of a transparent stream.</analepsis>

        Sunlight painted the sleeping girl's hair and the mountains beyond as well.

        Aurelie's new lover, Lisa, <analepsis>said he imagined too much about women. She had told him this</analepsis> (Tevet's mother, his ex-wife, Aurelie, not Lisa) <analepsis>on the phone. Her new lover was a California girl, all blond and tan with bright blue eyes. She had been Tevet's swimming coach, a salmon, it was a strange thing. Once he had read the journal of Vasco de Gama, a Portuguese sailor. It was filled with tales of sea creatures who were half-women and who could glide in the band of salt spume above the waves.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl4_6.html">
        Sometimes songs flowed through her, like breath like blood like water. Yet she couldn't carry a tune, not like some women did, though <analepsis>she had sung well enough she supposed to suit Samantha, half whispering lullabies in her apricot ears, singing tickling rhymes of itsy bitsy spiders, the chained verses of diamond rings that didn't shine and mockingbirds that didn't sing.</analepsis>

        Now it was a May song rang through her like a memory.

        <analepsis>As a girl in Fort Erie she hadn't sung well enough to suit the wimpled nuns and so never mounted the choir loft beneath the wash of colored light from the rose window. (Once singing in the congregation an old woman hushed her and half-frantic she whispered a lie about being part of the choir, how sister had dispersed a number of them throughout the seats to spread out the sound of the hymns.)</analepsis> It was maddening to think a song could so pursue you, or for that matter any memory.

        All day long she remembered the drowned boy in conjunction with the hymn from the May crowning: Hail Virgin, dearest Mary, our lovely Queen of May, Oh spotless blessed virgin.... (lingering over long notes on dearest and virgin).

        "What is that you are humming?" Samantha demanded. "You're driving me crazy, I swear you're becoming an old lady."

        Lisle recalled <analepsis>the white, white ankle socks of the girl, Mary Louise Dillard, and the pink of her calves stretched out atop the wooden stepladder, its steps swathed with blue crepe paper.</analepsis> She could recall as clear as yesterday <analepsis>the collective sigh of all the girls and nuns as the virgin's statue swayed and threatened to topple when the outstretched Mary Louise slipped with the crown of white, woven flowers, the baby's breath, carnation and lady slipper, half-grasping the virgin's head to steady herself.</analepsis> She remembered <analepsis>her satisfaction at this failing, how much she despised Mary Louise, the little saint, how much she envied her crowning dress, white lace bodice beneath the white lace veil, white crinoline above the flushed and trembling legs on the ladder covered in blue paper. How, briefly, she had hoped the girl would fall and drown in her awful goodness and the swirl of lace.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl4_7.html">
        She didn't need to know the sign for drowned. It was like thinking he couldn't shout. Not so much wrong as backwards, as if he were you. He wouldn't need to know the sign for what he was. She wondered if that was what love was, how you thought what the other thought was what you thought or something. The words all backwards. Now she would never know. (It would have been useful to know it, actually, had he come back: Thought drowned: two signs. Smile. Hug. Make the sign for worried and heart. Love.)

        She would sit forever on the damp log and haunt him like love.

        <analepsis>Though he could shout, he could never know if someone heard, never know the sound of his own voice.</analepsis> She would be his voice, that too was love. Though now it was all over. It was as if she had lost her baby, a blue fetus screaming silently in the swirling dark water, arms flailing like the sign for love.

        <analepsis>Once on the eighth grade trip she had seen a painting of a blue Christ the color of sidewalk chalk.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl4_8.html">
        Lisa could literally lift her up. <analepsis>Did once, gripped her at her waist with soft, dark (tanned, always tanned) fingers and raised her up, perching her on the kitchen counter in a single sweep and without a grunt or gulp of breath. It was a whirligig ride, a carnival swirl, a hoot, a giggle. It took her breath away at least, the rise, the laughter, what came after.</analepsis> (Lisa was a hungry girl sometimes, such a swimmer.)

        <analepsis>These were their honeymoon days.</analepsis> Lisa could lift you, lift even a word so hokey into something exact. A honey moon: not full but gibbous. slightly swollen, ripe, the curve and color of tropical fruit (what were their names? she never could remember: mango or papaya, threads of gold in your teeth and the honey sweet astringency on your broad tongue ).

        <analepsis>It was a sitcom at first, like Ricky Ricardo sweeping Lucy off her feet, when she lifted and propped her up on the counter.</analepsis> Tropical fruit.

        <analepsis>"Is that how you think of me?" she was hurt. "Lucy to your Ricky, foolish and noisy."

        "My god," said Lisa, laughing helplessly, "You sound like a gay boy! You should hear yourself: is that how you think of me, wah-wah-wah like Lucy... No, darling, I've always seen you as darker, more Rhoda than Lucy, less the whining orangutan more the tuft of dark, unwanted hair..."

        They laughed. They laughed. It was good. They laughed. Honey moon.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl4_9.html">
        <analepsis>There came a time when they began to build roads in the air. It was a fad, a certain madness or a fancy that overtook engineers throughout Canada. The States as well: there was a road wended in a snake's curve high over the harbour, above the maze of ship's canals and the grain elevators, in Buffalo. They called it the Skyway and</analepsis> in retrospect she supposed <analepsis>the others followed from this; it was that way then, everything in her youth followed from the States.</analepsis> Now the flow reverses, a river of cars toward Toronto every weekend.

        In any case <analepsis>for a time it was a pastime for her father to motor through the air in the way some men motored the river in boats. They would fly over St. Kitts (and he'd recite an elaborate rhyme of pies and a place called St Ives) then settle down briefly along the blue oceanic edge of Lake Ontario before flying up over Burlington and into Hamilton, where on a good day, a clear day, you could see not forever but Toronto, "the toe" her father called it, the spire of the CN Tower a needle over the pearl water. He was the only man she knew who called it the toe. When they told her he had died in an auto accident, she imagined he had taken off into the air on a whirly wheel, motoring high across the water of the lake and beyond the toe.

        She imagined an invisible city in the air, its roads like glass.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl4_10.html">
        <analepsis>In Ontario her mother knew a girl named Delores Peters (she remembered the name, "sad stones" her mother said, "it means sad stones,") whose father had purchased a carnival ride and brought it home on a trailer hitched to the back of his Mercury. It was a children's whirly wheel, blue metal cars like stumpy little shoes each with a black rubber safety belt and running around a sheet metal track, scuffed and burnished to a dim mirror where the car wheels ran and the children walked getting on and off the ride . The cars were attached to the end of blue steel spider arms with a string of Christmas lights down their centers and ran round and round the polished metal track without spinning or rising, one behind another until you squeezed the handle of the greased upright brake and slowed them to a stop.

        It had been a bargain. The man who sold it owed a gambling debt to a gangster from Niagara Falls and he needed to move fast. He showed a picture round the taproom of a tavern in Crystal Beach, itself an amusement park town. The picture had scalloped edges as if cut with a pinking shears and the image was a little faded, <prolepsis>or so her mother remembered over the years. She knew that Delores Peters kept it even after her father's death.</prolepsis>

        The tavern parking lot was unpaved and huge, large enough that sometimes tractor trailer drivers parked there while they had an ale, easily pulling in and out without the need to turn their rigs around. It was a dusty space that left a taste of stone in your mouth when you walked across it.

        ... </analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl4_11.html">
        He settled like the tide, then sank eventually, floating aimlessly and softly, not at all like a log but languishing and plump, a white witness to the darkness.

        <analepsis>After the first spike of pain and the panic there was a settling sense of inevitability, the body pitted against itself, both longing for breath and at the same time snuffing it with each gulping inhalation of the frigid, pungent water. The first swallow tore against his lungs but successive ones softened them and made him heavy. Soon he was beyond panic.

        There was a pinging echo as if someone hammered against a nearly empty air tank with a wrench.

        A sense of someone swimming nearby in dark water.</analepsis>

        A woman came to visit him bearing a garland of dried vines strung with flowers of various shades of blue and a few stray blossoms of pink and yellow. She sang a strange song of a Portuguese sailor and a witch. Above him water lilies floated like green clouds. They were tethered to the muck on swaying cords of soft green. Another girl signed his name over the water, singing as she formed the letters.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl4_12.html">
        Her mother's lover had a daughter not much older than her. She supposed they could be sisters if that interested either of them, her mother or the other girl, Beth. Samantha had no strong feelings, one way or the other.

        Actually she supposed Javier, the lover, would have a say as well. He was a doctor also, they always had their say. And his wife as well, the lost one with the fairy tale name, Lorelei or something. <analepsis>She had seen her once with her lover, another woman, they were walking near the park and laughing and someone, this boy in her class, said something dumb; Samantha told him to shut up even though she felt it was kind of weird for your mother to love another woman. She felt like she was already defending her sister, long before she had her.</analepsis>

        Sometimes it was so confusing figuring out the relationships among people anymore that she thought it might do just as well to think you were related to everyone. Your mother's lover would be your other mother or your aunt. <analepsis>There was a girl whose boyfriend had drowned in the creek and her mother (Samantha's not the drowned girl's) had rushed out to look for her after they saw her on TV.</analepsis> She was no relation to the boy who had died and yet Samantha was certain her heart must have ached as much as anyone's. Samantha would let her be her sister as well if she wanted to.

        Outside her window the moon shone blue on the dark water.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl5_2.html">
        He told Tevet the story of the twelve foot quilt that Lee was making. (He addressed his daughter as Beth, using the name she preferred because it seemed right for a story of what flows. They were still driving in the blue mountains.)

        "But who would ever use it?" Beth asked.

        "I don't know that she has thought of that," Javier said, "To her it is a place. Like these mountains..."

        He gestured along the windshield indicating the panorama before them. Sometimes, Beth thought, he was a man of grand gestures.

        "It is the river," he said.

        "So it's not for using, it's for flowing," Beth said.

        (Such a coincidence. Still not unusual.)

        "I suppose," Javier said. She was a good daughter, a poet.

        They flowed through this time together and he felt they touched upon something central between them, some fundamental link, the antithesis of water.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl5_3.html">
        The truth was Ed Stanko was as terrified of death as any man, though once he got used to it it didn't seem so bad, only lonely, far lonelier than he ever had imagined. At first he felt the searing knife sunk through his gut like a falling anchor until it stuck, caught on a bone or rock deep in the muck and hooked there, steadying him. Then fire. For awhile he was blinded by the blue rage in the woman's eyes but after a time that too grew familiar and vaguely distant like the anchor within him. Then he became slowly aware of the smells in the killing room, lilacs and the damp, metallic smell of blood, musk perfume, faint clove, and the oily smell of the steel blade, the familiar stench of shit in his drawers. Something else, the smell of a woman in sex.

        He pulled the water over him like a blanket and slept, lonelier than he had ever been.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl5_4.html">
        <prolepsis>She wore a mantilla of black lace and waited for her Portuguese lover to return from the sea. It wasn't long before he arrived in the company of their daughter, a girl with eyes as black as night and whom Eleanore hadn't seen since <analepsis>they went to sea.</analepsis>

        They paused at the door, sweetly reticent and appropriately formal after these years (Javier was nothing if not courtly).

        The daughter asked to see the owner. It was charming, she had lost all memory of her mother it was clear. Eleanore smiled at Javier, but subtly so as not to embarrass the charming girl. It was something they shared, a recognition.

        Outside the twilight sky turned from Delft to Dresden blue.

        "Oh my darling, he's burning in hell by now," Eleanore said and smiled.

        Though his corpse lay wide-eyed above, sunk in a tub of flowers.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl5_5.html">
        <analepsis>They paused at the door, sweetly reticent and appropriately formal after these years (Javier was nothing if not courtly).

        Tevet asked to see the owner.

        The woman was mad as the wife of a sea captain. She was all done up in a black lace mantilla and her eyes flashed white as new stars. He recognized her well.

        "Senor Stanko is indisposed," she said.

        Javier eased his daughter toward the door, his hip pressing against hers, his eyes locked upon the mad stars beneath the black lace.

        Tevet...Beth couldn't hear what the madwoman said.

        "Burning...Oh my darling, he's burning in hell by now," the woman said, letting the mantilla slip from her head to show a sad smile.</analepsis>

        Her cheeks were streaked with bloody tracks like warpaint. Her lips were painted black. It was something he was used to from Beth (from his daughter, from Tevet, not the blood but the lipstick, young girls wore it).

        "Another time then," Javier said, still easing his daughter toward the door, this time taking her arm.

        "Daddy," she said, "her face... she"

        "I need your help, little one," the madwoman said. Her eyes were painted with dark blue eyeshadow, dark as plums. She hissed her request like an asp, though softly, forlorn.

        Black lips against pale white flesh.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl5_6.html">
        Samantha loved these days when she drowned in her mother's memories and sailed amidst a sea of stories. She could even put up with the godawful humming and the maudlin episodes of scanning the river for silk cocoons, sunken boys, avenging queens and whatever else floated there in her mother's seeing.

        "Tell me about when you first met my father," she would say and her mother obliged her, adding levels of detail as they each aged.

        "He had the bluest eyes and hair as black as peat moss," was an answer for a young girl.

        To the young woman, she made this confession:

        "His ass was white and skinny as a whippet and I clung to it so hard I broke a fingernail. I sang all the way through and screamed when I came and I knew I had you."

        "My god, how gross!" Samantha protested, "Who could believe you, Lisle? You go from May crowning and the Virgin Mary to much more than I ever wanted to know about my missing father. Couldn't you just start with a name and work your way up to the broken fingernail?"

        Still she hunted her mother's eyes for this passion and wondered what <analepsis>she meant about knowing she had her.</analepsis>

        The crimson name drawn, like a knife, against the white.

        Her father's name was lost in history. She remembered <analepsis>his face like a dream of television.</analepsis> She had a firmer memory of <analepsis>brown fingers and the smell of tobacco. She was three when he left them, her mother had begun medical school.</analepsis>

        "I've told you a hundred times. His name was Henry. His friends called him Corky. It's a better name for him. He floated in like a cork, he floated away. There you were."

        "Henry what?"

        "Henry Stone, Henry Cloud. What does it matter? He sank from sight, he floated away like a Portuguese sailor. We have each other."

        "That never happens, Lisle. People have names and stories. They have middles and endings."

        "It happened this time," her mother said. "He was once, you are now. This time there are only beginnings."
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl5_7.html">
        Salt. Semen. Shore. Semaphore. Semiquaver.

        She was still a baby when her mother died though as she grew she would stand on the shore and search for her for hours, year on year, sometimes standing so still so long that her feet sank to her ankles in the doughy sand and her eyes hurt from the glare.

        <prolepsis>There was a shore where your eyelids met that shone with salt sometimes if you squinted after you swam, diamonds of light so sharp they stung like nettles if you stared too long. Jellyfish lazed like transparent parasols in the lapsing surf, viscous as sperm. "And what is sperm like?" precocious she, age three, asked her father after he told her where babies came from. Salty, he said, like the ocean and smooth like egg white or jellyfish. "Can I see it?" she asked. It embarrassed him, then made him angry when his girlfriend laughed. When you marry, he said, when you marry.

        It was a confusion. She thought that sperm was a shore and she could find her mother there like a mirror. Where babies came from.</prolepsis> <prolepsis>In time she saw sperm and knew she would never marry. In girl scouts she learned how to send code by semaphore and from time to time for years after would stand at the edge of the sand where the surf curled like lace spelling out the letters of her mother's name. She did this idly, without belief, in the way other people prayed.

        Like a girl at the edge of a dark creek signing the words "love" and "silence."</prolepsis>

        <prolepsis>As a teenager she would snorkel and dive down, trying on the thick ropes of weed like her mother's jacket. By that time she knew the stories of mermaids, naiads, and sirens. Back on shore she would weep a high howling that quavered like blues notes among the darkening waves. She became a strong swimmer out of grief.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl5_8.html">
        Lisa inevitably called it "the life." It was, Aurelie knew, a political term, something proud and meant to comfort and affirm. And yet it left her feeling dangerously superior, bemused in the way that Tevet's idealism likewise delighted and saddened her all at once. It was dangerous to think of one's lover and daughter in the same way: lovely, earnest, and--to be sure-- strong (Lisa's shoulders were a Tuscan wall, brown and softly contoured, smooth as dew slicked clay but somehow ancient), both so very quick to change moods, emotions, ideas, causes, attentions.

        Mercurial. A girl with a silver ball in her palm.

        Aurelie thought of it as the quiet space. <analepsis>They had not run away (runaway train came to mind, or the curious curlicue exits from mountain roads where runaway trucks were supposed to barrel off up a slope into the percussive barrier and soft sand, rocking gently to a stop like a silver ball in a pinball machine), instead this space had always been there like an unnamed prospect. Lisa arrived like someone who had long been expected, a traveler, a distant relation, now for a while home here.</analepsis> Ah, there you are, she thought (if she thought anything). She watched through the hexagons of a chainlink fence as the coach prowled the concrete margin along the blue water of the pool, intense and somehow regal, a faded bath towel around her shoulders like a shawl, long brown legs with perfect calves, and Cleopatra toes, the same long, slightly knobby toes as her own daughter churning now among the other swimmers in the pool. Ah, there you are, she thought, the brown toes lifting up and curling down.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl5_9.html">
        There was more than one way to go over the Falls. The wind stole across the lake sometimes and brought snow so deep it drifted blue; other times it roared across the prairie from Manitoba and beyond leaving mountains of white as high as Horseshoe Falls and as hard as ice beneath the feathery drifts. When the wind ceased and the thin sun came out they would bundle in leggings with scarves around their faces and drag toboggans up the wind-whirled hills leaving swirls of wake in the trail behind them. Though the toboggans were of course open to the air they seemed as dim as tunnels once everyone was bundled within and huddled together, arms around each other, their heads tucked down into the available darkness. Someone, a strong boy or one or two of the bigger girls, would push them off and plop in behind the last rider and they would roar down in light and darkness through a plume of white powder and laughter.

        It was in the tunnel of a toboggan that she first felt someone, a boy named Eddie, fondle her breast, kneading it as he clung to her from behind, his thighs pressing against her sides and ribs. She made certain to sit in front of him the next time down to be sure that what she felt hadn't been by accident. When he fondled her again, she elbowed him sharply, enough to let him know, and then made certain never to ride in front of him again.

        In the carnival there was a ride which was sometimes called the Alpine toboggans. The cars sped round and round upon an inclined circle faster and faster forward and then once again faster and faster in reverse while all the time rock music played almost louder than you could stand if you weren't on the ride. It was always full but especially at night when the toboggan cars whirled through the half-circle tunnel of darkness and into the falling water of the midway lights. She asked him once what made everyone want to ride this bright and noisy, awful thing. "It makes you hot," he said and he had a buddy take over for him and jumped on the ride with her. They went faster and faster and he fondled her breasts as he held her. When the ride was over they went back to their trailer and fucked until she screamed like she had on the Alpine ride.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl5_10.html">
        There hadn't been time to go back home and get the pickup truck when Delores Peters father bought the whirly ride and so the man who sold it threw in a ball hitch as part of the bargain and then helped him balance the load of the Mercury using blocks of wood to shim the shot springs. The ride was surprisingly compact on its trailer. The blue cars stored up on end like cupcakes, the curves of their metal pitted and scarred from being painted over where it had been chipped. The spider legs folded like a pocket knife when their bolts were loosened. The engine and the upright brake were bolted to the trailer together with a folding metal stool where the operator could sit to take tickets or run the ride.

        The ride ran on either 220 or 440 power and had a noisy gas powered generator for when there was no power available, although the generator roared so bad it made the ride unpleasant and sometimes stalled or spewed black smoke which tended to frighten children. Delores Peters' father paid nine hundred dollars cash for the whirly ride in 1965. He was a farmer and his credit was good and the bank in Crystal Beach lent him the cash on his word. It was something you could take from fair to fair or just set up on its own for children to ride.

        There hadn't been time to go home for the pickup yet he and the stranger went into town to get the loan and the cash. For an awful moment after the stranger drove off, Delores Peters' father feared that he had been fooled and his stomach felt hollow from the beer, the sunshine, and the dusty stone parking lot. But the ride ran just right when he got it home and he was able to set it up without much trouble although it hadn't come with any directions but the fading scalloped snapshot.

        ...
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl5_11.html">
        You naturally think none of this can happen, no consciousness in the grub or maggot, none in the the fallen bird, the grain of wood, the drowned boy. And yet for all of your life you have wondered, redeeming that word: a wonder.

        What the world knows without us. A pang of remorse after snuffing the ant, a lingering melancholy as the jaunty wires of the daddy longlegs fold beneath a scuffing foot, the soft pellet of the knowing body smearing into liquid. You think only boys feel this? So be it, this was a boy who floats now like a sunless leaf.

        A wonder. Do we live beyond our breath?

        The fascination of maggots, which should be god's brightest creatures in some other telling, corpulent and bright, all one mind. The tern you watched until the fear made you turn away. Solitary on a forlorn rock, squawking at the unrelenting wind, wings rusted, feet scummed, clear dark eye upon you. This is life for some creatures.

        He feels the hot knife and the lonesome scream of the man in the blue mountains, feels the woman's eyes like searchlights, listening within, floats beneath the water lily and the green skim of water chestnut.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl5_12.html">
        Life was hard sometimes for everyone, Samantha knew. Hard as coal, her mother said. It was a strange phrase, Samantha thought. It confused her because she always thought of charcoal, which wasn't hard but crumbled into powder. There were charcoal sticks you bought for art, some still in the shape of twigs, there were the dark pillows of briquettes.

        Coal she knew was like a faceted black mirror. <analepsis>It was what her mother was raised with in Canada. There wasn't a son on the farm and so like everyone she shoveled coal, her mother and father both doing so as well. The wind stole across the lake sometimes and brought snow so deep it drifted blue; other times it roared across the prairie from Manitoba and beyond. You had to shovel a lot of coal.</analepsis>

        Still to hear her mother say so was strange. She had soft fingers and wore tailored suits which flattered her hips. Life was hard as coal.

        Her mother's lips were plums and her eyes clear blue, like water. It was, she said, because she needed clear eyes to fight diseases. <analepsis>There was a play they read in junior high when everyone else was reading Lady Macbeth called The Enemy of the People by Ibsen. The hero of the play made her think of her mother. He too was a doctor, he too believed in the clarity and truth.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl6_2.html">
        Like most men of his age, and physicians especially he supposed, he was not necessarily able to take to heart-- (he was not unaware of this pun on his calling: he was the heart's colonialist and wore a broad Panama, harvester sometimes, implanter others) what he otherwise could see. Yet he tried to look at things through other's viewpoints. He thought of Lee and her microscopes and how the world for her flowed vitreous, our lives already patchwork, platelet rafts, petals on a stream.

        "So it's not for using, it's for flowing," the lesson Beth learned from Lee's quilt came naturally to them both. But not to him. It was harder not to think the world was made for use. He had been brought up so, proud son to a proud father, and medicine believed as much then when he came to it. It believed so still. You found a use for what you do, you intervened in flow, not like a young boy dams the water but like the one who streams his hand behind the boat, trolling for patterns.

        The scalpel found patterns of life's flowing.

        He feared for Tevet (for Beth) that sometime the pure intervention of events would stop the flow. It was a father's fear of accident or murder, heartbreak or breathstop, loss or leaving. She was his chicory flower, his margin, his everpresent beauty, the measure of miles.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl6_3.html">
        Ed imagined he had floated at least three miles before he surfaced next and his lungs fairly burst with the pain of holding his breath. At first when he surfaced he spit blood but then he realized it was only plum wine and probably a dream.

        He floated up in a still pool fringed with iris among waterlilies and blood red lotus. There were Jerries nearby and so he broke off a hollow reed to breath through and slipped below the black surface of the water, drawing it over him like the rubber sheets that whores used.

        Someone tossed daisies upon the surface of the water and bluegills rose and hit them thinking it was bait fall. A Messerschmidt strafed the water and the shells went pock pock pock, echoing hollowly beneath the surface, then tumbling down into the sand. A young girl was mourning for her drowned lover, tossing carnations on the water.

        Each white puff was a cloud.

        The buddha sat on the shore large as life, his skin green and smooth as the belly of a copper frog. It was the damnedest thing.

        "I didn't think you were real," Ed said gently.

        "Oh I am, lover, I'm as real as an ocean," the whore said. She was Eleanore of Aquataine or someone, the queen who floated away from King Arthur in the mist.

        He was enjoying this. He laughed so hard his neck split open and his guts spilled out.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl6_4.html">
        Vasco de Gama took her in his arms. He was a copper, a watersnake, a vascular surgeon on vacation. Everything went crazy and they gave her a standing ovulation.

        The carotid was uncommonly hard to slice, more giblet than sweetbread.

        Or did she mean gizzard? The blue heart like a stone.

        She spat Jack Sprat from her mouth in one deft slice, she was Ophelia, sister to D'Artagnan, lover of Les Trois Mousquetaires.

        You think it is all comic? There is real evil in this world and we have to root it out by the root. (She took his unlovely member in her mouth and, a watersnake, sucked the venom out.)

        The way to heal a snakebite was to cut slashes across the affected part.

        The blue heart like a stone.

        Athos, Pathos, and Thanatos.

        You have the right to remain perfectly silent.

        You have the right to remain eternally silent.

        You have the right to silence.

        Or fire.

        You have silence.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl6_5.html">
        Afterward Beth wondered why he hadn't just taken the picture of his great grandmother if that was the reason for this whole crazy quest. In the excitement no one would have questioned it, no one really would have known it was gone.

        She was glad <analepsis>she hadn't seen the dead guy, not even in the body bag when they took him out. It was sad enough seeing that poor woman with her face streaked with blood.</analepsis>

        The bag she knew was made of vinyl and zipped from end to end like a sleeping bag but closing over his head. In their car they had a soft-sided cooler, an insulated bag where they kept drinks cool while they drove, the teeth of its zipper large and shiny.

        <analepsis>The ride home was like a funeral procession in a dream where they had somehow gotten lost, detached from all the others cars.</analepsis>

        The things you thought she thought. It was peaceful in the mountains, the light at dusk along the ridges as blue as their name.

        <analepsis>Eleanore of Castile was so mourned by her husband, Edward I, that he erected crosses at each place where her cortege stopped between Lincoln and Westminster.</analepsis>

        She remembered <analepsis>the face of her great great grandmother in the picture. She had studied it while they waited for the state troopers. How brave her father was, how gentle with the lady murderer.

        In English class they had read Macbeth. Lisle, her father's lover, told her that actors never called it that, never said it by name, because it was unlucky.</analepsis>

        A murder most foul. The Scottish play.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl6_6.html">
        Samantha walked down to the edge of the creek where the spongy earth ceased in a scrum fringe like the edge of a dark carpet. The shore smelled like potting soil or something more familiar, the smell of blood sometimes at your period.

        <analepsis>It was ripe water her mother said once.</analepsis> Already the water chestnuts began to grow beneath the black surface of the water. They would grow into another carpet, an emerald one extending from the scum fringe to the opposite shore of the estuary.

        Ripe and riparian.

        There was an image of the sky inside the ebony water, a scoop of blue and tufts of feathery white, the reflection floating there like a damp photograph.

        She was startled by a swimmer surfacing exactly in the patch of blue where the photograph floated. He was a skinny boy, naked and white as soap, the hollows of his buttocks as blue as photographs. The boy smoothed his black hair straight back against his skull. It was black as tar and shined like the water. He smiled and showed uneven teeth. His eyes were wary.

        His name was Henry Stone and he had come back to her.

        It is a good story, her mother said, I like how the earth smells like blood.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl6_7.html">
        She had never been lonelier, never more blue. When you are the surviving girlfriend and a teenager you are no one. His family didn't really know her. She imagined they were suspicious of her for slipping into his silence with him (both his parents were hearing and <analepsis>had swum with him in this dark pool long before she joined him</analepsis>). Sometimes she thought of really joining him, getting up from the bleached log and all its familar warts and eyes, walking the five feet along the gravelly sand and wading into the water until she sank like a stone, until she too could hear nothing but the roar of the sea within.

        Like the girl on the Pacific shore tries to decipher the voice of her mother in the roar.

        Already she was deaf to so much. In the cafeteria in the days after she would see the eyes upon her, see the lips move, the tears and the laughter, the fright and disdain. Yet she heard nothing. It was the same when she sat at the boatlaunch, watching empty voices shout and hearing nothing. It was as if she were underwater (she was not unaware of these ironies, or their commonplace, she was a bright girl, his family liked her, her own family worried about her). She was a minor character.

        Sometimes she imagined she had a friend, another girl, who understood. They stood near the dark lip of water, their shoulders barely touching, their eyes like searchlights, listening within.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl6_8.html">
        We were raptors, falcons, women clinging to one another and the earth, long toes curled about a brown limb in expectation or ecstasy, poised in the fecund air and awaiting the moist thump and the envelopment of flesh like water washing over, bloody but all vowel: elegant, elegiac, electric, easing into each other's embrace within the tinsel-spun hardened case of the pupa, angel hair trailing like ripples (your hair on my stomach raked in carefully combed waves, a zen garden tended by silent woman dragging the rattan claws over the sand like swirling gentle scratches).

        In the blue pool below the falls, moaning.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl6_9.html">
        We were raptors, falcons, clinging to one another and the earth, long toes curled about a brown limb in expectation or ecstacy, poised in the fecund air and awaiting the moist thump and the envelopment of flesh like water washing over, bloody but all vowel: elegant, elegiac, electric, easing into each other's embrace within the tinsel-spun hardened case of the pupa, angel hair trailing like ripples (your hair on my stomach raked in carefully combed waves, a zen garden tended by silent woman dragging the rattan claws over the sand like swirling gentle scratches).

        In the blue mirror of your eye, moaning.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl6_10.html">
        He tapped power from the 220 line in the barn and ran the thick black rubber cable to a nice shady space not far from the chestnut tree. There weren't neighbors nearby to watch this effort or it might have gathered a crowd. Even so Delores and her mother watched expectantly and not without some puzzlement. Despite the shade her father sweated, his shirt dark with moisture under the arms and in an upright swatch from his chest to his belly. Sometimes when he caught her eye he smiled.

        There was a trick or two to getting the whirly ride set up just right. You had to be plumb level or the spider arms would shudder slightly and groan and the wheels of the blue cars would skid or balk a little by turns. Still he got it going all right.

        "Have a ride," he said to Delores when he was done. He gestured toward the blue cars on their track like someone pointing to a dance floor.

        "You too, love," he told her mother, "It's strong enough for both of you if you ride across the way from her."

        At first it was very strange for them, mother and daughter on opposite arms, one at three o'clock and one at nine. They were not certain whether they were chasing each other or balancing each other, and if chasing each other who came first and who behind. It was also very quiet at first, only the wobbly rubber noise of the greased black wheels along the burnished track and the softly urgent straining of the electric motor. For awhile they may have wondered if they should have made a noise, whether squealing or laughing brightly, and how exactly they should let him know when they had had enough.

        He watched them happily, the ride was running smoothly and it was a bargain really, though he wasn't really one to show a range of emotion. In time he discovered a small basket weave suitcase tucked next to the wheel of the trailer, the straw colored basketry frayed and torn but the latch and hinges still shiny brass. Inside there was a record player with a large speaker and two different records with tunes to play along with the ride. It was a surprise. They waved when they wanted him to stop.

        ...
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl6_12.html">
        Sometimes she couldn't believe her mother; she could go from telling stories of <analepsis>when she was a little girl in a farmhouse on the Canadian plain and of May crownings and the Virgin Mary dressed in blue to telling you way too much more than you ever wanted to know about getting felt up on some amusement park ride and having sex in trailers.</analepsis> It was all too strange for a women who wore tailored linen suits and bare legs in January.

        Yet she was a mom and when you needed her she was there.

        She never needed her more than when the boy floated up along the shore outside their house.

        One story her mother used to tell her still confused her. <level degree="2">There was a Chinese poet named Li Po who fell in love with the moon's reflection on his way home in a boat after a night of drinking plum wine. He stood up in the rocking boat and the stars spun as he reached out to embrace her, to embrace the moon, and, dizzy from the wine and the stars and the moon, he fell in and drowned.</level>

        It was supposedly a true story.

        But what confused her was something she remembered about <analepsis>a movie made by a German lady where a man falls into the earth and which her mom had thought of out of nowhere another time when she told the story of Li Po. That second time he was called Li Bo, B like boy, and he really didn't drown for love of the moon but died in some relatives house where he had gone because he had no money and no one to love him except the moon.</analepsis>

        There was an image of the sky inside the ebony water, a scoop of blue and tufts of feathery white, the reflection floating there like a damp photograph. She was startled to see the surface of the moon, as real as flesh, exactly in the patch of blue where the photograph floated.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl7_2.html">
        She wondered why he didn't simply take the picture. It was a wonder for a heart's colonialist, an intervener.

        Events had only the sadness of their course to give them form. Yet since form gave the world what joy we could discern there, this was a paradox. There were times when he wasn't too hardened by the routine of his practice when he could discern the merest turning, like someone standing high upon a precipice beyond a river (here among the Blue Ridge mountains say, or the Catskills near the creek where Lee lived; though he was aware, even as it came, that this image had its source in dark nuns' childhood explanations of how God's bright providence shone in the face of our free will).

        He would see a patient in a pre-op consultation, the room light low for the vigil of his family, a hopeful wife perhaps (the damp and wadded handkerchief in her hand belying her humble confidence), a solicitous son or a brash one (filled with golf course businessman's bravado, "Let's get this over, doc, huh? You and me."); and look past them beyond the dark hollow man's of the man's eyes looking for what spark was there, if any.

        It was like standing high above a stream.

        He would sometimes shudder in the knowledge that he would see them each again, humble wife, brash son, dark father alike, each at last transported into something transcendent and bright, the sadness of his life's course giving them form.

        "I'm sorry," he would say, "We did all we could do, your loved one as well. He couldn't sustain this operation and we couldn't keep him beyond what he could sustain."

        It was a photograph as well. All history was a photograph you couldn't take (he was aware of this pun as well. it was what people said in their grief: they couldn't take it), a photograph you couldn't take but could only to be given.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl7_3.html">
        He didn't deserve any but the death he was destined for though he understood in some sense what had brought him to this one. <analepsis>As a child with Polish parents he had been raised a Catholic and was as a result imbued with a sense of the necessity for repentance.</analepsis> It wasn't clear to him whether this belated recognition of how the woman might have found him worthy of death could qualify as same.

        In any case he had not sought confession or absolution, from her or any man, or from any human creature. <analepsis>On chill Spring mornings as a child during Holy Weeks he had made the pilgrimage with other children to seven churches, a devotion said to ensure a last confession.</analepsis> (Or was it the nine First Fridays?)

       <analepsis>He had loved his wife once and, for awhile, raised his children as best he could. He worked hard for many years without insisting that it be recognized as anything more than what it was.</analepsis>

        He liked to fish, liked the moment when the dark form struck from deep within the blue water, liked the smell of them when the batter touched the hot grease.

        He sometimes thought about things.

        He wasn't a good man. To his credit he knew as much at the end.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl7_4.html">
        She was not crazy, it was a pose, a stance she took as others did happiness. She supposed that to act according to your nature and hold to that was a measure of holiness. Thus she convinced the public defender not to enter a plea of insanity.

        It isn't pleasant to kill someone and harder than you think, whether in real life (an ironic usage) or in writing.

        It made her blue (and neither of us proud).

        <analepsis>Ed Stanko never deserved any but the death he was destined for.</analepsis>

        Though who can say whether he died too early.

        Not her. She had her own death to face now.

        And the memory of the poor child, sister to her unborn daughter.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl7_5.html">
        They drove straight through on the way up North unlike <analepsis>the ride down.</analepsis> <analepsis>It was early morning before the police finished questioning them, finally letting them go with the promise that they would return for further questioning.</analepsis> They set off for home as the sun rose in the mist and didn't really stop except for the bathroom all the way up 95, the Garden State, and the Thruway. The sun followed them all the way. Tevet slept fitfully, sometimes catching her breath in dreams and once or twice moaning, yet when she woke she couldn't remember whether or what she dreamed. Her eyes were so vacant that he hoped she would fall back to sleep. He offered her a sedative but she declined.

        She sprawled on the seat like a ragdoll until her eyes closed.

        Javier called Lisle from the cellphone and learned what had gone on there, then he called Tevet's mother and spoke to her lover, Lisa, who said Lee was out but had been worried all night. He left her the number for the carphone although they had it and Aurelie called back when she got home. Javier woke Beth to take the call but she was still too tired to really offer anything but grunts. He had thought she would cry again when she spoke to her mother but there was no weeping. One time, however, after a long silence on Beth's end her mother must have said said something that made her laugh.

        The laughter didn't last long and her eyes were wet after the call. When he asked what had made her laugh she said it was nothing.

        It annoyed him unreasonably the way she had laughed and then said it was nothing. Little things were suddenly bothering him beyond what they should. There was a blue insulated picnic sack in the back of the car where they stowed diet cola for her and a few bottles of Evian for him. At one point, trying to get himself a drink while she slept, the zipper jammed as he reached back. He dragged the damn thing up to the front and sat it on his lap, thrashing at it to get at the drinks.

        The jammed teeth of the zipper grinned like a circus clown. It made him so mad that the ripped the bag to shreds with his teeth and hands.

        <analepsis>The police had not asked whether he knew the suspect.</analepsis> The insulation from the shredded bag hung down in jagged grey tongues while the melting ice and water soaked his lap and the seat next to him.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl7_6.html">
        Her mother liked to listen to the BBC on a huge wooden radio curved like the arch of a cathedral, a Philco <analepsis>she had brought down from Canada after her father died.</analepsis> The radio was almost chest high to Samantha and divided into segments. The upper panel was a midnight blue rainbow of all the frequencies, AM, FM, SW1, SW2, and so on, the numbers silver against the curve of the rainbow dial. That dark curve nestled within the cathedral arch like a rhyme. A large black tuning knob as big as your palm moved an amber needle across the rainbow. The needle moving like a caravan through storms of static, unintelligible broadcasts in lost languages, the high pitched chirps of Morse code, and echoing signals that she used to imagine were the dispatches from ships at sea.

        There was a center panel of cherry wood narrower than the top and about two thirds of the way up from the floor. Swirls of burnished woodgrain floated like auburn honey within the panel. It was beautiful to look at when all the other lights were out and the cherry wood was illuminated by only the spill of the pale orchid light from the tuning panel.

        Beneath the cherrywood a broad expanse of silver-blue speaker cloth was pulled taut behind sunburst spokes of the same cherrywood. If you looked closely at the speaker cloth you could see it pulse and sigh in the exhalations of the great paper bellows of the speaker behind it.

        It reminded her of an Easter lily the silky way it sat there.

        Usually her mother listened to the BBC Foreign Service on which pompous British men spoke the news in low tones and later earnest English women announced elegies by French composers. Today she listened to the Newburgh all-news station which twenty past and twenty before every hour carried breaking news for the mid-Hudson valley, today headlined by the recovery of a drowning victim from Wappingers Creek.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl7_7.html">
        Mine. Mind. Wine. Time. Dive.

        It wasn't that she felt she had rescued Lee from something, never thought she pulled her out of her own depths as if from a dark current. Lee was the kind of person who periodically gave birth to herself.

        "Parthenogenetic," Aurelie suggested and Lisa shrugged.

        "If you say so, " she smiled. "You know me. I don't do words."

        It was true and, shockingly, a delight to Lee. Lisa was given to simple rhymes and musical elisions, the new age vocalise of a California girl. "It means giving birth to yourself," Lee said, "I got that stuff from my husband. Words and wine lore, a love of wine."

        A thigh stained ruby, the blue red of Merlot or raw beef. Her birthmark.

        "And a daughter."

        "Do you mind that?" Aurelie asked suddenly aware that the younger woman could have been. It was hard to know how to talk with her about mothers.

        "Don't go sitcom on me, woman. You know I love Beth. I wouldn't have her any other way, even if she hates me."

        "She doesn't hate you. It's just that she doesn't know what to think. Her world hasn't had enough women in it until now."

        The phone rang. It was the sheriff's dispatcher wondering if Lisa was available to dive that night with the auxiliary. It was the first time they had called since the deaf boy drowned in the creek and so Lisa drove out in the warm air to the river where she suited up and dove through a spill of moonlight looking for a lost girl.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl7_8.html">
        Floating she found herself worried about her daughter, about Tevet, about Beth. It wasn't that she thought something had happened to her while she was away with her father. Or not at least something physical. It didn't feel like peril but it was woe.

        Lisa noticed her unsettledness in her sleep and woke silent and that sudden in the way she did, her dark eyes wide and upward.

        "You alright?" she asked.

        Aurelie smoothed the sheet along the other woman's breast as in other years she had smoothed the blankets over Teveth. "Yes," she said, "a mother's fears."

        Regretted as soon as she said it: Lisa didn't do mother.

        "Mmm hmm," Lisa purred, "Let me know if I can help you." Almost instantly she slipped back to sleep in the way she could, a swimmer knifing into dark and dreams, her long flanks stretching and then relaxing as the sleep closed over her.

        <analepsis>Aurelie had willed Beth along through life, she knew, luring her from where she sometimes snagged and lingered, bringing her shoreward through dreams and distant worries. Just as surely once she had birthed her. Reaching inward to the smooth space in the center of the terrible and seismic contractions, she had guided her serene daughter, willing her through the channel like a child in a basket. She had felt her coming like a lost memory, sailing from the bay where she floated, placid as the moon, in the buffering waters of her mother's belly.

        When they had brought the baby to her, put her daughter to her breast, her cheeks were streaked with blood like a warrior woman and her blue eyes were fierce and clear.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl7_9.html">
        There were so many ways to go over the Falls, whether in a barrel or a book or in a body. <analepsis>When she was a child she used to especially like a certain series of illustrated books where every chapter or so was punctuated by an ink line illustration. She read these books as if they were tunnels where each illustration was a glimpse of light before you burrowed back under.</analepsis> It was like when you tarried too long underwater and had to pump your legs and pull the water down from overhead in long strokes behind you in order to surface. Breathless, the upper world seemed miraculous, a place of impossible beauty beyond the blue page of the water, too dazzling to look at for long.

        Tunnels in her own or any body likewise led to impossibly bright vistas.

        In retrospect she realized that <analepsis>the illustrations in the children's classics were almost surely tied to some episode or chapter but she knew she never really saw them as such. Instead they seemed another story in each story, wordless and isolate, as secretive as icebergs.</analepsis>

        You could fall through the world in any book really. That was the point of the rabbit hole that Alice fell through, an image so obvious she always found the story tiresome although girls were supposed to like it. There were times sometimes when she found herself reading a scientific journal in the same way she read as a girl, each figure and illustration an inner landscape, like lovers entwined in a blue and white field of waves.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl7_10.html">
        Delores Peters' father wanted her to invite her friends over for a ride on the whirly wheel and she of course wished to do likewise at first. From the beginning there was something wanting in the experience, a curious sense of mixed expectation and loss. It isn't common to go somewhere where there is a single amusement ride unless it is a carousel and then all the llamas, camels and horses make it seem more than a single ride and the calliope and colors form a spectacle.

        The whirly ride was modest and not a spectacle. In the sunshine the uniform blue enamel had the flatness of weathered house paint although it was clearly fresh and even possessed of a little sparkle. The blue cars seemed somehow Dutch, perhaps on account of the delft color, perhaps because their snub shape suggested foreshortened wooden shoes. Still Delores' mother and father did their best to make the occasion something festive for her friends. Her mother made a frosted cake with roses like a birthday and put a jug of lemonade on ice in a washtub, covering the jug with a dishtowel to keep the yellowjackets away. Her father added other records to the two which had come with the record player in the straw colored suitcase. The song called "How much is that doggie in the window?" was a favorite with the girls. He also found ways to vary the speed of the cars, manipulating the brake somehow to add variation to the ride and making the girls squeal at first. When that wore off, Delores' mother ripped strips of muslin for blindfolds for any girl who wanted to ride with them and both her parents helped tie them over the girls' eyes.

        Before long, of course, the girls drifted off to other play but Delores Peters' father did not seem disappointed. The ride was a success in what it brought together and it was beautiful in its way even when it went around without any riders.

        ...
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl7_11.html">
        You get used to floating, it is after all only a resumption of what we all once had and lost in the light. Even the sounds are the same: the thump and rush of blood, the dark static of the nerves, the soft cry of silence. The thing reaches toward the two faces which float like balloons above the wicker bassinet, their mouths curved to crooning, their eyes bright with expectation and urging. Once the child has clamped the father's finger he swings it gently to the rhythm of her unheard song. They so want you to sing along and yet you are lost in silence, although as yet you do not know it as such, thinking it only the medium you were born into, the jell of distant vision and the inward hiss and bloodrush.

        Years move on above you like clouds. You look into the grimace and rage of the would be playmate who has been shouting at you through the blue haze of the playground. He scuffs the hills you've made with your fingers and the replica metal earthmover. You croon the song you think machines make, unerringly close (you are told) to the actual mechanical grunt. The bully swipes at the toy and your fingers with his foot. You float. He is angry that you do so.

        You float untouched by anger or delight.

        In the cafeteria once school began you see the eyes upon you, see the lips move, the tears and the laughter, the fright and disdain. Yet you hear nothing. It was the same finally when you sat at the boat launch, watching empty voices shout and hearing nothing. It was as if you were underwater (in time you floated beyond these ironies, beyond her reach though you long for her to hold you). You recall love like bright balloons.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl7_12.html">
        Everyone continued to wish they knew more about Samantha. After the drowned boy surfaced she went into a shell of jaunty but ultimately false happiness, doing it so successfully that she fooled everyone, herself included. The truth is she had a knack for feigning happiness and did it so well that she was mostly happy though most nights she was assailed by strange dreams. For some time she was too silent even for her own tastes, but then she began to smile. After awhile she was able to talk so easily that people around her treated her as if she were someone who had come back from a long journey with stories to tell, which was of course the truth in a way although it was literally true for Javier's daughter, Beth.

        They had a brief meeting when her father got back and brought her over with him when he came to see Lisle. Neither girl told the other much, though not really out of any lack of compatibility. Quite the contrary, Samantha thought, it was really a way to make space for each other given how much they each had been told by their parents about the other's adventures. While her mother and Beth's father talked they went to her room and laughed about some stuff and looked at old pictures. Beth played a CD by the Smashing Pumpkins and Samantha played a CD by the Talking Heads. Samantha wore blue cut-off jeans, Beth wore one blue earring and her nose was pierced.

        Before she and her father left Samantha told Beth how as a girl she had once resolved to fall in love as often as possible so as to avoid the inevitable distrust which afflicts an orphan or the child of divorced parents.

        "I am both, you know," she said, " a divorced child and an orphan." It was the first she had considered the latter possibility.

        "I like that term for it," Beth said. "A divorced child."
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl8_2.html">
        What happened after all? Was he the man to love a woman who once went over the falls, who whirled a wheel of life, who quilted a river? Did his daughter witness the death of innocence like a comic opera in the forlorn, rustic lobby of a run-down mountain inn? Did fate take its course and did revenge seize its bounty?

        Will we tune in another time.

        What he couldn't understand, finally, was Samantha, his heart's half-daughter, the distant and improbable sister to his own grown girl.

        Couldn't by definition. He hadn't raised her with her mother, hadn't earned (had he raised or earned anything with Tevet, with Beth, his own daughter?) her heart's intervention.

        It wasn't that she was distant, in fact she took him in as she did all others. Her mother's daughter, she had an eye for floating things and for the ever-flowing form of a directionless world.

        There was no single blue for her. She was one who wanted to open things so all threads showed, diurnally, measuring their progress in the stories and occasional proximities. It was November and winter would follow. He hoped his own daughter would like her.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl8_3.html">
        What links the dead man and the murderer, the drowned man and the shore, a once wife and her current lover, dream to memory, November to the new year?

        What links daughter to daughter, girl to boy, sky to moon, blue river to blue air?

        Why do we think the story is a mystery at heart? Why do we think the heart a mystery?

        Who shares one voice?

        Why do you want more?

        Why do we live? Why do we have to die?

        Turn the page, child, turn the page.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl8_4.html">
        I had the strangest feeling, like someone was watching me.

        It was like we shared one voice.

        I called you but you weren't home.

        <analepsis>My mother used to know someone with the same name.</analepsis>

        My body seems to live its own life without me.

        <analepsis>I used to have something the same color blue.</analepsis>

        Why do we think the story is a mystery at heart?

        Why do we think the heart a mystery?

        Who shares one voice?

        Why do you want more?

        Why do we live? Why do we have to die?

        I forgot to turn the calendar after Halloween.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl8_5.html">
        She finally met Lisle's daughter, Samantha, who wasn't half bad really, just a little artsy and pretentious, though Beth supposed she probably seemed pretentious in her own way to her. They listened to records and talked some, each of them aware that the visit was therapy in their father' and mother's eyes respectively and so a little too much on guard. Predictably enough Samantha liked the Talking Heads and actually the CD really wasn't all that horrible if you had to listen all the way through it. She probably had a tattoo on her shoulder or thigh.

        Speaking of tattoos, for a long time Beth found herself doodling the same thing again and again. She would fill sheets with the blue glyphs while she talked on the phone to her boyfriend or someone and sometimes made a variation of it on the back of her hand with a felt tip.


        She knew it was meant to be the Blue Stag. If she had a tattoo she would put it on the underside of her left breast if she could stand it. She didn't see much of Samantha and sometimes thought of giving her a call but she figured it would be best to see what developed between her father and Samantha's mother before making any gestures she would regret.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl8_6.html">
        She watched the Medical Examiner's stethoscope move like a silver moon over the boy's bloated ivory chest. What do we listen for? eternity? echoes of water? all the lost sounds he never heard? a message from Mars? It was merely a reflex gesture or perhaps, she considered, a first step toward establishing time of death. From inside her house, ironically, the BBC Foreign Service broadcast the Kintertotenlieder. None of the police or firemen, nor the Medical Examiner, gave any side of recognizing the Mahler and so perhaps it wasn't ironic but simply elegiac.

        She had made the same gestures, moon across soft ivory, in her case somewhat irrationally assuring herself there were no signs of life before calling the authorities. Then until the sirens arrived she went back in and held the sobbing Samantha.

        What use were sirens? What use were the red and blue lights alternately painting the water? What use were lieder? What use doctors? What could we read in ivory? in air? in water? in the warm hollows of our flesh?

        She watched an ivory moon move over a silver sky. Inside the house her daughter saw death again. Its face was pale as a slice of icicle radish, cold as creek water, soft as the down of a swan. It held her gently as she sobbed and impregnated her dreams.

        Inside the house her phone lay on a pillow buzzing insistently with each unanswered ring at her lover's apartment. <analepsis>She had rung his private number after calling the police and when there was no answer she had left it off the hook and ringing</analepsis>. There was no machine there, few people had this number. She imagined that it might ring eternally, a broadcast into the void, like signals from a satellite moving beyond the edge of our galaxy into empty space and seeking signs of life.

        With her own phone tied up now she knew no one could reach her directly. There was only the service and the beeper, itself a satellite of a sort, on her belt. She thought briefly of tossing it away, far out into the black water where snapping turtles dwelt and bullheads prowled the mucky bottoms. Then she thought of tucking it within her, deep in some orifice like a perverse prosthetic, a fetus of possibility, a drowning child.

        Instead she held it to her cheek and cried.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl8_7.html">
        They stood near the dark lip of water, their shoulders barely touching, their eyes like searchlights, listening within. They were minor characters, suspended between more momentous others, a soft blue line like chalk or thread, curving ever so gently.

        Yet here's a curious thing, not something you might be likely to elevate into a story but one of those cases of interesting coincidences nonetheless. It seems that Lisle saw each of them within one hour on the same summer afternoon. Lisa she recognized because she was Javier's wife's lover, the girl she knew from the news story about the drowning. A forlorn creature at the edge of the frame of the news footage, bone white and gawky and clearly hysterical, alternately looking up to scream and then crying into her hands. It was excruciating to see, the kind of thing television news specializes in, and it made Lisle so distraught that she drove down the creek road to the boat launch as if the girl would still be there, hours after the newscast. She wasn't of course, though she was the following day and the day after, vacant and silently sitting on a bleached white log. Lisle never went back after that but then saw them the same day within an hour, Lisa moved across the marble floor of the post office in rubber flip-flops and a long wrapped skirt of polynesian cotton, a lavalava, so sensuous as she walked you had to watch.

        The girl was on Main Street in the village, hurrying somewhere along the sun-baked sidewalk, bone white in the glare, vacant, silent, and, although she hurried somewhere, unalterably lost.

        Each curving ever so gently.


        To Lisle they seemed like old friends, twin silences, and she wished (absurdly) that she could have embraced them.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl8_8.html">
        .
        .
        .
        .
        .
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl8_9.html">
        In November she had the strangest dream in which Samantha and Javier's daughter were sleeping in the nude together and embracing, face to face, innocent as lovers. The dream was all in swirls of blue like housepaint when you first open it or like the swirly art they used to sell to rubes along the midway.

        "What are you doing?" she asked Samantha, who rose from the swirl like a swimmer surfacing in a dream but who somehow didn't leave the embrace of her sleeping sister.

        That was how she thought of her in the dream, a sister.

        "Can't you see I'm in cyberspace," Samantha protested. Her voice was annoying and annoyed.

        "Don't be absurd," Lisle said. "I've been to cyberspace. No one sleeps there. It's all August and autumn rushing in and back to school."

        And still they floated on, the girls, not ignoring her but somehow knowing otherwise.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl8_10.html">
        Most of the girls had to go home before nightfall which was still fairly late then in Ontario in August. But for those who could stay the whirly ride was wonderful with its arm of strung lights in bright colors. The music from the record player seemed both distant and near in the summer night, like a dream and a memory at once.

        The girls who remained rode dreamily, taking interest in the ride again under these new circumstances. Delores' father adjusted the rheostat which controlled the speed of the cars so that they circled lazily and the hum of the wheels softened to a low buzz like locusts. The ice in the washtub had melted to a dark pool and white moths caught themselves on its surface struggling against wet wings.

        As the parents of Delores' friends came to pick up their girls, they would mostly stand there for awhile watching the spider arms of light go round and flash against the chestnut tree, the barn, and their own faces. Her father nodded silently from where he stood by the upright brake, forgoing his seat at the folding stool, keeping watch over the ride in the night. He waved to the girls and their parents as they left.

        Finally when everyone was gone, he invited Delores and her mother to ride again at three o'clock and nine. This time they seemed to spin like people holding hands, not chasing each other at all.

        <prolepsis>Her mother did not know what eventually happened to the ride. She seemed to think that Delores Peters' father had rented it out once or twice to a church fair or a volunteer firemen's picnic over the years. She also felt certain that he pulled it out from the barn and set it up near the chestnut tree from time to time again, one time even when they were teens and rode the whirly wheel ironically with their boyfriends, cramped one to a car. Her mother also wasn't sure what had happened to Delores Peters exactly. She knew Delores had married unhappily but then remarried happily. She also knew Delores' father died before her mother, who in fact she thought might be living still in Ontario since farm wives tended to be hardy.</prolepsis>

        ...
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl8_11.html">
        .
        .
        .

        Everything can be read, every surface and silence, every breath and every vacancy, every eddy and current, every body and its absence, every darkness every light, each cloud and knife, each finger and tree, every backwater, every crevice and hollow, each nostril, tendril and crescent, every whisper, every whimper, each laugh and every blue feather, each stone, each nipple, every thread every color, each woman and her lover, every man and his mother, every river, each of the twelve blue oceans and the moon, every forlorn link, every hope and every ending, each coincidence, the distant call of a loon, light through the high branches of blue pines, the sigh of rain, every estuary, each gesture at parting, every kiss, each wasp's wing, every foghorn and railway whistle, every shadow, every gasp, each glowing silver screen, every web, the smear of starlight, a fingertip, rose whorl, armpit, pearl, every delight and misgiving, every unadorned wish, every daughter, every death, each woven thing, each machine, every ever after

        ...
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/1/works/joyce__twelve_blue/sl8_12.html">
        Samantha had this crazy thought that wasn't anything really except a very weird kind of lonesome nostalgia for her childhood coupled with a completely irrational idea. She was smart enough to know it was a kind of shock, like a dream, how the mind tries to hold onto what it cannot understand.

        A little before Thanksgiving she found herself thinking of having a tea party and inviting Javier's daughter, the girl whose boyfriend drowned in the creek, and maybe one or two other females. Though she wasn't sleeping she could see it and it was more like a dim memory of some birthday party than a girls's tea party because all the girls were little and wore white dresses with crinolines and ribbons at the waist. Even as she thought of this stuff she knew how stupid and hallucinatory it was and it made her laugh a little inside though she also found herself wanting to cry.

        She could also see the tea cups. They were these strange tin cups and saucers and a teapot her mother had as a girl in Canada and which Samantha had seen only in family photographs. Each saucer had a rolled rim where the tin was crimped to keep from cutting you, each cup also. There was a pattern of blue flowers on the rim of the saucers and the side of the cup.

        She asked mother the name of the flowers and, then because she had asked such a strange question she felt she might as well tell her what she dreamed in her delirium.

        "You could do it, you know, though probably not with those people," her mother said. "When I was growing up women had teas for all sorts of reasons. Not tea parties exactly, but teas. They calmed things that way."

        You could never really tell what Lisle would say, she was so strange. To Samantha it felt like more of the delirium, like when you get away from someone in a dream and wake from one dream into another...
    </div>

</text>
