<text>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party1.html">
<analepsis>I drank too much red wine.</analepsis>
The Broadthrow's party is looping in my mind,
nested with brief dreams and nightmares.

<analepsis>I dreamed that Jeff and I were in bed.
He was running his hands up and down my body.
He put his tongue in my mouth. His hands were on my breasts.
He ran his fingers down the inside of my thighs.
We made love.

In the morning, he wanted a cheese omlette,
but there was no cheese in the refrigerator.</analepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party2.html">
<analepsis>When the party began, the plastic cover
was removed from the white couch.
Mrs Broadthrow was wearing a lime green silk suit
that I had just picked up for her at the cleaners.
Her blouse was white silk with a plunging neckline. Gold earrings
framed her finely chiseled face.</analepsis>
Her name is Louise.
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party3.html">
It's September in Woodside, California
where I've been for two weeks with the Broadthrow family.
They say that strange cloying smell
is Eucalyptus.

I'm the live-in babysitter for Caroline Broadthrow.

My name is Jenny.
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party4.html">
My room at the house in Woodside is in the back of the garage
where Tom and Louise keep their two Mercedes.
It is a small room, wallpapered with peeling seascapes.
A window looks out on an area of sagebrush and brown grass
where <analepsis>two nights ago, I looked out and saw Uncle Roger.
Together under a full moon, he and a woman I had never seen before
were looking at a floor plan of the Broadthrow's home.
I heard him whisper loudly: "It is a warm California evening.
Let us take off our clothes and make love on the ground."</analepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party5.html">
<analepsis>I remembered a round tray of buffalo chicken wings
on a marble coffee table, beside a silver candle holder bearing pink candles.
Uncle Roger eating chicken wings, one after another,
putting the bones in a small pile
beside coffee table books about Michelangelo and Rembrandt.</analepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party6.html">
<analepsis>Louise buying olives at a Greek Delicatessen.
The man behind the counter couldn't take his eyes off her.
The perfectly waved blond hair,
the deep glance from her brown eyes
- like an unexpected thaw in early spring
exposing bare but promising earth.</analepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party7.html">
<prolepsis>I dreamed I lived with Louise
on a long boat-like dock in the harbor.
The place was called Trinnywind
or Tinnywild or something like that.
It was on the Eastern Seacoast
(because the view to the water wasn't reversed
the way it seemed on Western beaches).</prolepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party8.html">
<prolepsis>We all went out to lunch in Trinnywind.
Louise seated us at a dining table with chairs between us.
I was opposite a girl with short, neat brown hair
and a small white coller on her red plaid dress.
She didn't talk to me. I didn't talk to her.</prolepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party9.html">
<prolepsis>In the dream, I walked around the town of Trinnywind.
I had never seen it before.
There was a long straight street through the center of the town.
Like a scene of the canals in Amsterdam,
black brick buildings with crenelated facades
were situated close together on either side of the street.
In front of the main building was a small square black fountain.
The buildings had large glass windows,
like a row of black mirrors all along the street.</prolepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party10.html">
<prolepsis>There is a funny feeling in my stomach,
and I can't erase Jeff's image. It hovers over my bed</prolepsis>
<analepsis>like the image of God when I said the prayer
that began "Heavenly father hear my prayer, keep me in your loving care"
and lay in bed in the house in Massachusets.

God was a sort of long, dark man
who hovered horizontally over me
and had no face.</analepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party11.html">
<prolepsis>Uncle Roger usually wears tweed suits which look
as if he has had them for a long time.
He is short and plump,</prolepsis> <analepsis>and when I was younger,
I thought that his briefcase was glued to his right hand.
Because one day when we picked him up at the station,
he said to my Mother: "Given that I live on the train,
I wish that they would serve martinis,"
I also thought
that he lived on the Boston &amp; Maine.</analepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party12.html">
<prolepsis>One evening in California, Uncle Roger invited me to his home.
We sat in the living room; the walls were painted tan
and there were requests for funding for unusual inventions
in piles on the tables.
He took a long, white package out of his pocket.</prolepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party13.html">
<prolepsis>The party was about to begin.
In a pink dress with pearl buttons and roses embroidered on the hem,
Caroline was sitting on the white couch. She was drinking gingerale
and crumbling a small cocktail napkin into her lap.</prolepsis>
<analepsis>("Carnitas with extra sour cream and guacamole.
"Would you like a bite?" Uncle Roger had asked)</analepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party14.html">
<prolepsis>I wore my grey skirt with the wide waist band,
that makes my waist look smaller than it really is,
and a blue silk shirt that makes my eyes look devastatingly blue.
<analepsis>I had given myself a bad haircut.</analepsis></prolepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party15.html">
<prolepsis><analepsis>I had put some perfume on under my breasts.</analepsis>
My shoes were silver flats; my socks were the blue of my shirt.

Mark, who was 16, was in the bathroom with the door open.
looking at himself in the mirror.

He asked me to come in and help him with his tie.</prolepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party16.html">
<prolepsis>The doorbell was ringing. Guests were arriving.
Tom Broadthrow was standing by the front door,
dressed casually, as usual, in white pants and a blue and tan checked shirt.

Caroline's cat Puffy jumped up on the table
and licked a long salmon and cream cheese roll.
I picked her up. She put her tail in the clam dip.
No one noticed.</prolepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party17.html">
<prolepsis>
In this dream, I was on a pullman train with Jeff.
It was like <analepsis>the train I took to Washington, DC with my Mother and Aunt Sally
when I was in Junior High.</analepsis>
Jeff and I were in the top bunk.
I put my hands on his body. It was dark,
and the train rocked gently on the tracks
as it moved swiftly along towards San Francisco.
</prolepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party18.html">
<prolepsis>I dreamed that Jeff and I were standing in a shallow pool.
The water came up to our waists.
Along the edges of the pool were blue green tiles
with handpainted pictures of birds and fish and flowers.
Jeff was holding a multicolored beachball in his hands.
I was wearing an old blue bathing suit that was a little too small for me.</prolepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party19.html">
<prolepsis>
The Broadthrows own three houses - one here in Woodside,
half an hours commute to BroadthrowMicro;
one in Massachusetts, near Broadthrow headquarters;
and "The Cottage" in New Hampshire, near BroadVentures.
The Cottage has six bedrooms.

The Woodside house sprawls sideways over a hilly wooded corner lot.
It is painted a powdery, paint sample brown.
Many balconies stick out from the structure.
Inside, the floors are covered by dense blue grey carpets,
and all the walls are painted pale pink.
</prolepsis>
</div>

<div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party20.html">
<analepsis>The Broadthrows spent the summer at the cottage in New Hampshire.
I started working for them in August when Louise was in Paris
and Tom was in Huntsville
and Leslie, my predecessor, went unexpectedly to Mexico
with the lifeguard at the lake.</analepsis>
</div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party21.html">
        <prolepsis>Tom Broadthrow was in Colorado Springs when Jeff Gallagher picked us up
        -- Louise, Caroline, Mark, and me --
        at the San Francisco airport two weeks ago.
        Louise did not introduce me.
        I reached for the back door handle.
        Jeff's hand was there first.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party22.html">
       <prolepsis>He is about 6'2". Brown hair. Boyish smile.
        There is a sort of glow or halo about his head,
        and when my hand touched his on the car door,
        there was a wild reaction in my body
        that I cannot explain.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party23.html">
        <prolepsis>On the table was a large glass tray heaped with olives
        -- green olives in the center, ringed with black olives, all sprinkled with parsley.
        Beside me, a man and a woman were talking.
        He said: "I don't want a blue rug in our house. I want a grey rug."

        I put some olives on my plate.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party24.html">
        <prolepsis>Mark was sitting on the couch with a plate of cheese balls in his lap.
        Beside him, drinking white wine from a fluted plastic glass,
        was a blond with green eyes. Short streaked hair in an elfin cut.
        She was wearing a gold skirt with turquoise images of dancers
        in a style of the fifties.
        Shiny pink plastic shoes on her feet.
        Mark's English teacher, Miss G.....</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party25.html">
        <prolepsis>"I read about you in Mark's diary," she said.
        "But of course I cannot tell you what he wrote."
        There was an expression on her face
        that I could not decipher.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party26.html">
        <prolepsis>I dreamed that Jeff and I were lying on the sand
        beside the water on a small island in Trinnywind harbor.
        I had taken off my bathingsuit and was lying on my stomach.
        Jeff was rubbing suntan lotion on my back
        and down the backs of my thighs.</prolepsis>

        <analepsis>"Do you know Jeff Gasllsgher?" I asked Jane at the party.

        "A nice solid guy," said Jane. "Have you heard anything
        from David? she asked, looking at me seriously
        over the tops of her glasses.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party27.html">
        <prolepsis>On a glass table were white plates loaded with warm mushroom sandwiches,
        bottles of red and white wine,
        stacks of plastic glasses.

        Three men in tan suits were standing over the table,
        eating mushroom sandwiches and talking.
        I poured myself a glass of red wine.
        "250 gigahearts," said one of the men.
        At least that's what I think he said.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party28.html">
        <prolepsis>"I hear Broadthrow is hiring,"
        said the man with iridescent green flecks in his tan suit.

        "Yeah, and it looks like he's settling his family in for at least a year."

        "I'd like to settle in to her,"
        The man with the pink striped shirt beneath his tan suitjacket smiled at Louise.
        She was putting rippled potato chips into a crystal bowl with a silver rim.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party29.html">
        <prolepsis>I poured some more red wine into my plastic glass.
        I lingered over the mushroom sandwiches
        and the salmon roll that Puffy had licked.

        The men in tan suits had lowered their voices.
        I reached for a mushroom sandwich.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party30.html">
        <prolepsis>In the dream, I went back to the long boat in Trinnywind harbor.
        I went below. Louise was there with a bag full of tacos.
        I looked out the window and saw a sign that said: "GIANT SANDWICHES".</prolepsis>

        <prolepsis>(Louise does not eat tacos from a bag. It was a dream.
        I am only writing what happened in the dream.)</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party31.html">
        <analepsis>The sun was shining on some small islands
        in Trinnywind harbor. The water was very blue.
        My brother and I got into a rowboat and rowed out to a little island.

        There was one tree on the island. My brother
        had brought some bread and cheese and red wine,
        and we sat on the warm sand and ate lunch.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party32.html">
        <analepsis>I was eating a mushroom sandwich,
        when I heard a noise from the large window beside the Broadthrow's front door.
        Puffy was sitting on the windowsill, looking out the window and meowing.
        There was a man outside the window, looking in.
        It was Uncle Roger.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party33.html">
        <prolepsis>Louise let Uncle Roger in.
        Uncle Roger is vice president of a brokerage firm, Clark and Clark.
        He's a semiconductor industry analyist.
        He might even have been invited.

        "Why Roger, I thought you were in New York.
        What a nice tie," said Louise.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party34.html">
        <prolepsis>My Grandfather Grandy is the other Clark in Clark and Clark.
        Grandy speaks Latin fluently
        and remembers things about the Greek and Persian Wars
        that I have already forgotten even though I majored in history.
        He asks me questions like "Would you like to discuss
        Spartan naval strategies?"

        Uncle Roger asks questions like
        "Do you know the name of that woman in the red dress
        who isn't wearing a bra?"</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party35.html">
        <prolepsis>Uncle Roger was coming towards me.
        He was wearing a bright red wool tie that Aunt Sally had knitted last Christmas.

        I opened my mouth.
        Uncle Roger put his finger to his lips and brushed past me,
        pressing a note into my hand as he passed.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party36.html">
        <prolepsis>The note Uncle Roger handed me said,
        "Pretend you don't know me."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party37.html">
        <prolepsis>Tom Broadthrow said, "Roger Clark! Great of you to come!"
        Then he saw me. I was eating potato chips.
        I had just stuffed Uncle Roger's note into my skirt pocket.
        "Our babysitter must be a distant relative of yours - Jenny Clark."

        "How do you do, Miss Clark," said Uncle Roger.

        The doorbell rang again.
        Tom left us standing over the tray of salmon cream cheese loaf and sour dough bread
        that Puffy had licked.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party38.html">
        <prolepsis>"Destroy that note," said Uncle Roger quietly.
        His breath smelled of Kentucky Fried Chicken.

        "What are you up to?" I asked.

        "I'm going to Haiti tomorrow," he whispered.
        "I'll call you when I get back."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party39.html">
        <prolepsis>He ate about 1/4 of the salmon cream cheese loaf,
        from the end that Puffy hadn't licked.
        "Where is the bathroom?" he asked.

        "There are three upstairs," I said.
        "The one that adjoins Tom and Louise's bedroom
        is closest to the top of the stairs."

        "Thank you", said Uncle Roger.
        He put a large chunk of sourdough baguette into his pocket
        and headed upstairs, whispering "Be careful, Jenny,
        this is a dangerous household."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party40.html">
        <prolepsis>I filled up my plastic glass with red wine.
        The men in the tan suits were still talking.

        "I hate all that togetherness shit,"
        said the one with the pink striped shirt.
        As he reached for a mushroom sandwich, his hand collided with my hand.
        "Hi there," he said. "My name is ......" </prolepsis>
        <prolepsis>(I can't remember what it was.)</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party41.html">
        <analepsis>Jack and Jane had arrived.
        By the bar that separates the kitchen from the dining room,
        and was covered for the party with potato chips and bottles of booze
        Louise was pouring Jack a drink.

        Jane was sitting beside Caroline on the white couch,
        wearing a plain navy blue cotton shirtdress and small silver earrings.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party42.html">
        <prolepsis>Louise was standing too close to Jack,
        who</prolepsis> <analepsis>just came out from Massachusetts to manage BroadthrowMicro.</analepsis>
        <prolepsis>Tom joined them.

        Jack is originally from Texas.
        He looks like Elvis Presley might had looked if he had played a lot of football
        and worn Brooks Brothers shirts.
        I got a plate of cheese balls.

        "The yield is down. I think we've lost the process," said Jack.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party43.html">
        <prolepsis>I pictured a whole line of men in tan suits
        scampering around on a stage, singing
        "The yield is down. I think we lost the process."
        The chorus was "We lost it in the submicron area,"
        which is what Jack said next.

        I ate some cheeseballs.

        "Call Dennis and tell him to get out here right away," said Tom.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party44.html">
        <prolepsis>Uncle Roger went out the front door.
        He had a bottle of vodka tucked under his arm.
        His pockets were bulging.
        He had forgotten to zip up his fly.

        "Good kitty," he said to Puffy as he left.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party45.html">
        <prolepsis>Puffy usually sleeps here with me,
        or on the top of Tom's white Mercedes.
        She is lying on my pillow now, licking her fur
        and purring loudly in my ear.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party46.html">
        <analepsis>I sat down beside Caroline and Jane.
        Caroline's napkin was on her pink lap in small pieces.
        I noticed a grease spot on my skirt.
        When I looked up, Louise was standing over us.
        "Come on, Caroline," she said. "There are some people I'd like you to meet."
        Caroline got up, scattering paper napkin on the thick rug.

        "That old man said something wierd to me," she whispered.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party47.html">
        <analepsis>I had supper last week with Jack and Jane.
        Jack showed me around their new home in Sunnyvale.
        Pink stucco arched doorways opened into gold wall to wall carpeting.
        And on the walls there were electron microscope photographs.

        It was a sunny California evening, and the front yard
        was landscaped with cacti and rocks.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party48.html">
        <prolepsis>While we were eating dinner,
        Jack talked about their neighbors' motorboat.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party49.html">
        <prolepsis>I moved a little closer to Jane on the white couch.

        From Massachsetts, near where I grew up,
        she has long brown hair, brown eyes, round glasses,
        and a calm, pleasant face.</prolepsis>
        <analepsis>She met Jack while she was working in a lab on route 128 in Boston.</analepsis>
        <prolepsis>(I don't know why they fell in love.)</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party50.html">
        <prolepsis>The den in Jack and Jane's house was panelled with brown plastic wood
        and on the mantel there was a photograph of Jack and the Secretary of Defense.
        "Did you have a good time on your neighbors' boat?" I asked Jane at the party.
        Jane didn't answer.
        She was looking at the table where the salmon loaf was situated.
        Jack was talking to a women in a red patterned silk dress.
        They were sharing cheese balls and stuffed cherry tomatoes.
        As she reached for a cheese ball,
        her hand touched his.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party51.html">
        <prolepsis>I dreamed that Jeff and I were at a party on a cruise ship.
        Rows of glasses shone in the sun on the shelves of the ship's mahogany bar.
        I was disguised as a cigarette girl.
        When I went to the bathroom, the Secretary of Defense was there.
        He helped himself to a cigarette.
        I was wearing a shiny green bathing suit.</prolepsis>

        <analepsis>"Do you know Jeff Gallagher?" I asked Jane
        at the party.

        "A nice, solid guy," said Jane.
        "Have you heard anything from David?" she asked,
        looking at me seriously over the tops of her glasses.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party52.html">
        <prolepsis>The woman who sat down on the couch beside Jane
        was tall - at least 6 feet, squeezed into tight jeans
        and a yellow fringed cowboy shirt with pearl buttons.

        "Hi Jane," she said.
        "I see that bitch Rose has got her hand on your husband's crotch
        again."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party53.html">
        <prolepsis>"I'm Dorrie - Jack's right hand at BroadthrowMicro.
        That's Rose, his secretary."
        She pointed to the woman in the red dress, who was eating cheese balls
        and looking into Jack's eyes.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party54.html">
        <prolepsis>Jane introduced me.
        "You mean you work for both of them?"
        Dorrie's laugh carried across the room.
        The men in tan suits stopped talking and stared at her.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party55.html">
        <prolepsis>In the dream, the bathroom had turned to a tropical garden.
        I was surrounded by tall plants.
        A chorus line of women in red dresses were dancing
        for the Secretary of Defense.

        The waiter serving drinks looked vaguely familiar.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party56.html">
        <analepsis>"There are many stories in the Valley," said Dorrie.

        She was easy to listen to. Jane and I sat quietly.

        "Some are fairy tales, but there are nightmares.
        Look into the nightmares and you'll see Tom Broadthrow's name
        every other page."

        I looked at Tom. He has a slight build, sandy hair and a pleasant smile.
        "Why do you work for him?"

        "Someone has to protect the girls on the line."</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party57.html">
        <prolepsis>She rolled up her right sleeve,
        flexed some impressive muscles, and said,
        eying a husky male whose open shirt revealed
        a commemorative Xerox PARC medallion,
        "I don't know about you girls, but I'm horny."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party58.html">
        <prolepsis>"Look at the size of his hands," said Dorrie.
        "My mother always said to look for big thumbs."

        "Big thumbs? I don't understand."

        "If a man has big thumbs,
        he probably has a big..........." said Dorrie.
        To illustrate what she meant,
        She made a sliding in and out gesture with her hands

        "I have to go to the bathroom," said Jane.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party59.html">
        <prolepsis>I was watching the door when Jeff came in.
        He saw me sitting on the couch,
        hiding the spot on my skirt with a plate full of cheese balls.

        He smiled at me.

        A warm flush spread slowly over my face.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party60.html">
        <prolepsis>Jeff sat down beside me on the couch.
        "Hello, Jenny," he said, "How do you like California?"

        He had stray gray hairs in his thick brown hair
        and big sloping shoulders.
        I wanted to unbutton his shirt and kiss his stomach.

        "I don't know," I said.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party61.html">
        <prolepsis>Puffy jumped into Jeff's lap.
        We both patted her, and she purred happily.
        He asked me why I had taken this job.
        I told him that I wasn't sure what I wanted to do yet.
        This job was giving me a chance to do some thinking,
        to see another part of the country.
        I didn't mention that</prolepsis> <analepsis>David had decided we shouldn't see each other for a while.</analepsis>

        <prolepsis>Puffy licked the cheese balls on the plate on my lap.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party62.html">
        <prolepsis>Jeff said</prolepsis> <analepsis>he had been born in San Jose and had lived there all his life.</analepsis>
        <prolepsis>He told me that he had a small company,
        but they weren't doing very well.
        He said</prolepsis> <analepsis>he had designed a custom chip</analepsis> <prolepsis>which he thought was "pretty hot",
        but they didn't have the money to produce it.</prolepsis>
        <analepsis>He had tried to get money,</analepsis> <prolepsis>but times weren't very good right now.
        He said</prolepsis> <analepsis>Tom Broadthrow's venture capital company had been interested,
        but Tom had decided that the chip wouldn't be practical to produce.</analepsis>

        <prolepsis>"I don't know why I'm telling you all this.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party63.html">
        <prolepsis>Jeff kept talking about custom chips.
        He got very excited.
        I looked into his eyes which are brown.
        I wanted him to keep talking.

        "What is a custom chip?" I asked.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party64.html">
        <prolepsis>Tom came over with a couple of bottles of beer in his hand.
        "Good to see you, Jeff. How about a beer?"

        Puffy jumped off Jeff's lap and ran under the couch.
        Jeff took both beers and handed me one.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party65.html">
        <prolepsis>Jeff kept on talking about semiconductors.
        I lost track of time.

        "Jenny, it's time for you to read Caroline her story,"
        Suddenly Louise who was hovering over us.
        "Why hello, Jeff.
        There's some people I'd like you to meet."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party66.html">
        <prolepsis>Caroline was sitting on a silver chair
        staring at a painting of her father's first company
        on the far wall.

        As we headed up the stairs, Louise called after us:
        "Jenny dear, you don't need to come back to the party."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party67.html">
        <prolepsis>I read Caroline the chapter of Pride and Prejudice where Darcy
        refuses to dance with Elizabeth.
        Then I went back to the party to say goodnight.
        As I walked into the room, Jeff and a woman who teaches at Stanford
        were talking over the salmon roll.
        She was wearing a velvet suit with a long skirt and a dark purple blouse.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party68.html">
        <prolepsis>She was talking to Jeff, smiling into his eyes.
        "Next Saturday. I'll be looking forward to it,"
        she said, slicing off the end of the salmon roll
        that</prolepsis> <analepsis>Puffy had licked.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party69.html">
        <prolepsis>Jane said she would like to see my room.
        We walked through the garage, past the two Mercedes,
        and into my little room.

        "Isn't there an extra bedroom in the house?" she asked.

        I had some sherry and a couple of glasses.
        I poured us some.
        "I wish we were back home in Boston," she said.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party70.html">
        <prolepsis>The swimming pool in my dream
        was surrounded by an ivy covered fence and large maple trees.
        The grass was bright yellow-green.
        Jeff tossed me the beach ball.
        I dropped it.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party71.html">
        <analepsis>On the bureau in his residence, Uncle Roger has a ceramic egg
        with round eyes and a big smile painted on it.
        The egg is sitting in a little basket full of yellow straw.
        A small piece of paper about the size of a fortune cookie fortune
        is stuck in the straw. It says,
        "You'd be happy too, if you'd just been laid."</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party72.html">
        <prolepsis>I wish I had some alka seltzer</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party73.html">
        <analepsis>I dreamed that Jeff and I were lying on the sand
        beside the water on a small island in Trinnywind
        Harbor. I had taken off my bathingsuit and
        was lying on my stomach. Jeff was rubbing suntan
        oil on my back and down the sides of my thighs.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/party74.html">
        <prolepsis>I dreamed I was in Venice, Italy.
        I got a letter from Tom saying he was passing through Venice
        and he wanted to see me.

        I met him in the lobby of my hotel. He said
        "Hello, Jenny," but he wasn't Tom. He was tall
        and thin with black curly , greasy hair, and he
        didn't look anything like Tom. We got into a
        gondola. He was talking away as if he were Tom.
        I didn't know what to say. When we got out of the
        gondola, I said, "I'm sorry to have to say this,
        but you're not Tom."

        He said, "Yes I am."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <!-- File 2 begins here -->
    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue1.html">
        I was down at the end of the last table.
        There was no one to my right and no one
        across from me.

        It was Tom's birthday. He was at the head of the
        table. Louise was sitting at his right. We were
        sitting at four tables pushed together in a
        restaurant in a hotel just off the highway that
        runs down the East side of the South Bay.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue2.html">
        <prolepsis>The ceiling of the restaurant was painted with
        dancing women. They wore purple and yellow
        outfits, trays of painted fruit on their heads.
        Strings of tiny Christmas tree lights were
        stuck among the fruit.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue3.html">
        <prolepsis>At the second table, Jack and Rose sat together.
        A white jersey dress clung to her thighs.
        Dorrie sat across from Rose.
        The perfume Rose was wearing smelled like my
        grandmother's back yard on an unseasonably
        hot day in late spring.

        Sitting next to Dorrie and across from Jack
        was Uncle Roger.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue4.html">
        <prolepsis>Three men in tan suits and Dennis, who wears his
        hair in a long ponytail and is out here
        from Albuqueque because of some crisis
        at BroadthrowMicro, sat at the third table.

        Uncle Roger was still pretending that he didn't
        know me. He had on a tweed suit and a tie with
        little pink hula dancers on it. Everytime he got
        up to go to the buffet, he looked down
        Louise's dress.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue5.html">
        <prolepsis>We were eating lunch.

        Heart shaped silver and red balloons were
        tied behind Tom's chair. There was a platter
        of curly fried potatoes and a small pile of presents
        in front of him.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue6.html">
        <prolepsis>Louise was putting her fork
        into a pale jello salad with cherries in it.

        "I've been to Hawaii. I got laid," said
        Uncle Roger loudly.

        He didn't look very tan.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue7.html">
        <prolepsis>"Cute lifeguards with big muscles," he said inexplicably
        to Tom's lawyer Mr. Draper,who was staring furtively at Jack's arms.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue8.html">
        <prolepsis>The restaurant was separated from the hotel lobby
        by low green marble planters filled with plants
        with big shiny dark green leaves.
        There was a pink and green patterned rug on the floor.
        Through the leaves of the plants,
        square cream-colored marble columns were visible in the lobby
        A woman in a long red dress was playing the piano.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue9.html">
        <prolepsis>Louise took one of Tom's presents from the pile.
        "To Tom from everybody at BroadthrowMicro."
        It was a flat rectangular package
        wrapped in flowered paper and lime green stick-on bows.

        Dennis was talking to the men in tan suits,
        picking the shrimp out of his rice and
        putting them in a neat pile on the edge of
        his plate as he talked. "It's probably a photograph of Henry Kissenger,"
        he said.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue10.html">
        <analepsis>A week ago, I was sitting at a small sticky table
        outside a cafe, in San Jose.
        It was my day off, and I was writing in the blue notebook.
        It was a gray, overcast day,
        not quite warm enough to be sitting outside.
        The coffee was good. There was a jelly doughnut
        on a paper plate in front of me.

        I was writing about <analepsis>a trip I took last year with David.</analepsis></analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue11.html">
        <prolepsis>The things I wrote in the blue notebook
        didn't happen in exactly the way I wrote them.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue12.html">
        <analepsis>David's apartment was one room
        with a bathroom on one side and a very small kitchen
        on the other side.

        The floor of his apartment was covered with dirty
        clothes and empty food wrappers.
        Photos of people's picnics, weddings, and vacations
        were tacked all over the walls. David worked in
        a 24 hour photo processing store, and he took
        home the pictures that he liked.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue13.html">
        <prolepsis>I put on cut off dungarees and a sleeveless
        blue shirt. Sally rubbed against my legs.

        David had built a castle of catfood cans on the kitchen floor.
        I opened a can and gave her some.

        He was standing by the window
        pulling on his pants. It was a Monday morning
        in the middle of July, and he was already late
        for work.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue14.html">
        <prolepsis>I peeled an orange and went to the window.
        We were standing by the window, eating pieces of the orange,
        when we looked out and saw the blimp over the Square.
        It was a large, silver blimp with no writing on it.

        Attached to the bottom of the blimp,
        was a huge photograph of Henry Kissinger.

        "I think we should go to the lake," said David.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue15.html">
        <prolepsis>I put some things that were in David's
        refrigerator in a plastic bag. We put the
        plastic bag, some clothes that were on the floor,
        David's sleeping bag, his camera, and Sally
        into his old black Buick. The only door
        that opened was on the passenger side because
        a steam roller had run into the driver's side.

        We got into the car and started driving.
        We were headed for a place up North
        where David kept his boat.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue16.html">
        <prolepsis>"Do you have any money?" he asked.

        "Only about $5.00 ," I said.

        He reached in his back pocket,
        pulled out his wallet, and handed it to me.
        "See if I've got any," he said.

        David had over $50.00 in his wallet.
        In a side pocket was a picture of Linda.
        I took it out and looked at it. She was
        wearing a white sun dress, and her long red hair was blowing around her face.
        David was looking at the road.
        I tore the picture into little pieces and
        put it back in the pocket of his wallet.
        "You have about $50.00," I said.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue17.html">
        <prolepsis>We had left the highway and were driving
        along the edge of a steep rocky hill.
        Houses with back porches protruding out over the rocks
        were built into the hillside.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue18.html">
        <prolepsis>There wasn't much traffic on the road.
        "Maybe no one else saw it," I said.
        It was hot in the car. I rolled down my window.
        "It probably wasn't Henry Kissinger," said David.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue19.html">
        <prolepsis>The houses on the hillside were made of gray weathered shingles.
        Sally ran down the hill. I got out of the car
        and ran after her, but she was very fast.
        She was a small calico cat
        and hard to see among the rocks.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue20.html">
        <prolepsis>Three women were standing over a silver bucket
        on a back porch above the rocks where Sally
        was sitting. They shouted at each other
        in a language which wasn't English. One women
        reached into the bucket, pulled out a dead fish
        and threw it down the hill. It went into a hole
        between three rocks. Sally went after it, and I
        caught her with the fish in her mouth.

        David was leaning against the car
        watching.

        I put Sally in the back seat of the car with the
        fish still in her mouth. It was a flat scaly
        fish - about eight inches long. David said to
        let her keep it.
        She lay down on his sleeping bag.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue21.html">
        <prolepsis>We were outside the town where David's parents
        had their summer house. David's father
        was a consultant in a military think tank.
        David's mother liked to talk about laundry.
        I was getting nervous.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue22.html">
        <prolepsis>The cafe in San Jose faced a parking lot.
        All around, the streets were torn up. The cafe was an oasis
        in piles of dirt, stripped barriers, and plank walkways over excavations.

        It was cold.
        I stopped writing and finished the coffee.
        There was some powdered sugar on my sweater. I brushed it off.

        "Jenny."

        I looked up. Jeff was standing there
        with a plastic tray in his hands.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue23.html">
        <prolepsis>I put the blue notebook in my pocketbook.

        He set a styrofoam cup full of coffee and an oblong doughnut
        on the table and sat down.
        "I wanted to call you."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue24.html">
        <prolepsis>It had been two weeks since</prolepsis> <analepsis>the party in Woodside.
        Every time the phone rang, I had hoped it would be Jeff.</analepsis>

        <prolepsis>He said: "My business with Broadthrow is going badly.
        "I didn't want to call you there."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue25.html">
        <prolepsis>Jeff told me that he grew up in San Jose
        where his father owned a gas station.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue26.html">
        <prolepsis>"And it turned out he hadn't backed up any of it,"
        said a man in a tan suit and a thin blue tie
        with gold stripes on it.

        Tom untied the ribbon on the present
        "from everybody at Broadthrowmicro".
        "Did you pick this out?" he asked Dorrie.

        Dennis said something softly to Dorrie.
        She knocked over a double marguarita with her elbow.

        "Rose picked it out, " said Jack.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue27.html">
        <prolepsis>A waiter mopped up the area in front of Dorrie
        with an unwieldy pink linen napkin.

        Uncle Roger pushed his chair out from the table.
        On his lap was a marguarita soaked magazine.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue28.html">
        <analepsis>Uncle Roger and Grandy were both born in April.
        Every year they had a birthday party together where
        we all sat around a big table wearing
        pointed silver hats. Uncle Roger
        did his imitation of a German U-boat commander,
        and he and Grandy gave out small presents
        such as fake dog throw up or
        boxes containing naked plastic women.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue29.html">
        <prolepsis>Louise took one of Tom's presents from the pile.
        "To Tom from everybody at BroadthrowMicro."
        It was a flat rectangular package
        wrapped in flowered paper and lime green stick-on bows.

        Dennis was talking to the men in tan suits,
        picking the shrimp out of his rice and
        putting them in a neat pile on the edge of
        his plate as he talked. "It's probably a photograph of Henry Kissenger,"
        he said.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue30.html">
        <prolepsis>The desk stand moved slowly around the table
        for inspection
        until it got to Uncle Roger.

        He stood it beside his plate.
        "Excuse me ," he said
        getting up from the table.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue31.html">
        <analepsis>Louise took one of Tom's presents from the pile.
        "To Tom from everybody at BroadthrowMicro."
        It was a flat rectangular package
        wrapped in flowered paper and lime green stick-on bows.

        Dennis was talking to the men in tan suits,
        picking the shrimp out of his rice and
        putting them in a neat pile on the edge of
        his plate as he talked. "It's probably a photograph of Henry Kissenger,"
        he said.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue32.html">
        <prolepsis>I needed to go to the bathroom.
        I followed green and pink carpeted corridors,
        opened the door to the ladies room.

        Inside, the walls were distressed pink, and the tiles on the floor
        were the color of mountain stone.
        Uncle Roger was lying on the couch
        drinking a margarita.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue33.html">
        <prolepsis>"This is the ladies room, Uncle Roger, " I said.

        "I know. I've been waiting to talk with you."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue34.html">
        <prolepsis>There was no one in the ladies room except
        Uncle Roger and me.
        Uncle Roger finished his magarita.
        He set the empty glass on a chrome shelf
        under the green marble bordered mirror.

        He said: "Your father asked me to watch over you."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue35.html">
        <prolepsis>"No he didn't," I said. I went to the sink and
        removed the pink paper from a bar of hotel soap.

        "I paid for your college tuition," Uncle Roger said,
        patting me on the shoulder.

        "Mom paid for college, " I said.

        "Yes, but I gave her the money."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue36.html">
        <prolepsis>I dropped the soap.
        It clattered loadly on the tiled floor.

        "I want to talk with you about Jeff Gallagher and Tom Broadthrow,"
        Uncle Roger said.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue37.html">
        <analepsis>Jeff and I sat talking at the table outside the cafe.
        I had no idea what time it was.
        My hands lay on the table a few inches from his.
        Dark hairs curled on his wrists.
        Our fingers were almost touching.

        Simultaneously, we stopped talking
        and looked at the table.

        "I've got to get back to work ," he said.
        "Would you like to stop by and see my company.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue38.html">
        <prolepsis>In the Broadthrow's white Pontiac,
        I followed Jeff's pickup truck onto the highway.
        We drove North for what seemed forever,
        pulled into a driveway where grey buildings were clustered closely together.
        A sign in the parking lot said "MicrArt."
        We went in.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue39.html">
        <prolepsis>No one was sitting in the green chair
        behind the front desk in the MicrArt lobby.
        A tower of advertisements on 4"x6" cards
        balanced precariously on top of
        several blue and white boxes with letters and numbers
        printed on their sides. We walked through a door
        into a vast expanse of gray cement floors.
        There were no windows.
        Rows of benches were covered with black and silver equipment; piles of cables;
        boxes of small objects encrusted with wires;
        microscopes; tv screens;
        clear plastic boxes with holes in them; surgical gloves.
        In the back exposed pipes
        alternated with ten foot tall machines.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue40.html">
        <prolepsis>Four or five women were bent at intervals over the benches,
        peering through microscopes, putting
        white plastic gloved hands in the holes in the plastic boxes
        looking intently at grainy black and white pictures on tv screens.
        They were all wearing white coats like doctors wear.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue41.html">
        <prolepsis>A woman not much more than 5 feet tall,
        stood up. Her lab jacket,
        stained with grease or coffee,
        reached almost to the floor.
        "Really fucked up!" she said.

        Jeff scowled at an overhead tv screen.
        "Bumps on the chips," he said.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue42.html">
        <prolepsis>A poster of Ronald Reagan with Bonzo
        in the move Bedtime for Bonzo
        was tacked next to a faded list
        of warnings about the hazardous effects of various substances.

        I studied the Snickers Bars,
        peanut butter and cheese crackers, Cheezits, and
        Reese's peanut butter cups
        in a vending machine against the wall.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue43.html">
        <prolepsis>Next to the vending machine
        on an old typing table
        was a Mr. Coffee machine containing an
        almost empty pot of coffee which smelled
        like it had been there since yesterday.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue44.html">
        <prolepsis>"Jenny, I've got to take care of a problem, " Jeff said.

        "I'll go now, " I said.

        "Please wait, " he said.
        His eyes were dark brown</prolepsis>.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue45.html">
        <prolepsis>He took me to a cluttered office.
        "I'll be back in five or ten minutes.
        You are welcome to play with the computer."

        I pulled the blue notebook out of my pocketbook
        and started to write.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue46.html">
        <analepsis>David didn't say anything about stopping to see
        his parents, but we turned off the road,
        and in five minutes
        we were pulling into their driveway.

        The driveway was empty, and there was no laundry
        on the line.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue47.html">
        <prolepsis>It was a smoothly finished log cabin with red trim
        and windowboxes full of well controlled geraniums.

        The front door was open. We walked in.
        "Hello, " David said.

        There was no answer.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue48.html">
        <prolepsis>He shut the door behind us,
        reached out and put his hand on the zipper
        of my shorts. He pulled my zipper down,
        and put his hand in under my panties.
        With his other hand, he unbuttoned my shirt.

        "Where are your parents?" I asked.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue49.html">
        <prolepsis>He picked me up and carried me to the leather couch
        in front of the fireplace.
        On the couch, he climbed on top of me
        and parted my legs.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue50.html">
        <prolepsis>I noticed that there were placards of service
        from the Heritage Foundation, The John Birch Society,
        and the Catholic League of Decency
        on the mantel of the cabin.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue51.html">
        <prolepsis>Afterwards, we lay quietly on the couch.
        David reached over and turned on the radio.
        There was bad news.</prolepsis> <analepsis>Six more blimps with photographs of Henry Kissenger
        had been sighted over the downtown area.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue52.html">
        <prolepsis>He took me in his arms again,
        his lips were on my mouth; his hands on my breasts.

        The front door opened.

        "David are you home?"
        I heard his mother say.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue53.html">
        <prolepsis>"What are you writing, Jenny?"
        Jeff was back, standing in the doorway of his office.

        "Nothing much," I said.
        I put the blue notebook
        in my pocketbook and stood up.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue54.html">
        <prolepsis>He stood there looking at me.
        "This isn't how I wanted things to happen," He said.
        He had put on a lab coat and was trying awkwardly to unbutton it.

        The telephone rang. No one answered it.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue55.html">
        <prolepsis>He reached behind him and closed the office door.
        Putting his hands on my waist, he pulled me
        gently towards him. He put his lips on mine.
        I felt my legs go weak.

        The telephone was still ringing.

        He pulled me closer, stroking my hair while
        he kissed me again and again.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue56.html">
        <prolepsis>In the ladies room of the hotel restaurant,
        I dried my hands. The soap was still on the floor.

        "Jeff?" I said, feeling the color rise on my
        cheeks as I turned to face Uncle Roger.

        Uncle Roger reached into his pocket and pulled out
        a small chip. It was less than an inch long -
        covered with colored ridges and gold lines.
        "What's that?" I asked.

        "It's a knock off of the chip Jeff designed
        and Tom stole, " he said.
        There was a piece of rice stuck between
        his front teeth.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue57.html">
        <prolepsis>Uncle Roger handed me the chip. I grasped it
        tentatively. He reached down, picked up the soap
        and put it in his pocket.
        I heard footsteps in the corridor.
        "Let's talk somewhere else," I said.

        "How about in here," he said,
        stepping into one of the toilet stalls.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue58.html">
        <prolepsis>I went into an adjacent stall and closed the door.
        "I don't understand, " I said.
        I was still holding the chip.

        Two women entered the ladies room,
        and stood by the mirror.
        I could see their shoes
        a pair of shiny black high heels and a pair of
        red leather jogging shoes.

        "I had it knocked off in Haiti, " he whispered.
        "Wonderful isn't it?"

        The women were talking.
        "There aren't any men in the bar."
        "Let's go somewhere else."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue59.html">
        <prolepsis>"Broadthrow is hung up on the process
        and I've got a million of them coming off the line in Haiti."
        Uncle Roger was dancing around in the toilet stall
        humming "fast fast fast" softly to himself.
        I could see his black shoes and brown socks
        moving on the pink tiled floor.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue60.html">
        <prolepsis>"But Uncle Roger isn't that illegal?" I asked.

        "You don't understand the semiconductor business,
        my dear child." He flushed the toilet.

        "I think I'm in love with Jeff Gallagher,"
        I said.

        "There's a nice young stockbroker in our San Francisco office
        I want you to meet, " said Uncle Roger.
        "And by the way,
        I've arranged for you to start work there next week."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue61.html">
        <prolepsis>The toilet in my stall was new and clean.
        It smelled of disinfectant.
        "I don't want to work in your office
        and what's the matter with Jeff
        besides the fact that you just ripped him off?" I whispered angrily.

        "Broadthrow stole Gallagher's design.
        I merely helped myself to some things I found in Broadthrow's study
        the night of that party in Woodside," said Uncle Roger.
        "The trouble with Jeff Gallagher is that he's not a good businessman."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue62.html">
        <prolepsis>"I have two pieces of advice for young women:
        No. 1 - It's what's up front that counts.
        You may have some difficulty with that one."

        "No. 2 -it's not what you know that counts,
        but who you know." Uncle Roger smiled at me. "You'll be our new file clerk."

        "I don't want to be a file clerk," I said.

        "My dear, when this all breaks, Broadthrow's sure to find out
        you're my niece. He has a large detective agency working for him.
        You must get out of Woodside. I'm going back to Haiti."

        But you told everyone you were in Hawaii."

        "I lied " said Uncle Roger.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue63.html">
        <prolepsis>The women at the ladies room mirror were whispering to each other.
        "Those guys in tan suits are kind of cute."

        Uncle Roger bounded out of the toilet stall.
        Did I hear you say you were looking for men?"</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue64.html">
        <prolepsis>Uncle Roger left with the two women.
        Or rather, they left very quickly and
        he followed.

        Slipping the chip in my front shirt pocket,
        I opened the toilet stall door.
        I turned on the cold water and ran it slowly
        until the sink was very full. Then I put
        both hands in and splashed cold water repeatedly
        over my face.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue65.html">
        <analepsis>As I headed up the hill to Woodside, I was
        anticipating a few quiet hours.
        Caroline and Mark were still at school.
        Louise was supposed to be shopping.

        I pulled into the Broadthrow's driveway.
        There was a familiar looking old black Buick
        parked a little up the hill.
        David was leaning against his car, reading
        a green book with GUIDE TO THE CALIFORNIA
        COASTLINE printed in large black letters
        on the cover. "Hi Jenny," he said.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue66.html">
        <prolepsis>I stood with my back to the door of
        Broadthrow's white Pontiac.

        David laid the book down on the hood of his car.
        "I've been driving for 3 days
        I really wanted to see you," he said.
        He walked towards me still talking.
        "I've been waiting for you for hours.
        I've got a picnic. Let's go to the beach."

        "I don't know," I said. He had on old jeans and
        looked like he hadn't shaved for several days.

        "Please " he said.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue67.html">
        <prolepsis>The beach was empty except for
        a dog and a man; (the man throwing sticks into the water;
        the dog chasing them)

        David had a large paper bag with him.
        Inside was a bottle of Italian red wine,
        two tin coffee cups, a loaf of French bread
        broken in two halves,
        and a wedge of nondescript cheese.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue68.html">
        <prolepsis>He opened the wine with a Donald Duck commemorative corkscrew.
        "Are you mad because I didn't
        want to see you for a while?" he asked</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue69.html">
        <prolepsis>He poured us each a glass of wine.
        The sun had come
        out. The waves lapping on the
        shore sounded just like</prolepsis> <analepsis>the waves at the beach on the North shore
        where David and I had had a picnic like this
        last summer.</analepsis>

        <prolepsis>"How's Linda?" I asked.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue70.html">
        <prolepsis>David's wine glass fell over.
        A stream of red wine soaked the sand.
        He righted the glass carefully,
        sticking its stem deep into the sand.

        "How did you know about Linda?" he asked.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue71.html">
        <prolepsis>Cold water dripped down my face.
        I looked at myself
        in the mirror of the ladies room.
        David wanted me to go back East with him.
        I was having dinner with Jeff next Monday.
        Uncle Roger wanted me to be a file clerk.

        Water splashes had left dark spots on the front
        of my gray sweater. I took off the silver
        barrette which held my hair away from my face,
        and put it in my pocketbook.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue72.html">
        <prolepsis>I walked slowly back to the table in the restaurant,
            thinking about</prolepsis> <analepsis>how Linda and David had looked
        the night I drove by David's apartment
        and saw them coming out together.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue73.html">
        <prolepsis>The translucent desk stand
        engraved with a scene of boats and clouds and birds
        had stopped at my place.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue74.html">
        <prolepsis>As I leaned over to pick it up,
        Uncle Roger's chip fell out and bounced
        on the floor beside Dennis
        just as two waiters brought in a white cake
        with pink candles and pink flowers on it and
        "Happy Birthday Tom" written across the top
        in green frosting letters.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/blue75.html">
        <prolepsis>Everybody started singing "Happy Birthday"
        except Dennis and me:

        Dennis reached down and picked up the chip.
        He looked at it closely, holding it in the palm
        of his hand. There was a pile of uneaten shrimp
        on his plate.

        He handed the chip to me and joined in on the chorus.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <!-- File 3 begins here -->
    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/scene.html">
        In the room where I work, there are
        about twenty desks, called "stations".
        A computer takes up most of the space at
        each station. Each computer has a
        black screen which rests on a gray case,
        and a keyboard which is attached to the
        computer by a cord, like those cords which
        hold the two pieces of telephones together.
        They call the computers "terminals".
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/101.html">
        <prolepsis>I looked up at the clock. It was 4:15.
        I was supposed to finish the shopping center
        report by the end of the day, but there were still
        thirty pages left. Some of them had intricate
        tables which compared attendance at various
        shopping centers at different times.
        My eyes hurt. It was hard to keep them open.
        I felt like putting my head down on the desk
        beside the computer.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/102.html">
        <prolepsis>At the front of the room, under a round clock,
        the Supervisor, was writing in the notebook
        which she locked in her top desk drawer
        every evening at 5:00 before she went home.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/103.html">
        <prolepsis>I dreamed I was sitting at a small desk
        in the back of a room. There was an
        enormous central processing unit and a
        computer keyboard on the desk in front of me.
        I was typing the results of a study of
        visitors to the El Cerrito Plaza shopping center.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/104.html">
        <prolepsis>Everything I typed on the keyboard
        showed up on a large screen
        which filled the entire wall at the front of the room.
        Five men in tan suits were sitting around the screen,
        watching the words as I typed them in.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/105.html">
        <prolepsis>My fingers felt heavy and wooden,
        and they moved on the wrong keys. Instead of
        THE EL CERRITO PLAZA VISITORS STUDY,
        I typed THE EL CERRITO PIZZA VIOLATORS STUDY.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/106.html">
        <prolepsis>On the long table in the Broadthrow's living room,
        there were silver plates piled with cookies
        shaped like stars, bells, and snowmen.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/107.html">
        <analepsis>What I type on the keyboard appears in green
        on the screen which is called the monitor.
        When the screen is full, the letters
        scroll up somewhere inside the machine.
        The woman at the station to my left is typing steadily.
        Her husband is an IBM salesman, and she
        keeps his picture in a small silver frame
        beside her computer.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/108.html">
        <prolepsis>The egg salad sandwich was made with soft
        white bread. Some of the filling oozed out
        and fell on the computer keyboard
        between f9 and f10.
        I reached in my pocketbook to get a napkin to
        wipe it up, but there wasn't one.
        I tore off a small piece of the brown paper bag
        which the sandwich came in.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/109.html">
        <prolepsis>Caroline was passing around a silver tray
        laden with hot cheese puffs. Dennis offered Dorrie
        a star-shaped cookie topped with red and green sugar.
        I took a cheese puff. "Hi, my name is Jake,"
        said a man in a tan suit.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/110.html">
        <analepsis>The lunch room is a small rectangular room
        with no windows. There is a sink and a counter
        with a Mr. Coffee machine at one end of the room.
        At the other end, there is a refrigerator and
        a microwave oven.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/111.html">
        <prolepsis>Most of the women who work in the room where I work
        eat their lunch in the lunch room. They
        keep frozen tv dinners in the freezer
        compartment of the refrigerator, and at lunch
        time, they heat them up in the microwave.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/112.html">
        <prolepsis>"Press esc to hyphenate consu-mer."
        The computer beeped loudly.
        I didn't wanted to hyphenate consumer,
        so I pressed f2 instead.
        "Press esc to hyphenate consu-mer,"
        the computer screen flashed again, beeped loudly.
        The Supervisor looked up from her notebook.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/113.html">
        <prolepsis>"It's an FX-7000G ," said one of the men
        in tan suits. He pulled a thin calculator
        out of his pocket. The other two men leaned
        over the calculator while he pushed some buttons.
        Small grey graphs appeared
        on the tiny green screen.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/114.html">
        "It's an FX-7000G ," said one of the men
        in tan suits. He pulled a thin calculator
        out of his pocket. The other two men leaned
        over the calculator while he pushed some buttons.
        Small grey graphs appeared
        on the tiny green screen.
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/115.html">
        <analepsis>I pretended to read the help screen
        while I took large bites of the sandwich,
        making sure before each bite that
        the Supervisor was absorbed in her notebook.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/116.html">
        <prolepsis>The men in tan suits <analepsis>had unwrapped their
        silver-coated butter</analepsis> and were carefully spearing
        it with their forks.
        The stewardess gave us each a small bag of
        Hawaiian potato chips. "I've got some Haitian
        chips," said Uncle Roger. His briefcase was open
        on the plastic tray where the burrito had been.
        Inside the briefcase were about ten ziplock plastic bags
        full of small chips covered with tiny gold lines.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/117.html">
        <prolepsis>"Its lasagna," said the stewardess,
        handing the little pots of pasta
        to the men in tan suits. On each tray,
        beside the pot of lasagna was a piece of
        yellow cake with white frosting.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/118.html">
        <analepsis>I dreamed I was wearing a white lab coat
        in a large room with concrete walls
        and long rows of sliver and plexiglass
        machinery. About 20 other women wearing
        white labcoats were moving slowly around the room.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/119.html">
        <prolepsis>In the center of the room in the dream,
        there was a circular glass bin, about 6 feet high.
        It was filled with several thousand chips.
        I walked over to the bin and looked in.
        Inside, giant blades, like those in a blender,
        were moving slowly, grinding the chips
        into small, powdery pieces.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/120.html">
        <analepsis>I dreamed I was sitting at a small desk
        in the back of a room. There was an
        enormous central processing unit and a
        computer keyboard on the desk in front of me.
        I was typing the results of a study of
        visitors to the El Cerrito Plaza shopping center.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/121.html">
        <prolepsis>I slid the egg salad sandwich
        out of the paper bag in my pocketbook.
        It had been cut in half
        diagonally and wrapped in cellophane.
        The two halves were seperated with a
        triangular shaped piece of cardboard.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/122.html">
        <analepsis>Everything I typed on the keyboard showed up
        on a large screen that filled the entire wall
        at the front of the room. Five men in tan suits
        were sitting around the screen,
        watching the words as I typed them in.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/123.html">
        <prolepsis>Uncle Roger smiled and started walking back
        down the aisle.
        "I keep mine in a PC fortress"
        said a man in a tan suit.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/124.html">
        <analepsis>In the lunch room, three women in grey
        straight skirts were sitting around the table
        eating microwaved frozen tv dinners.
        "I had this mail merge all set up,
        but when I sent it to the printer,
        all the names and address were indented wrong."</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/125.html">
        <analepsis>We came out into a clearing.
        At the top of a hill covered with tall grass,
        each stalk topped with a heavy bunch of brown seeds,
        we stepped into an open field.
        The grass came up to our knees. It was hot.
        Jeff took off his jacket and tied it around his waist.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/126.html">
        <prolepsis>Sun coming in the window woke me early.
        I was curled up in Jeff's arms.
        He was sleeping.
        I turned over in his arms and nibbled his neck,
        softly where his hair curled under his ear.
        I ran my fingers gently down his chest, following
        the line of his thick, dark hair.
        I put my hands on his thighs.
        He moaned softly in his sleep.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/127.html">
        <analepsis>We were in the ruins of an old fort overlooking
        San Francisco Bay. We stood there for a while
        looking out through crumbled windows.
        A few sailboats tossed in the rough blue green
        water of the Bay. Jeff pulled me to him,
        unbuttoning my blouse while he put his tongue
        deep into my mouth. He took one of my hands
        and guided it down to his crotch.
        I sank to my knees and unzipped his pants.
        Water soaked into my jeans where my knees
        touched the ground.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/128.html">
        <prolepsis>In my dream, there was a rectangular room
        at the end of a long hall.
        A picture window almost the size of the far wall
        looked out on a stone platform
        surrounded by green, close cut grass.
        Two behaviorists were lying on the platform watching us,
        as still as statues with yellow eyes.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/129.html">
        <prolepsis>In the livingroom of the house where I grew up,
        the wood floor was sparely covered with
        two faded oval braided rugs.
        I went to the window and looked out at the
        snow-covered backyard.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/130.html">
        <analepsis>Jack's arm was around Rose's waist.
        He kissed her. His hand moved to her breast.
        "I've been thinking of getting a dog,"
        Dorrie said.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/131.html">
        <prolepsis>I looked out the Broadthrow's window.
        A white car drove up and stopped across the street.
        Uncle Roger got out.
        It was a sunny December Sunday afternoon in Woodside,
        but he was wearing a long black overcoat,
        and a black fakefur Russian hat.
        In his hands he held a sprig of mistletoe
        and a brown paper bag.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/132.html">
        <prolepsis>Uncle Roger and Jeff followed me into my room.
        I didn't have three chairs, so I sat on the edge of the bed.
        "Uncle Roger has something he wants to tell you,"
        I said to Jeff.
        Uncle Roger reached into his pocket and pulled out
        a chip covered with tiny gold lines -- like the chip
        he had handed me in the bathroom of the hotel
        where we celebrated Tom's birthday.
        "Young man, does this look familiar?" he asked.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/133.html">
        <prolepsis>"That's my chip," Jeff said to Uncle Roger
        before he hit him.
        "Yes," Uncle Roger said,
        getting up slowly from the floor.
        "But it was Tom Broadthrow who stole your design.
        Admittedly, I ripped it off from him."

        Uncle Roger began to discuss the details
        of the chip in technical language
        that I did not understand.

        But Jeff did not stay to listen.
        He exited, slamming the door behind him.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/134.html">
        <prolepsis>Uncle Roger sat down on the couch beside Dorrie
        and started to tell her a story about
        a Priest, a Rabbi, and two Born Again Christians.
        <analepsis>I'd heard it before.</analepsis>
        Just as he got to the part about how they
        went to a shopping center,
        and argued about which store they would go to first,
        Jeff strode through the front door of the Broadthrow's house
        without ringing the bell.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/135.html">
        <prolepsis>We had an absolutely wonderful time,"
        said the woman with the pink sweater pulled down
        over her straight gray skirt. There was a
        tupperware bowl full of sliced carrots and celery
        in front of her. "But it's been two weeks,
        and he hasn't called me. What do you think
        I should do?"</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/136.html">
        <prolepsis>Jeff's face was white.
        "You son of a bitch," he shouted.
        He hit Tom squarely on the jar.
        The glass of whiskey fell onto the floor
        and broke into several pieces.
        Whiskey oozed into the blue gray carpet.
        Tom grabbed a bottle of Russian vodka and
        threw it at Jeff. The bottle hit one of the silver
        candlesticks on the mantle and broke into many pieces,
        splattering vodka and fragments of glass
        down the front of the marble fireplace.

        Louise picked up the phone.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/137.html">
        <analepsis>My fingers felt heavy and wooden, and they moved
        on the wrong keys. Instead of THE EL CERRITO
        PLAZA VISITORS STUDY, I typed
        THE EL CERRITO PIZZA VIOLATORS STUDY.
        It's January in San Francisco.
        Through the windows that run along the East side
        of the big room where I work as a word processor
        for a market research firm,
        I can see that the sun is shining outside.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/138.html">
        <prolepsis>Jeff hit Tom again.
        Tom staggered against the table,
        squashing a row of plastic glasses.
        His nose was bleeding.
        "When they arrived at the shopping center,
        they could not decide which store to go to first,"
        Uncle Roger continued.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/139.html">
        <prolepsis>"You bastard," Jeff said.
        He grabbed the end of Tom's tie.
        Tom picked up a plastic cup half full of eggnog
        which was sitting on the edge of the table.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/140.html">
        <analepsis>"I had this mail merge all set up,
        but when I sent it to the printer,
        all the names and address were indented wrong,"
        said the woman, who was sticking her fork into
        a frozen fettucini dinner.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/141.html">
        <prolepsis>Three men in tan suits were standing
        beside the Broadthrow's Christmas tree
        with their hands full of cookies and eggnog.
        "I have a LEADING EDGE," said the first one.
        He was wearing a red striped shirt.
        "2400 baud is the way to go," said the one
        who was eating a sugar cookie shaped like Santa Claus.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/142.html">
        <analepsis>I put 40 cents into the coffee money box
        and poured some coffee from the Mr. Coffee machine
        into a white styrofoam cup.
        "I really like your shoes," said the woman
        who wearing a straight gray skirt and
        a matching gray jacket.

        I was wearing red plastic sandals.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/143.html">
        <prolepsis>I dreamed I was wearing a white lab coat
        in a room with concrete walls
        and long rows of sliver and plexiglass
        machinery. About 20 other women wearing
        white labcoats were moving slowly around the room.
        In the center of the room, there was a circular
        glass bin, about 6 feet high.
        It was filled with several thousand chips.
        I walked over to the bin and looked in.
        Inside, giant blades, like those in a blender,
        were moving slowly, grinding the chips
        into small, powdery pieces.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/144.html">
        <prolepsis>I dreamed that Jeff and I were standing
        in a shallow pool. The water came up to our waists.
        Along the edges of the pool were blue green tiles
        with handpainted pictures of birds and fish
        and flowers. Jeff was holding a big beachball
        in his hands. I was wearing an old blue bathing suit
        which was a little too small for me.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/145.html">
        <prolepsis>Tom picked up another bottle of Russian vodka
        and threw it hard at Jeff's head.
        It missed.
        It smashed through the big front window and
        hurtled out into the Woodside hills.
        I heard police sirens.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/146.html">
        <analepsis>I combined the oil, egg, and milk
        and stirred them into the cornmeal and sugar,
        licking the wooden spoon to see what the batter
        tasted like. Jeff came up quietly behind me.
        Brushing my hair aside,
        he kissed the back of my neck.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/147.html">
        <prolepsis>Dennis was wearing faded blue jeans
        and a red velvet jacket.
        He came over to me, holding a beer.
        "Ah, the girl with the chip. Tonight we match."
        He put his red velvet sleeve next to the
        red wool sleeve of my Christmas season dress.
        "The sooner I get back to Albuquerque the better,"
        he said. "Uhh - that chip? I never saw it."
        He took a big swig of the beer,
        and walked away.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/148.html">
        <prolepsis>"Press esc to hyphenate consu-mer."
        "Press esc to hyphenate consu-mer."

        "beep beep beep beep"

        The Supervisor looked up from her notebook.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/149.html">
        <prolepsis>With their hands full of cookies and eggnog,
        three men in tan suits were standing beside
        the Broadthrow's Christmas tree, talking about their systems.
        Dennis offered Dorrie another star shaped cookie.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/150.html">
        <prolepsis>Uncle Roger came out of the kitchen,
        a glass full of whiskey with
        no ice in it in each of his hands.
        Tom was lying on the floor
        beside a table which was covered
        with beer, wine, vodka, whiskey, and gingerale.
        He was wearing a dark blue suit and a red tie
        with small blue sailboats on it.

        "Would you like a drink?" Uncle Roger asked.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/151.html">
        <prolepsis>Small foil bags full of ribbon candy
        hung on the boughs of the Broadthrow;s tree,
        Beneath the tree,
        were gold packages with red ribbons,
        silver packages with pink ribbons,
        packages wrapped in patterned papers,
        bottles of wine and whiskey,
        wooden baskets of cheese and sausages,
        shipping containers packed with pears and apples,
        enameled tins filled with fruit cake or cookies.
        "I keep mine in a PC fortress,"
        said one of the men in tan suits.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/152.html">
        <prolepsis>The traffic on 128 has slowed to a crawl.
        I turned on the car radio, switching stations
        until I found one playing "The Little Drummer Boy".
        The car windows kept fogging over inside.
        My mother rubbed them with her mittens.
        The heater in her car wasn't working.
        I reached for the blanket in the back seat.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/153.html">
        <analepsis>My present from Uncle Roger was
        a round trip ticket to Boston.
        On December 23rd, we flew home together.
        "I'll bet Bruce has a bigger you know what,"
        he said, fingering his cheek
        which was still slightly black and blue
        where Jeff had hit him.

        I stared at an article about Donald Trump
        in the Airline Magazine.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/154.html">
        <prolepsis>"Bruce and I had a party once in a hot tub
        with some stewardesses," said Uncle Roger.
        Do you want to know how much money he makes?"</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/155.html">
        <analepsis>I looked up at the clock. It was 4:15.
        I was supposed to finish the shopping center report
        by the end of the day, but there were still
        thirty pages left. Some of them had intricate
        tables which compared attendance at various
        shopping centers at different times.
        My eyes hurt. It was hard to keep them open.
        I felt like putting my head down on the desk beside the computer.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/156.html">
        <prolepsis>"I don't know why you won't come to work
        for Clark and Clark," Uncle Roger said on the airplane.
        "You can have your own office
        with a blue rug
        and a view of San Francisco Bay.
        Bruce has some new underwear
        with pictures of Christmas presents imprinted on it.
        He is really looking forward to meeting you."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/157.html">
        <analepsis>Jeff stepped towards me and started slowly
        to unbutton my white dress.
        It was warm in my apartment, and I wasn't wearing
        anything underneath.
        He unfastened all the buttons
        that ran down the front
        of the dress.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/158.html">
        <prolepsis>The stewardesses were coming down the aisle
        with metal carts full of plastic trays
        containing beef stroganoff, lasagna, and
        baked fish with cheese sauce. Uncle Roger was
        half way through the super burrito he had brought
        with him. Some guacamole and sour cream dripped
        onto the red knit tie that <analepsis>Aunt Sally had made
        him</analepsis>, and he wiped it up with a piece of the
        airline magazine magazine that was in the seat
        in front of him.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/159.html">
        <analepsis>Dennis offered Dorrie a cookie
        from the paper plate he was carrying around
        which was loaded with cookies and cake.
        She was wearing tight jeans and a lacy black top.
        I put a cheese puff on my plate.
        "Hi. My name is jake," said a man in a tan suit.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/160.html">
        <prolepsis>The eggnog was thick and heavy like whipped cream
        or marshmellow mixed with custard and rum.
        A man in a tan suit reached out
        and put his hand on a transparent
        pink glass heart on the Christmas tree.
        "It's an FX-70000," said one of the men
        in tan suits. He pulled a long thin calculator
        out of his pocket. The other two men leaned
        over the calculator while he pushed some buttons.
        Small gray graphs appeared on the calculator's
        tiny green screen.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/161.html">
        <prolepsis>The traffic on 128 has slowed to a crawl.
        I turned on the car radio, switching stations
        until I found one playing "The Little Drummer Boy".
        The car windows kept fogging over inside.
        My mother rubbed them with her mittens.
        The heater in her car wasn't working.
        I reached for the blanket in the back seat.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/162.html">
        <analepsis>I opened the door. It was Jeff.
        He was standing outside the door of my California apartment,
        The blue and tan flannel shirt he was wearing
        was rolled up at the sleeves.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/163.html">
        <prolepsis>Jeff stood in the doorway, looking at me.
        I was wearing an old white dress
        that buttoned down the front.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/164.html">
        <prolepsis>The swimming pool in my dream
        was surrounded by an ivy covered fence
        and large maple trees. The grass was bright yellow green.
        Jeff tossed me the beach ball. I dropped it.
        A car drove into the driveway.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/165.html">
        <prolepsis>The hall was filled with winter coats on hooks.
        Old tennis rackets and wooden skis from another era
        leaned against the wall.
        Buckle-up rubber boots and unmatching mittens
        were piled in a big basket by the door.
        Wool scarves hung on a coar tree beside the basket.
        In the kitchen, my mother was heating red wine,
        orange juice, sugar, and cinnamon
        in an old aluminum pan.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/166.html">
        <analepsis>Uncle Roger walked down the aisle of the plane.
        He still had on his tweed suit jacket
        and the red wool tie that <analepsis>Aunt Sally had knitted for him.</analepsis>
        He was carrying his pants rolled up under his arm.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/167.html">
        <analepsis>Puffy was up on the table,
        licking eggnog out of a big silver bowl.
        Plastic glasses and little red and green napkins
        were spread out around her feet.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/168.html">
        <analepsis>Every morning I stand in line to buy
        a saran-wrapped sandwich
        on white bread from the silver-coated truck
        that pulls up between seven and eight
        outside of the building where I work.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/169.html">
        <prolepsis>The Broadthrow's blue spruce Christmas tree
        reached almost to the ceiling.
        It was covered with gold and pink ornaments
        and spray-on snow.
        At the top, white lights twinkled on and off
        around the angel with the pink dress
        and silver wings.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/170.html">
        <analepsis>There was a half eaten sandwich on a plate on the floor.
        Nearby, an industrial size wastebasket
        was full of empty beer and diet pepsi cans.
        Propped up on a floor
        beside David's sleeping bag and his camera
        was a copy of the same picture of Linda,
        with her red hair blowing in the wind,
        that <analepsis>I had torn into little pieces several months ago.</analepsis></analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/171.html">
        <prolepsis>The eggnog was thick and heavy like whipped cream
        or marshmallow mixed with custard and rum.
        I was wearing a silk dress.
        As if he wondered if it was real,
        a man in a tan suit reached out
        and placed his hand on a transparent,
        pink and gold glass ornament on the Christmas tree.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/172.html">
        <prolepsis>Uncle Roger and Tom came out of the kitchen
        with large glasses full of whiskey with
        no ice in it in their hands.
        Tom leaned against a table which was covered
        with beer, wine, vodka, whiskey, and gingerale.
        He was wearing a dark blue suit and a red tie
        with small blue sailboats on it.
        A misunderstanding on the golf course,"
        Uncle Roger said, touching the black and blue
        place on his face where Jeff had hit him.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/173.html">
        <analepsis>I dreamed that Jeff and I were standing in a
        shallow pool. The water came up to our waists.
        Along the edges of the pool were blue green tiles
        with handpainted pictures of birds and fish
        and flowers. Jeff was holding a big beachball
        in his hands.
        I was wearing an old blue bathing suit which
        was a little too small for me.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/174.html">
        <analepsis>I unwrapped the sandwich quietly with one hand,
        while I pressed shift-f3 on the computer keyboard
        with the other hand.
        I pretended to read the help screen
        while I took large bites of the sandwich,
        making sure before each bite
        that the supervisor was absorbed in her notebook.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/175.html">
        <prolepsis>There was a large tray of buffalo chicken wings
        on a marble coffee table
        beside a silver candle holder with pink candles.
        Uncle Roger was eating chicken wings,
        one after another.
        putting the bones in a small pile
        beside some books about Van Gogh and Rembrandt.
        He held up a bone as Louise walked by,
        "Does this remind you of anything?" he asked.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/176.html">
        <prolepsis>I listened to the radio on the way home to Woodside.
        There was an old song they played that made me cry</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/177.html">
        <prolepsis>"I need some exercise," said Uncle Roger,
        squeezing past me into the aisle.
        He walked up and down the aisle, bumping
        into stewardesses. "I'm a frequent flyer,"
        he said to the stewardess with the red hair who
        was collecting half empty plastic food trays
        a few rows behind us.
        He flapped his arms like wings and pivoted around,
        heading down the aisle the other way, still
        flapping his arms.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/178.html">
        <analepsis>In my dream, the men in tan suits
        got up from the table and came slowly
        down the aisle to my desk.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/179.html">
        <prolepsis>I dreamed that Uncle Roger and I
        were in Filene's basement in Boston.
        Behind a dress rack, a woman
        was trying on a pair of grey corduroy pants,
        pulling them on up under her mini skirt.
        Uncle Roger was with her,
        his arms full of women's pajamas
        with leopard and tiger skin patterns.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/180.html">
        <prolepsis>I dreamed that David and I were walking along
        an overgrown path. He walked ahead of me,
        trampling the brush, making it easier for me to pass.
        We came out into a clearing
        at the top of a hill covered with tall grass.
        Each stalk was topped with a heavy bunch of seeds.
        We stepped into the field. The grass came up to our knees.
        It was hot.
        I took off my jacket, tied it around my waist.

        David grabbed my arm and pointed to the right.
        There was a large lion there,
        sleeping in the sun.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/181.html">
        <prolepsis>I dreamed I lived in an old farmhouse
        on top of a hill in Vermont or New Hampshire.
        I was sitting on the doorstep.
        Six wild kittens who lived in the barn
        were playing around my feet,
        and they nibbled at my fingers with tiny sharp teeth
        when I tried to pat them.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/182.html">
        <prolepsis>There wasn't much furniture in my apartment.
        The bed, which the previous tenant had left,
        had broken springs which stuck out from holes on the mattress
        and scratched my legs at night.
        Jane was sitting on the edge of the bed, fighting back tears.
        "I'm going back home," she said.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/183.html">
        <prolepsis>We were driving North on 128.
        The windshield wipers squeaked loudly
        as they pushed off the heavy snow.
        It was snowing hard. Through the windshield, the lights of other cars
        were a diffused glow amidst the thick snow flurries.
        It was very cold.
        My mother was concentrating on the road,
        and we didn't talk much.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/184.html">
        <prolepsis>My brother strung the faded blue and white plaid
        bathrobe belt that <analepsis>had belonged to our Dad</analepsis>
        across the fireplace the was he did every
        Christmas eve. On it, we hung our stockings,
        pinning them with safety pins
        from the family sewing basket.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/185.html">
        <analepsis>My sandwich is in my pocketbook.
        It is only ten o'clock,
        but I'm already thinking about it.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/186.html">
        <prolepsis>To make most things happen, you have to push other
        buttons at the same time that you push the
        f buttons. Holding down the shift key and the
        f10 key loads a document into the computer.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/187.html">
        <analepsis>David was sleeping on the floor
        of his friend Robert's studio in Emeryville.
        Robert was making a book of photographs about baseball caps,
        David explained. He wasn't wearing a shirt.
        The walls were covered with photographs of men in baseball caps.
        Above me, a man wearing a baseball cap
        was eating a piece of lemon cream pie.
        Across his baseball cap's visor,
        was a brilliantly colored picture of surf and a sunset.
        The word "Hawaii" was embroidered
        in yellow black-bordered letters.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/188.html">
        <prolepsis>I dreamed that I was sitting on a bench in Civic Center Park.
        I was wearing a dirty corduroy skirt.
        My hair felt like it hadn't been washed for several weeks.
        On the bench beside me, there was a brown paper bag
        full of empty soda bottles that I had been collecting in the park.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/189.html">
        <analepsis>"Those are really sexy shoes," David said.
        One of his hands was still on my shirt pocket,
        and he pulled me towards him. He unzipped
        his pants.
        "I think we should just be friends," I replied.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/190.html">
        <prolepsis>On the long table in the Broadthrow's living room,
        there were silver plates piled with cookies
        shaped like stars, bells, and snowmen
        In the middle of the table,
        was a green frosted cake, shaped like a Christmas tree.
        Beside it, there was a cheese ball studded with walnuts.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/191.html">
        <prolepsis>Louise was wearing a pink satin dress,
        It was a short dress, revealing, when she sat down,
        translucent white stockings
        with a lacy sknowflake pattern.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/192.html">
        <prolepsis>Mark cut through the thick green frosting of the cake,
        put a large slice on a paper plate
        that had pictures of snowmen running around its rim.
        "I have some photos of me surfing on my new surfboard," he said.
        "They're in my room. Do you want to see them."</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/193.html">
        <prolepsis>"You bastard," Jeff said.
        He grabbed the end of Tom's tie.
        Tom picked up a plastic cup half full of eggnog
        which was sitting on the edge of the table.
        A gold glass ornament shaped like a
        French horn fell off the tree and broke
        into little pieces.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/194.html">
        <prolepsis>My mother's house was white with black shutters
        and a peeling barn door.
        It faced a path that once must have been a street.
       <analepsis>Someone had shoveled the path, piling the snow on
        the sides so it was waist high.</analepsis> I walked to
        the door, carrying my blue duffel bag.
        A battered snow shovel was leaning against
        one of the white columns on the front porch.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/195.html">
        <prolepsis>The tiles on the bathroom floor were freezing cold.
        I wrapped myself in a faded blue bath towel.
        It was slightly damp and smelled like the cellar
        where my mother usually dried the laundry
        on a clothesline which stretched from the furnace
        to the door of the room where my brother
        did experiments with his chemistry set.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/196.html">
        <analepsis>We were sitting in the modern aisle.
        I was on the outside. Two men in tan suits
        were beside Uncle Roger. He was showing them
        some things in the Wall Street Journal.
        The two tiny bottles he had brought
        with him in the pocket of his raincoat
        were protruding from the plastic bag
        where the airline magazines and the throw-up bags
        were kept. "Those are nice socks
        you men are wearing," he said.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/197.html">
        <prolepsis>Uncle Roger pulled a big, long, white
        parcel out of his other pocket. He pulled down
        the tray in front of him, and unwrapped the
        package. It was a super burrito.
        "Carnitas with extra guacamole,"
        he said. "Would you like a bite?"</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/198.html">
        <analepsis>I dreamed that a baseball game had just finished.
        All the seats on the BART car were filled with
        men and women wearing green and yellow
        baseball caps.
        Jeff and I stood close together. In the
        gentle forward motion of the train,
        He was pressed against me by men with thermos bottles.</analepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/199.html">
        <prolepsis>The Christmas tree, a hemlock with fine,
        flat needles, was so big that
        it almost touched the ceiling.
        It was Christmas eve. <analepsis>My mother
        had put red candles in silver candlesticks
        in the window.</analepsis> There was a bowl of popcorn on the
        floor beside the tree. My brother was eating it.</prolepsis>
    </div>

    <div title="http://collection.eliterature.org/3/works/uncle-roger/END.html">
        <analepsis>Uncle Roger smiled. "By the way Jenny," he said.
        "I signed the company that I formed with his design
        over to Jeff"
        He disappeared in the throng of people
        at the exit gates.

        "Get away from me you dirty old man," a woman
        in a blue uniform yelled from the area
        where the guards and the x-ray machines
        were located. Uncle Roger reappeared.

        "Merry Christmas!" he shouted,
        blowing us a kiss.

        THE END</analepsis>
    </div>










































</text>
