<text>

    <div title="key - http://collection.eliterature.org/2/works/coover_voyage/VoyageIntoTheUnknown/powell/index.html">
        <level degree="1">On May 25, 1869, you join the crew of one-armed Civil War veteran John
        Wesley Powell along with eight other fellow veterans, hunters and trappers,
        in an attempt to be the first to navigate the Colorado River, whose waters
        descend from the mountains of Idaho, Wyoming, Colorado, Utah, and
        Arizona toward the Gulf of California: the Sea of Cortez. After <analepsis>two tedious
        years in the army, mostly spent protecting stagecoach routes and railway
        construction teams,</analepsis> you are hungry for the adventure.

        Your map has few marks in the vast arid region between the Rocky
        Mountains and the California Sierras. Turning inward... this is, perhaps, the
        final American frontier, a terra incognita. No European-American has
        boated the formidable Colorado River — not, at least, and written about it —
        and none have mapped the maze of the canyons that surround it. What risks
        lie ahead? Sudden waterfalls and Whirlpools? Unwelcoming natives? The
        disappearance of the river underground? Hunger, fatigue, mutiny?

        What do you discover there, Mr. Bradley? And, what will you say to others?</level>
    </div>

    <div title="1 - Names of the crew and their ages">
        <level degree="1">Oramel G. Howland, 36
        John Wesley Powell, 35
        George Young Bradley, 32
        William H. Dunn, 30
        John Colton Summer, 29
        Walter Henry Powell, 27
        Seneca Howland, 26
        Billy Hawkins (a.k.a. Missouri), 20
        Andrew Hall, 19
        Frank Goodman, (d.o.b. unknown)</level>
    </div>

    <div title="1 - May 24 Powell writes of the launch">
        <level degree="2">"The good people of the city came to see us off. This does not indicate a great crowd, as the cities here lack people... there are plenty of vacant lots yet."
        All are aware the West is changing. Soon settlers will fill the landscape we map and name...</level>
    </div>

    <div title="1 - The names of Powell's boats">
        <level degree="2">The Maid of the Canyon
        Kitty Clyde's Sister
        The No-Name
        The Emma Dean

        The Emma Dean is named after the Major's wife. It is smaller and leads the other boats, scouting ahead for dangers. Our boats are laden with supplies, which are packed in enclosed compartments. Designed as seaboats, they are rudderless. You fear these Whitehall boats may not be the best choice for steering through rapids.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="2 - R">
        <level degree="2">Our boats descend through canyon rocks of yellows and reds, greens, grays and black: Kaibab limestone, Coconino sandstone, Hermit shale, and the Supai formation. Next comes Redwall limestone, a thin layer of Temple Butte limestone, more Redwall, Muav limestone, the green Bright Angel shale, Tapeats sandstone, and deepest and oldest: Precambrian schists and gneisses. Your journey into the unknown land is a voyage into the depths of geological time, stripped bare by unfathomable forces from above and below.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="3 - Sleeping Under Two Pines">
        Sleeping Under Two Pines
    </div>

    <div title="3 - Flaming Gorge">
        Flaming Gorge
    </div>
    <!-- Should the above be classed as first-degree narrative level? Because they are given by the over-all, modern (meta-)narrator, rather than by Powell or Bradley. But they are not narration, just place names. -->

    <div title="3 - N">
        <level degree="2">In mapping the unknown, we name it for generations to come. Some places we name for their beauty. Others we name because they are markers of of what we have faced and what others will surely face again, although perhaps these places have already been named long before in other tongues.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="3 - Canyon of the Rapids">
        Canyon of the Rapids
    </div>

    <div title="3 - Red Canyon">
        Red Canyon
    </div>

    <div title="3 - Cliff of the Harp"></div>

    <div title="3 - Canyon of Ladore">
        <level degree="2">THE CATARACT OF LODORE (1820)
        How does the water
        Come down at Lodore?"
        My little boy asked me
        Thus, once on a time;
        And moreover he tasked me
        To tell him in rhyme.
        Anon, at the word,
        There first came one daughter,
        And then came another,
        To second and third
        The request of their brother,
        And to hear how the water
        Comes down at Lodore,
        With its rush and its roar,
        As many a time
        They had seen it before.
        So I told them in rhyme,
        For of rhymes I had store;
        And 'twas in my vocation
        For their recreation
        That so I should sing;
        Because I was Laureate
        To them and the King.

        From its sources which well
        In the tarn on the fell;
        From its fountains
        In the mountains,
        Its rills and its gills;
        Through moss and through brake,
        It runs and it creeps
        For a while, till it sleeps
        In its own little lake.
        And thence at departing,
        Awakening and starting,
        It runs through the reeds,
        And away it proceeds,
        Through meadow and glade,
        In sun and in shade,
        And through the wood-shelter,
        Among crags in its flurry,
        Helter-skelter,
        Hurry-skurry.
        Here it comes sparkling,
        And there it lies darkling;
        Now smoking and frothing
        Its tumult and wrath in,
        Till, in this rapid race
        On which it is bent,
        It reaches the place
        Of its steep descent.

        The cataract strong
        Then plunges along,
        Striking and raging

        As if a war raging
        Its caverns and rocks among;
        Rising and leaping,
        Sinking and creeping,
        Swelling and sweeping,
        Showering and springing,
        Flying and flinging,
        Writhing and ringing,
        Eddying and whisking,
        Spouting and frisking,
        Turning and twisting,
        Around and around
        With endless rebound:
        Smiting and fighting,
        A sight to delight in;
        Confounding, astounding,
        Dizzying and deafening the ear with its sound.

        Collecting, projecting,
        Receding and speeding,
        And shocking and rocking,
        And darting and parting,
        And threading and spreading,
        And whizzing and hissing,
        And dripping and skipping,
        And hitting and splitting,
        And shining and twining,
        And rattling and battling,
        And shaking and quaking,
        And pouring and roaring,
        And waving and raving,
        And tossing and crossing,
        And flowing and going,
        And running and stunning,
        And foaming and roaming,
        And dinning and spinning,
        And dropping and hopping,
        And working and jerking,
        And guggling and struggling,
        And heaving and cleaving,
        And moaning and groaning;

        And glittering and frittering,
        And gathering and feathering,
        And whitening and brightening,
        And quivering and shivering,
        And hurrying and skurrying,
        And thundering and floundering;

        Dividing and gliding and sliding,
        And falling and brawling and sprawling,
        And driving and riving and striving,
        And sprinkling and twinkling and wrinkling,
        And sounding and bounding and rounding,
        And bubbling and troubling and doubling,
        And grumbling and rumbling and tumbling,
        And clattering and battering and shattering;

        Retreating and beating and meeting and sheeting,
        Delaying and straying and playing and spraying,
        Advancing and prancing and glancing and dancing,
        Recoiling, turmoiling and toiling and boiling,
        And gleaming and streaming and steaming and beaming,
        And rushing and flushing and brushing and gushing,
        And flapping and rapping and clapping and slapping,
        And curling and whirling and purling and twirling,
        And thumping and plumping and bumping and jumping,
        And dashing and flashing and splashing and clashing;
        And so never ending, but always descending,
        Sounds and motions for ever and ever are blending
        All at once and all o'er, with a mighty uproar, -
        And this way the water comes down at Lodore.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="3 - Bee-Hive Point"></div>

    <div title="3 - Ashley Falls">
        <level degree="1">You are not the first here.  Carved in the rockface are the markings, Ashley 1825 -or is it 1835? "Boys, let's name this spot Ashley Falls." Perhaps Ashley was on a boat that was said to have sunk in an attempt to navigate this part of the river several years before.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="4 - Powell portrays both ecstasy and foreboding">
        <level degree="2">The canyon opened like a beautiful portal to a region of beauty. Now the sun is going down and the shadows are setting into the canyon. Now ‘tis a black portal to a region of gloom.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="4 - Sleeping Under a Cottonwood"></div>

    <div title="4">
        <level degree="1">Sumner keeps a diary, too, and grumbles about Lodore...</level> <level degree="2">"It has been named Lodore Canyon by the Professor, the idea of diving into musty trash to find names for new discoveries on a new continent is un-American to say the least."</level>
    </div>

    <div title="4 - N">
        <level degree="1">Perhaps out of a lingering memory of <analepsis>that trapper named Ashley</analepsis> or a recognition of mortality, you might join the others in carving your name here on these canyon rocks.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="4 - Shadow Canyon"></div>

    <div title="4 - Dogs">
        <level degree="1">The major is not the only crew member to keep a log of the journey. Your own diary records the highs and lows of the descent into a gloomy darkness... Your prose is not quite like the Major's -- all he writes are scant notes scratched on stitched pages for later expansion. Today, you write;</level>
        <level degree="2"><analepsis>Have been working like galley-slaves all day...</analepsis> The rapid is still continuous and not improving. Where we are tonight it roars and foams like a wild beast....<analepsis>The Major as usual has chosen the worst camping-ground possible.</analepsis> It I had a dog that would lie where my bed is made tonight I would kill myself and burn his collar and swart I never owned him.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="4 - Deer"></div>

    <div title="4 - Echo Rock"></div>

    <div title="4 - June 9">
        <level degree="2"><analepsis>DISASTER IN THE RAPIDS!</analepsis> THE NO NAME is DESTROYED! It is BROKEN APART! With it go LOGS, GOODS and so many of our POSSESSIONS. Oramel, Seneca and Frank are lucky to still be among us, but poor Frank may have to finish the trip NAKED, for he has not a possession left but the britches he is wearing!</level>
    </div>

    <div title="5 - Life is good when the fish are biting"></div>

    <div title="5 - Clothes">
        <level degree="1">June 15 You put wet pen to wet paper:</level>
        <level degree="2"><analepsis>... My boat was sunk while being lowered over the rapid this morning and all of my books and papers soaked. .. My notes were soaked but I have dried them and since that have carried them in my hat.</analepsis> My clothing is of course all wet again but aside from the trouble of drying it, it is no matter for I need only shirt and drawers in this warm weather and <analepsis>lately have seldom worn anything else.</analepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="5 - Island Park"></div>

    <div title="5 - Whirlpool Canyon"></div>

    <div title="6">
        <level degree="2">We Have All Died! Newspapers announce our terrible death, publishing an account by John Risdon, who claims to be the sole survivor of our terrible death.  He says we were all sucked us all into the vortex of a massive whirlpool. <analepsis>Before, no one paid attention to our exploring expedition. Tragic headlines have made us national news</analepsis> -- only not one of us knows! <prolepsis>We later learn that <analepsis>search teams had been dispatched to find our remains,</analepsis> when suddenly, magically Powell comes back to life! One week after the story breaks, The Chicago Tribune receives a letter from Major Powell about the voyage sent from The Uinta Tribal Center. While we complain about the lack of food, the Major has become national hero in The Press; but, you might later wonder, does American think of the rest of us?</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="6">
        <level degree="2">Powell hikes out  to the Uinta Tribal Center to send his letters and buy supplies, but why doesn’t he purchase enough food - does he believe we can make it on fish and wildlife? We struggle to suppress our dissent.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="6 - July 5 - The Journey Resumes"></div>

    <div title="7 - Observations for Alt. July 7th at">
        Camp at cliff on right of river
        D		W		At		Bar
        74		54.8  	74.5	25.540
        81		57		81		24.426
        Upper bar against rocks
        exposed to the sun lower in shade
    </div>

    <div title="7">
        <level degree="1">The crew raid a field of vegetables being grown by local natives: everything goes into the pot. Later, you feel sick to the stomach. Others are vomiting the remains of boiled potato tops.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="7 - Bears"></div>

    <div title="7 - Desolation Canyon"></div>

    <div title="7 - The Butte of the Cross"></div>

    <div title="8">
        <level degree="2">We Have All Died! Newspapers announce our terrible death, publishing an account by John Risdon, who claims to be the sole survivor of our terrible death.  He says we were all sucked us all into the vortex of a massive whirlpool. <analepsis>Before, no one paid attention to our exploring expedition. Tragic headlines have made us national news</analepsis> -- only not one of us knows! <prolepsis>We later learn that <analepsis>search teams had been dispatched to find our remains,</analepsis> when suddenly, magically Powell comes back to life! One week after the story breaks, The Chicago Tribune receives a letter from Major Powell about the voyage sent from The Uinta Tribal Center. While we complain about the lack of food, the Major has become national hero in The Press; but, you might later wonder, does American think of the rest of us?</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="8 - 4,000'"></div>

    <div title="8 - hard rains"></div>

    <div title="8 - Pines - Cottonwood"></div>

    <div title="8 - Music Temple">
        <level degree="1">The natural accoustics seduce the musicians into the canyon’s bowl big enough for 2000 people.  Who will sing a song to complement to the Canyon Wrens?</level>
    </div>

    <div title="8 - If Only Milton Knew">
        <level degree="1">July 9. You will be happy to see the end of this day. If only Milton knew. Trying to keep your notes dry, you write.</level>
        <level degree="2">A terrible gale of dry hot wind swept over our camp and roared though the canon mingling its sound with the mellow roar of the cataract making music fit for the infernal regions. We needed only a few flashes of lightening to meet Milton's most vivid conceptions of Hell.... We are quite careful now of our provisions as the hot blasts that sweep through these rocky gorges admonish us that a walk out to civilization is almost certain death...</level>
    </div>

    <div title="8 - Beds and">
        <level degree="1">July 11. By the flames at night, you write;</level>
        <level degree="2">Sunday again and the Major has got his match in attempting to run a rapid... His boat swamped... He lost all of his bedding, one barometer, and two valuable rifles.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="8 - Poplars"></div>

    <div title="8 - Dirty Devil Creek"></div>

    <div title="9 - Marble Canyon"></div>

    <div title="9 - Glen Canyon"></div>

    <div title="9 - Cottonwoods"></div>

    <div title="9 - Clothes are wearing thin and with the rising rock a lack of sun and perspective."></div>

    <div title="9 - We enter The Great Unknown, not knowing"></div>

    <div title="9 - The Dirty Devil">
        <level degree="1">July 29.You write;</level>
        <level degree="2">Run 20 miles with ease. The Major names the new stream "Dirty Devil Creek" and as we are the only white men who have seen it, I for one feel quite highly complimented by the name, yet it is in keeping with his whole character, which needs only a short study to be read like a book.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="9">
        <level degree="2">The rock walls rise steeply and sometimes it is hard to find a place to sleep. The fish are no longer biting, the flour is wet and full of lumps, and <analepsis>none of these hunters on board have been able to bring in the bacon.</analepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="9 - Limestone and Marble"></div>

    <div title="10 - Silver Creek"></div>

    <div title="10 - Bright Angel"></div>

    <div title="10 - Gloom of the Canyons">
        <level degree="1">The walls become higher. The journey becomes darker. There is little chance for visual relief in this perpetual tunnel of rock. There is no end in sight. A gloom sets in.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="10 - Time Aug 16 69 Elgin">
        112-50= 10-23-58 =2 =09-52
        113-00=10-24-26 =2-09-20
        10=10-24-55 =2-08-48.5
        20=10-25-26 =2-08-18
        30=10-25-59.5=2-07-15
        40=10-26-31 =2-07-23
        50=1--27-02 =2-06-48
        114-00=10-27-33 =2-06-15
        10=10-28-06 =2-05-49
        20=10-28-33 =2-05-14
        I.E.  A.M.    42” -00
        -18 - 00
    </div>

    <div title="10 - heavy rains"></div>

    <div title="11 - Moqui Ruins"></div>

    <div title="11 - Granite heavy rains heavy rains"></div>

    <div title="11 - 4000' walls"></div>

    <div title="11 - Marble"></div>

    <div title="11 - No Place to Sleep">
        <level degree="1">August 14. Exhausted, you write;</level>
        <level degree="2">This is emphatically the wildest day of the trip so far. <analepsis>We ran the first rapid this morning, ran the one at its foot, a very heavy one, and then a succession of very rough ones until near noon when we came to the worst one we had seen on the river and, the walls being vertical, or rather coming to the water on both sides, we had to run it and, all being ready, away we went...</analepsis>    Tonight, no two except the Major and Jack can find space wide enough to make a double bed, and if they don't lie still we shall "hear something drop".... I sleep in a wide stream of rocks where I can't roll out. Andy has his bed just above the water on a fragment at the water's edge scarce wide enough to hold him. The rest are tucked around like swallows....</level>
    </div>

    <div title="11 - Lava"></div>

    <div title="12 - Lava"></div>

    <div title="12 - A Lightness of Being">
        <level degree="1">August 18. A lightness of being...you scratch out your notes;</level>
        <level degree="2">Coffee and heavy bread cannot be called light rations, but one feels quite light about the stomach after living on it for a while. ... <analepsis>This P.M. we have had a terrible thunder shower. We had to fasten the boats to the rocks and seek shelter from the wind behind boulders. The rain poured down in torrents and the thunder peals echoed through the canon from crag to crag making wild music for the lightening to dance to.</analepsis> After a shower it is grand to see the cascades leap from the cliffs and turn to vapor before they reach the rocks below. There are thousands of them all sizes, pure and while as molten silver.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="12 - Granite"></div>

    <div title="12 - Granite"></div>

    <div title="12 - Mutiny...">
        <level degree="2">Three men abandon the trip aiming to hike out to safety. They take with them some baked food and guns and valuable scientific gear.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="12 - Al. Alair Aug 27 fir Kat">
        Separation Camp
        125º  13'00"  I.E. 12.20
    </div>

    <div title="12 - August 27"></div>

    <div title="13 - The Darkest Hour">
        <level degree="2">August 27. The darkest hour. We worry what tomorrow will bring;  <analepsis>Run 12 miles today but at noon we came to the worst rapid yet seen.</analepsis> The water dashes against the left bank and then is thrown furiously back against the right. The billows are huge and I fear our boats could not ride them if we could keep them off the rocks.... We have only subsistence for about five days... There is discontent in the camp tonight and I fear some of the party will take to the mountains but hope not. This is decidedly the darkest day of the trip but I don't despair yet. I shall be one to try to run it rather than take to the mountains. "Tis darkest just before the day" and I trust out day is about to dawn..</level>
    </div>

    <div title="13 - Separation Rapid"></div>

    <div title="14 - August 28">
        <level degree="2">The Howlands and Dunn are gone. We say goodbye to the Emma
        Dean at the shore, and will continue the journey without it.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="14">
        <level degree="1">All the Major writes in his log is</level> <level degree="2"><analepsis>"Boys left us. Run rapids. Bradley boat broke.</analepsis> Camp on left bank. Camp 44."</level> <level degree="1">What will the Major say <prolepsis>when he has to explain this day?</prolepsis></level>
    </div>

    <div title="14 - The Untold Story of Three Dead">
        <level degree="1">Dunn and the Howland brothers hike out on August 28. They are never seen again. The official story is that the three men are killed by a local Native American tribe. That is what the Mormon authorities say. Others believe this is a cover-up....That the men are mudered by a group of Mormons who heard about the valuable goods the three were carrying, or who were simple unwilling to have outsiders prowling about their territory.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="15 - August 30">
     <level degree="1">Turning a bend you see some men on the shoreline. You have arrived at the mouth of the Rio Virgen! They feed you (melons!). There is no news about the men who left the voyage three days ago. For Major Powell, it seems, the journey is over. But, perhaps, you will join Sumner</level>
    </div>

    <div title="17">
        <level degree="1">1875. The fragments of a journey (or is it journeys) are
        constructed into a adventurous narrative report to
        Congress and a three part serialized illustrated story for
        Scribner's Monthly January, February and March. 1895.
        Powell publishes an extended account in Canyons of the
        Colorado, that includes 258 black &amp; white illustrations...</level>

        <level degree="2">May 26. To-day we pass several
        curiously shaped buttes,
        standing between the west bank
        of the river and the high bluffs
        beyond. ...The river is running
        to the south; the mountains have
        an easterly and westerly trend
        directly athwart its course, yet it
        glides on in a quiet way as if it
        thought a mountain range no
        formidable obstruction. It enters
        the range by a f‌laring, brilliant
        red gorge, that may be seen
        from the north a score of miles
        away. The great mass of the
        mountain ridge through which
        the gorge is cut is composed of
        bright vermilion rocks; but they
        are surmounted by broad bands
        of mottled buff and gray, and
        these bands come down with a
        gentle curve to the water's edge
        on the nearer slope of the
        mountain. This is the head of the
        f‌irst of the canyons we are about
        to explore-an introductory one
        to a series made by the river
        through this range. We name it
        Flaming Gorge.

        June 12. To-day we take the boats down to the bay. While at this work we
        discover three sacks of f‌lour from the wrecked boat that have lodged in the rocks.
        We carry them above high-water mark and leave them, as our cargos are
        already too heavy for the three remaining boats. We also f‌ind two or three oars,
        which we place with them. As <analepsis>Ashley and his party were wrecked here and as we
        have lost one of our boats at the same place,</analepsis> we adopt the name Disaster Falls for
        the scene of so much peril and loss. <analepsis>Though some of his companions were
        drowned, Ashley and one other survived the wreck, climbed the canyon wall, and
        found their way across the Wasatch Mountains to Salt Lake City, living chief‌ly on
        berries, as they wandered through an unknown and diff‌icult country. When they
        arrived at Salt Lake they were almost destitute of clothing and nearly starved...</analepsis>

        June 13. Rocks, rapids, and portages still. We camp to-night at the foot of the left fall,
        on a little patch of f‌lood plain covered with a dense growth of box-elders, stopping
        early in order to spread the clothing and rations to dry. Everything is wet and spoiling.

        June 18th. We have named the long peninsular
        rock on the other side Echo Rock... Looking
        about, we f‌ind a place where it seems possible
        to climb. I go ahead; Bradley hands the
        barometer to me, and follows. So we proceed,
        stage by stage, until we are nearly to the
        summit. Here, by making a spring, I gain a
        foothold in a little crevice, and grasp an angle
        of the rock overhead. I f‌ind I can get up no
        farther and cannot step back, for I dare not let
        go with my hand and cannot reach foothold
        below without. I call to Bradley for help. He
        f‌inds a way by which he can get to the top of
        the rock over my head, but cannot reach me.
        Then he looks around for some stick or limb of
        a tree, but f‌inds none. Then he suggests that he
        would better help me with the barometer case,
        but I fear I cannot hold on to it. The moment is
        critical. Standing on my toes, my muscles
        begin to tremble. It is sixty or eighty feet to the
        foot of the precipice. If I lose my hold I shall
        fall to the bottom and then perhaps roll over
        the bench and tumble still farther down the
        cliff. At this instant it occurs to Bradley to take
        off his drawers, which he does, and swings
        them down to me. I hug close to the rock, let
        go with my hand, seize the dangling legs, and
        with his asistance am enabled to gain the top.

        July 6. An early start this morning. A short
        distance below the mouth of the Uinta we come to
        the head of a long island. <analepsis>Last winter a man
        named Johnson, a hunter and Indian trader,
        visited us at our camp in White River Valley.
        This man has an Indian wife, and, having no f‌ixed
        home, usually travels with one of the Ute bands.
        He informed me that it was his intention to plant
        some corn, potatoes, and other vegetables on this
        island in the spring, and, knowing that we would
        pass it, invited us to stop and help our selves, even
        if he should not be there;</analepsis> so we land and go out
        on the island. Looking about, we soon discover
        his garden, but it is in a sad condition, <analepsis>having
        received no care since it was planted.</analepsis> It is yet too
        early in the season for corn, but Hall suggests
        that potato tops are good greens, and, anxious
        for some change from our salt-meat fare, we
        gather a quantity and take them aboard. At noon
        we stop and cook our greens for dinner; but soon
        one after another of the party is taken sick;
        nausea f‌irst, and then severe vomiting, and we
        tumble around under the trees, groaning with
        pain. I feel a little alarmed, lest our poisoning be
        severe. Emetics are administered to those who
        are willing to take them, and about the middle of
        the afternoon we are all rid of the pain. Jack
        Stunner records in his diary that "potato tops are
        not good greens on the 6th day of July."

        July 19. Bradley and I start this morning to
        climb the left wall below the
        junction...Bradley climbs f‌irst; I hand him
        the barometer, then climb over his head
        and he hands me the barometer. So we pass
        each other alternately until we emerge
        from the f‌issure, out on the summit of the
        rock. And what a world of grandeur is
        spread before us! Below is the canyon
        through which the Colorado runs...
        Between us and the distant cliffs are the
        strangely carved and pinnacled rocks of the
        Toom'pin wunear' T‘uweap'. On the summit
        of the opposite wall of the canyon are rock
        forms that we do not understand. Away to
        the east a group of eruptive mountains are
        seen--the Sierra La Sal, which we f‌irst saw
        two days ago through the canyon of the
        Grand. Their slopes are covered with pines,
        and deep gulches are f‌lanked with great
        crags, and snow f‌ields are seen near the
        summits. So the mountains are in uniform,-
        -green, gray, and silver. Wherever we look
        there is but a wilderness of rocks,--deep
        gorges where the rivers are lost below cliffs
        and towers and pinnacla, and ten thousand
        strangely carved forms in every direction,
        and beyond them mountains blending with
        the clouds.

        August 3. Start early this morning. The features of this
        canyon are greatly diversif‌ied. Still vertical walls at times.
        These are usually found to stand above great curves. The
        river, sweeping around these bends, undermines the cliffs in
        places. Sometimes the rocks are overhanging; in other
        curves, curious, narrow glens are found. Through these we
        climb, by a rough stairway, perhaps several hundred feet, to
        where a spring bursts out from under an overhanging cliff,
        and where cottonwoods and willows stand, while along the
        curves of the brooklet oaks grow, and other rich vegetation is
        seen, in marked contrast to the general appearance of naked
        rock. We call these Oak Glens. Other wonderful features are
        the many side canyons or gorges that we pass. Sometimes we
        stop to explore these for a short distance. In some places
        their walls are much nearer each other above than below, so
        that they look somewhat like caves or chambers in the rocks.
        Usually, in going up such a gorge, we f‌ind beautiful
        vegetation; but our way is often cut off by deep basins, or
        "potholes," as they are called. On the walls, and back many
        miles into the country, numbers of monument-shaped buttes
        are observed. So we have a curious ensemble of wonderful
        features-carved walls, royal arches, glens, alcove gulches,
        mounds, and monunents. From which of these features shall
        we select a name? We decide to call it Glen Canyon. Past
        these towering monuments, past these mounded billows of
        orange sandstone, past these oak-set glens, past these fern-
        decked alcoves, past these mural curves, we glide hour after
        hour, stopping now and then, as our attention is arrested by
        some new wonder, until we reach a point which is historic.

        August 13. We are now ready to start on
        our way down the Great Unknown. Our
        boats, tied to a common, stake, chafe each
        other as they are tossed by the fretful river.
        They ride high and buoyant, for their loads
        are lighter than we could desire. We have
        but a month's rations remaining. <analepsis>The f‌lour
        has been resifted through the mosquito-net
        sieve; the spoiled bacon has been dried and
        the worst of it boiled; the few pounds of
        dried apples have been spread in the sun and
        reshrunken to their normal bulk. The sugar
        has all melted and gone on its way down the
        river.</analepsis> But we have a large sack of coffee.
        The lightening of the boats has this
        advantage: they will ride the waves better
        and we shall have but little to carry when we
        make a portage... We are three quarters of a
        mile in the depths of the earth, and the great
        river shrinks into insignif‌icance as it dashes
        its angry waves against the walls and cliffs
        that rise to the world above; the waves are
        but puny ripples, and we but pigmies,
        running up and down the sands or lost
        among the boulders...We have an unknown
        distance yet to run, an unknown river to
        explore. What falls there are, we know not;
        what rocks beset the channel, we know not;
        what walls rise over the river, we know not.

        August 16.
        We must dry our rations again today and make
        oars...
        The Colorado is never a clear stream, but <analepsis>for the
        past three or four days it has been raining much
        of the time, and the f‌loods poured over the walls
        have brought down great quantities of mud,</analepsis>
        making it exceedingly turbid now. The little
        aff‌luent which we have discovered here is a clear,
        beautiful creek, or river, as it would be termed in
        this western country, where streams are not
        abundant. <analepsis>We have named one stream, away
        above, in honor of the great chief of the "Bad
        Angels,"</analepsis> and as this is in beautiful contrast to
        that, we conclude to name it "Bright Angel."

        August 17.
        Our rations are still spoiling; the bacon is so
        badly injured that we are compelled to throw it
        away. <analepsis>By an accident, this morning, the saleratus
        was lost overboard.</analepsis> We have now only musty
        f‌lour suff‌icient for ten days and a few dried
        apples, but plenty of coffee. We must make all
        haste possible. If we meet with diff‌iculties such as
        we have encountered in the canyon above, we
        may be compelled to give up the expedition and
        try to reach the Mormon settlements to the north.

        August 22. We come to rapids again this morning
        and are occupied several hours in passing them,
        letting the boats down from rock to rock with
        lines for nearly half a mile, and then have to
        make a long portage. While the men are engaged
        in this I climb the wall on the northeast to a height
        of about 2,500 feet, where I can obtain a good
        view of a long stretch of canyon below. Its course
        is to the southwest. The walls seem to rise very
        abruptly for 2,500 or 3,000 feet, and then there is
        a gently sloping terrace on each side for two or
        three miles, when we again f‌ind cliffs, 1,500 or
        2,000 feet high. From the brink of these the
        plateau stretches back to the north and south for
        a long distance. Away down the canyon on the
        right wall I can see a group of mountains, some of
        which appear to stand on the brink of the canyon.
        The effect of the terrace is to give the appearance
        of a narrow winding valley with high walls on
        either side and a deep, dark, meandering gorge
        down its middle. It is impossible from this point of
        view to determine whether or not we have granite
        at the bottom; but from geologic considerations, I
        conclude that we shall have marble walls below.
        After my return to the boats we run another mile
        and camp for the night. We have made but little
        over seven miles to-day, and a part of our f‌lour
        has been soaked in the river again.

        August 25. We make 12 miles this morning, when we come
        to monuments of lava standing in the river ,--low rocks
        mostly, but some of them shafts more than a hundred feet
        high. Going on down three or four miles, we f‌ind them
        increasing in number. Great quantities of cooled lava and
        many cinder cones are seen on either side; and then we
        come to an abrupt cataract. Just over the fall on the right
        wall a cinder cone, or extinct volcano, with a well-def‌ined
        crater, stands on the very brink of the canyon. This,
        doubtless, is <analepsis>the one we saw two or three days ago.</analepsis> <analepsis>From
        this volcano vast f‌loods of lava have been poured down
        into the river, and a stream of molten rock has run up the
        canyon three or four miles and down we know not how far.</analepsis>
        Just where <analepsis>it poured over the canyon wall</analepsis> is the fall... As
        we f‌loat down we can see that <analepsis>it ran out into side canyons.</analepsis>
        In some places this basalt has a f‌ine, columnar structure,
        often in concentric prisms, and masses of these concentric
        columns have coalesced. In some placs, <analepsis>when the f‌low
        occurred the canyon was probably about the same depth
        that it is now,</analepsis> for we can see where <analepsis>the basalt has rolled
        out on the sands,</analepsis> and what seems curious to me--the sands
        are not melted or metamorphosed to any appreciable
        extent. In places the bed of the river is of sandstone or
        limestone, in other placs of lava, showing that it has all
        been cut out again where the sandstones and limestones
        appear; but there is a little yet left where the bed is of lava.
        What a conf‌lict of water and f‌ire there must have been
        here! Just imagine a river of molten rock running down
        into a river of melted snow. What a seething and boiling of
        the waters; what clouds of steam rolled into the heavens!

        August 27. ...About nine o'clock we come to the
        dreaded rock. It is with no little misgiving that
        we see the river enter these black, hard walls. At
        its very entrance we have to make a portage;
        then let down with lines past some ugly rocks.
        We run a mile or two farther, and then the
        rapids below can be seen...We f‌ind that <analepsis>the
        lateral streams have washed boulders into the
        river,</analepsis> so as to form a dam, over which the water
        makes a broken fall of 18 or 20 feet; then there is
        a rapid on the other side, and points of the wall
        project into the river. Below, there is a second
        fall; how great, we cannot tell. Then there is a
        rapid, f‌illed with huge rocks, for 100 or 200
        yards. At the bottom of it, from the right wall, a
        great rock projects quite halfway across the
        river. It has a sloping surface extending up
        stream, and the water, coming down with all the
        momentum gained in the falls and rapids above,
        rolls up this inclined plane many feet, and
        tumbles over to the left ...On my return to the
        boat I announce to the men that we are to run it
        in the morning. [Captain Howland] thinks that
        we had better abandon the river here. Talking
        with him, I learn that he, his brother, and
        Wiliam Dunn have determined to go no farther
        in the boats. So we return to camp. Nothing is
        said to the other men.

        August 28. At last daylight comes and we have breakfast without a word
        being said about the future. The meal is as solemn as a funeral. After
        breakfast I ask the three men if they still think it best to leave us. The elder
        Howland thinks it is, and Dunn agrees with him. The younger Howland tries
        to persuade them to go on with the party; failing in which, he decides to go
        with his brother... With the loss of hands, consequent on the departure of the
        three men, we shall not be able to run all of the boats; so I decide to leave my
        "Emma Dean." edition and try to reach the Mormon settlements to the north.

        August 29.
        ...At twelve o'clock emerge from the Grand Canyon of the Colorado...
        The river rolls by us in silent majesty... our joy is almost ecstasy.</level>

        <level degree="1">Powell's narrative log is triumphant and singular. The actual diary is a collection
        of fragmented, incomplete and, at times, contradictory, scratched-out notes.</level>
    </div>

    <div title="19">
        <!-- Go back and check for analepsis/prolepsis in these. -->
        <level degree="1">How to picture the Great Unknown? The illustrations that Powell
        incorporates into his later publications about the famous pioneer
        journey are fabricated through the imagination of artists or adapted
        from sketches and photographs taken on return journeys; there are no
        artists on the maiden voyage. Documentary details of the photos are
        altered to magnify the emotional tenor of the narrative of these diary-
        like entries. In this image of the departure, mountains are added to the
        background, bushes become trees, and the vignette with f‌loral
        decoration adds a dreamy, mythical quality.

        There are no photographers on the f‌irst trip, either. Photographing the
        canyons becomes one of the primary goals of Powell's less reported
        second river voyage that begins in 1871, winters over in a Mormon
        village, and continues in 1872. Where the f‌irst journey is mostly about
        discovering what is there, the second trip aims at more serious
        cartography and documentation; in his report to congress and
        publications about the trip, Powell's texts about the voyage blend
        documentary and adventure narrative materials, obscuring the
        experiences of the second trip to illustrate the f‌irst. No other logs of
        the f‌irst trip are published, and an account of the second trip, a
        diar istic account by Frederick Dellenbaugh which includes many of the
        photographs from the voyage, is only published after Powell's death.

        In 1971, Powell enlists E.O. Beaman to join his second expedition
        down the Colorado River to photograph the canyons. They arrange
        to share prof‌its from the sale of stereographic photogr aphs,
        picturing the Wild West for a mass market. Along with the heavy
        state-of-the-art camera, Beaman brings a portable darkroom for
        developing the collodion wet-plate negatives. At the end of the 1971
        season, mid-trip, Powell takes a couple hundred of the photographs
        to Washington to help bolster his request for funds.

        To render the canyons in 3D, the stereoscopic camera records two images
        of the same scene through two lenses. The lenses are spaced apart from each
        other about the same distance as between two human eyes. Looked at
        through a special viewer, the two images combine into one. The
        photographic equipment needed for the task is heavy, weighing over 701bs.
        But the material is fragile; the images are recorded onto glass plates. And,
        furthermore, the process is time-consuming. It takes time to carry the
        materials to viewpoints, to prepare the plates and to shoot the images.

        The scenes of a wild nature are counter-balanced by serene scenes at
        the riverside. Beaman makes use of the ref‌lections in the water, the
        deep perspective, and framing to draw out formal relationships
        between the boats, shore, and mountains. Viewers are implicitly invited
        to f‌ill the empty seats of the Major's (and photographer's) boats.

        Whether out of personal taste or the commercial interests that shape the
        project, Beaman often selects subjects that are dramatic or romantic,
        foregrounding the meeting of man and nature. Here, some crew members
        are shown lining the boats through Ashley Falls. The rope along which the
        boats are pulled is barely visible against the blur of the rapids. The journey
        is suspended during the winter of 1871. The crew winters in Mormon
        village while Powell returns to Washington to seek further funding. After a
        dispute with Powell in the winter of 1872, Beaman quits the voyage. He is
        replaced by locally trained photographer, James Fennemore.

        Some of Fennemore's photographs are ordinary. Others are mysterious.
        This stereoscopic photograph of the canyon, Music Temple, offers no
        easy place at which the eye might rest — there is no centered object or
        vanishing point. A viewer confronts the messy details of the large,
        enclosed canyon with its brush in the foreground and it cavernous,
        curving rock surface behind. The viewer is an explorer: unsettled and
        with no obvious place to rest, the eye wanders about the details.

        Fennemore records the characteristic dark and twisting dry waterway of
        a side ravine. The image details the cluttered debris of storms or f‌loods,
        the differing plants that survive here, and the surfaces of the layered
        rock and sand. Light is ref‌lected in multiple directions and interrupted by
        the sequence of rock forms that have been shaped by forces of nature.

        The human story: in this photo by Fennemore, the shadow of the camera falls
        across the right image. This places the photographer, and, by extension, the
        viewer, in the scene. It is shot from between the grass, enhancing a voyeuristic
        sensibility. Crew members repairing the boat are frozen mid-action. Their
        materials are scattered haphazardly beneath the jagged overhang of the
        layered rock, and the scene in the foreground loosely parallels the form of rock
        outcropping and pinnacle, with their ship-f‌ike form, in background. It is not
        clear how large and far away the pinnacle is or what the rest of the surrounding
        landscape looks like. Cropping so tightly on the right, Fennemore does not
        situate the scene in relation to a larger horizon or the (presumed) river below.

        A young oarsman named John Hillers volunteers to assist Fennemore, helping
        him carry the 701b gear among the rocks. Together, they visit this viewpoint at
        Toroweap, and Hillers returns on a later occasion. In the left photo, a slouched
        f‌igure stands at the edge of the dramatic precipice, leaning forward to see what
        is below. A strange light is caught in the cloud cover while in the foreground of
        the immediate cliff face a f‌lat rock is leaning upright, catching the sun on its
        surface. In the right photo, the far more distant f‌igure is seated and in silhouette.
        Both images express the thrill of being on the edge of such a dramatic opening in
        the landscape, and the inclusion of human f‌igures accentuate the grandeur.

        Fennemore falls ill several months into the voyage, and Hillers takes over the
        task of photographing the canyons, launching a career in which he becomes
        one of the primary photographers for the U.S. geographic surveys in the
        West. However, none of the photographers are scientists. The photographers
        focus on the human relation to landscapes, the aesthetic beauty of views, and
        the adventures of Powell's crew. Artists rendering the f‌irst voyage into
        illustration seize on these aspects of the photographs over others.

        Lava Falls. Facts from the voyages blur both in the text and illustrations. The
        text clings to the dates of the f‌irst voyage as pegs by which to order the pictures.
        This etching is by Frederick Dellenbaugh who was on the second voyage, and
        who would eventually, after Powell's death, publish an account of it.

        Sentinel Rock Glen, Canyon. The exaggeration of
        human-like attributes on the elongated rock (enlarging
        the "head" and narrowing the "legs") set in moonlight
        silhouette transforms rock into an anthropomorphizecl
        totem. The radically altered perspective miniaturizes
        the onlookers standing at their peaceful riverside camp.

        The Little Colorado
        A plain image of the conf‌luence of the Colorado and little Colorado Rivers
        depicts what is a natura1 resting point on any journey down river. The photo is
        augmented through the artist's vignetted interpretation. Missing: one of the
        features that makes this conf‌luence so remarkable is color. Flowing over a bed
        of white, powdery calcium carbonate, the Little Colorado has a light blue glow
        that contrasts with the dark and, then, muddy waters of the great Colorado.

        In the photographs like this one in which crew members are repairing the boats
        near Cathedral Butte, individuals other than the Major are shot at distance.
        Dwarfed by the landscape, they are, for the most part, indistinguishable and
        nameless. In the illustration, added features such as the setting sun, delineated
        cliff lines, ref‌lections on the water, and articulated slopes add scale and a
        magical tone. The campf‌ire provides an intimacy. The higher angle widens the
        river, exaggerates the height of the mountains and lowers the individuals in the
        frame, further reducing their size and individuality.

        Dellenbaugh recalls a song that Major Powell would often sing as they boated along:
        I love it, I love it, the laugh of a child.
        Now ripping, now gentle, now merry and wild.
        It rings through the air with an innocent gush,
        Like the thrill of a bird at the twil‌ight's soft hush,
        It f‌loats on the breeze like the tones of a bell,
        Or music that dwells in the heart of a shell.
        Oh the laugh of a child is so wild and so free
        'Tis the merriest sound in the world no me.
        Dellenbaugh remarks that while Major Powell had no f‌ine voice, he always sang from
        his heart.

        A more acclaimed artist who worked with Powell is Thomas Moran. Decorating
        political institutions, parks, and travel materials of the period, Moran's images
        invoke romantic and clasical themes of Western dominion. Even after his
        production of 1400 photographs on the f‌irst two trips, Powell returns on a third
        voyage with artist Moran. Perhaps paint instead of photography would elevate
        the status of his journey using the romantic aesthetic of the moment to weave a
        personal journey into a national narrative. Powell's reports to Congress and
        public accounts integrate these aesthetics and geological notes. Art and science
        blur. Powell begins a political career as a U.S. geographer.

        From journey into documentation, and doctunentation into story, the narrative
        of Powell's encounter with the Unknown Territory is crafted into the imagery of
        an epoch and its narratives of expansion; the artistic aesthetic coincides with a
        political agenda. With the arrival of investors and settlers, also comes a wave of
        scientif‌ically trained graphic artists and cartographers who render this
        landscape in a very different way. The initial pictures offer Eden-like images of
        natura1 splendor — a mythic heritage for a nation. The scientif‌ic images delineate
        characteristies and boundaries. As the nation's geographer, Powell realizes that,
        in its current model, the new Western expansion --a growth he may have helped
        stimulate through his own fabulous narratives and image-production -- is not
        sustainable. As director of the Geographic Survey, Powell attempts to put the
        brakes on expansion. This is highly unpopular, and he is forced from office.

        From experience into photographs, and photos into text and illustration,
        narratives are transformed and take on lives of their own. Meanwhile,
        Powell, now forced from off‌ice, retreats to his secondary position as
        Director of the Smithsonian Institute of Ethnography. During these f‌inal
        years of his life, he records aspects of indigenous culturs of the desert
        territories whose worlds have little place in the newly imagined future of
        Great American Desert. And, encouraged by friends, he expands his earlier
        congressional report and journal publications into Canyons of the Colorado,
        drawing attention back to the initial voyage and the spirit of exploration.
        </level>
    </div>

</text>
